So, let's take a look at our very first file organization,
or rather, in this case,
disorganization, because the first one we're going to look at is a heap.
A heap is defined as a file of data that is not sorted,
so the records sit on a bunch of blocks and there is no sorting among the records.
Any record we're looking for in the whole file could sit on any block whatsoever.
We saw before that good assumptions,
for our example here,
would be to have block pointers that are four bytes,
four million records with 20 records per block,
we need about 200,000 data blocks,
and the file size is a total of 800 megs.
So, when something is a heap,
that basically means that we have to look at the data pages in
order to determine whether what we are looking
for is going to be in those data pages or not.
If there's a grand total of N data pages or N data blocks,
then sometimes, we are lucky and
the data we are looking for sits on the very first block.
Sometimes, we are unlucky and it sits on the very last block.
So, on the average,
we can expect that we have to look at N over
2 data blocks where N is the total number of data blocks.
So, with 200 data blocks,
if we are going to look at the average half of those,
we'll be looking at 100,000 data blocks.
If each one caused the default of 10 milliseconds,
that's going to cost us 16.6 minutes to look up a record in a heap.