So, data in the phone book is sorted.
Let's see how we utilize that in a binary search.
We're going to look for the phone number of Leo Mark.
So, we take the phone book,
we split it magically in half like here,
we look at the entry here through the my right,
it's New Birth Urban International Ministries.
So, Leo Mark comes before them.
So, let's split that next piece in half.
All right what does it say here?
It says friendship.
So, it comes after friendship and we are left with this piece here,
now let's split that in half,
it says here Jesse's flaws.
What comes after that?
Split that in half and we are here at Lloyd's Insurance.
So, it's still in the right side here.
We'll split that in half and it says Mack Miller, MC Miller.
So, Mack is in the left side.
Okay, so here it says magic and here it says,
Maine split that in half and see what we end up with here, Mason.
All right. We're down pretty small now.
Split that in half,
let's see which side we are in. All right.
That's Mark's.
So we're getting close. Would you believe it?
Right here on the page are the names that start with Mark. Thank you very much.