So, it was painful and expensive to lookup data in a heap.
So, let's try to sort the data on the file.
So now, the records will be sitting here,
multiple records on a block,
pointed to the next block,
several records on that etc,
and the data will be sorted here in some order.
Now, to look through and find a record with a particular key,
what is that going to cost us now?
Well, we could start at the first block and look through
the records and see if we find the one with the key desired,
if not, then we'll look at the second block,
see if we find it there,
third block, see if we find it there.
What is that going to cost us?
Well, sometimes the record we are looking for will actually be on the first block.
Sometimes the record we are looking for will be on the last block.
On the average again,
as for unsorted data,
we have to look at about half of the blocks of data.
Again therefore, the cost of looking up an element or
record with a particular key is going to again cost us 16.6 minutes.
But the reason for that is that we aren't
utilizing the fact that data is sorted that order.
So, what if we were to utilize the fact that data is sorted?
What if we had a little bit of metadata that would allow us to
understand where approximately the middle of the data file is?
Then we could go in.
We could look at that middle block,
and we could determine whether what we are looking for is to
the left of where we tried or to the right of where we tried.
So, we'll continue with half of the search space.
Then in the next step,
we'll hit about the middle of that and
continue either with the left piece or the right piece.
The amount of time it takes us to take something of size and look through
it and split in half each time is log base 2 toward this we are searching in.
Since we are searching in N blocks,
log base 2- N data blocks is what
the cost is going to be for binary search in order for us to
end up with a single block on which the data element
we're looking for is going to be stored if it's in the database.
With the numbers we have here,
log base 2- N,
where N is 200,000,
is 18 multiply that by 10 milliseconds,
and you get an access time which is 0.18 second.
Very, very much faster than the 16.6 minutes.
Before we proceed, I want to emphasize that the cost of
the search depends on the size of what we search in.
So N is the size of the file,
and the cost depends on that size.