So in addition to sorting the data and being smart about how we search in it,
we might want to consider ways of reducing the size of what we're going to search in.
That's where the idea of indices comes in.
We are going to look at two kinds of indices;
primary indices and secondary indices.
So, the idea of a primary index is as follows: we
have data here at the bottom and the data is sorted in some order.
So, the records come here with increasing or decreasing key values.
To build a primary index,
what we do is we take a look at
the first record and pick up the key of that record and make a copy
of it in an index block together with a point of
that point's back to the block on which the record with that key was the first one.
We go to the second block here,
look at the first record,
pick up the key value, make a copy,
insert it in the index together with a pointer back to
the block on which that key value was the key value of the first record.
Pick up the key value of the second one,
insert it with a pointer etc.
When that index block is full we continue.
So, the index blocks look like this.
There's a key value and a pointer to the record where that was the first key value.
So, these look like this.
There is a key value followed by a pointer
to the block where that key value was the first one,
then there's the next key value followed by a pointer, etc.
So, that's the content of each one of these.
When we come to the very last block of data here and we have
picked up the key value of the first record and inserted that,
we are done building the index.
Notice an interesting detail,
since we're picking up the key values in sorted order,
once we build the index does not even have reason to sort that, it's born sorted.
Also, notice that the only element we're
picking up from each record actually is the key value,
so all the other current city, birthdate,
hometown, etc., all of that is not picked up from here.
What does that mean?
That means that we can fit a whole lot of entries in an index page.
As a matter of fact,
let's take a look at exactly how many we could fit in there.
So, we know that we have 200,000 blocks of data at the bottom level here.
We know that a block pointer is four bytes.
We know we only want to fill also the index pages,
80 percent, so we've got 3,200 bytes to work with.
We know that the key value,
email is 50 characters,
varchar 50, you add the 50 to the four byte pointer size, you get 54.
Fifty four divided up into 3,200 is going to give you approximately 60.
So, when you look at one of these,
you're going to have approximately 60 key values
and a corresponding set of pointers that come out from that.
That's called the fanout.
So, with space being utilized 80 percent,
the fanout of this primary index is 60.
In other words, you're going to see 60 pointers
sticking out of each one of these pointing down to the data lab.