What does that mean in terms of how many index blocks we need?
Well, we need to point to 200,000,
we can point to 60 from each one.
So, you divide the 200,000 by 60 and you'll find out that the number of
index blocks on this sparse index is 3,334.
It would actually be possible to build a primary index as a dense index also.
So, instead of picking up the k value of the first block,
we pick up every single k value,
and then every single one of them will result in
an insertion of that k value and a pointer to block one, every single one.
Then when we come to the k values here,
they are going to be entered together with pointers to block two.
It will still be sorted,
it will be dense,
meaning that all the k values are in the index.
The index will certainly be bigger.
Using the same numbers,
you will actually see that it's about 20 times bigger at 66,000.
One advantage of having every single k value is some queries can now actually be s,
that do not need to access the data but instead can just access the index.
So, it says, for example,
what's the maximum k value,
the minimum k value, average k value,
et cetera, that can be termed by query on the index alone.
Also, want to emphasize that primary indexes are great not just to find
a particular record with a particular value
but they are great at allowing you to do range queries.
So, once you find the first one in a range, then of course,
you can just follow the next values at the data level or at the index level.
So, let's take a look at some lookup times.
So, since what we have now is a sorted file,
but the file is smaller than the data file here,
let us use n to indicate the number of index blocks
where previously we used uppercase N to indicate the number of data blocks.
So, now the cost of doing a search in this sorted file
is therefore log base 2 to lowercase n. But then,
once you find the correct value, then of course,
you have to go access the data,
so we got to add one.
So, for the sparse index where the number of blocks is 3,334,
to look things up,
you basically do log base 2 to 3,334 plus 1 and multiply
that by the 10 millisecond for a grand total of
0.13 seconds to do the lookup through this index.
Notice that the 0.13 second is lower than the
0.18 seconds we used when we did binary search on the data file.
So, it is cheaper because we cut down the size.
There's also a penalty involved in that because there's an extra level to access now.
But all in all, we went down from 0.18 seconds to 0.13 seconds.
The dense index is obviously larger so we can expect the cost to be higher,
so log base 2 to the 66,666 plus the 1 is about
17 multiplied by the 10 milliseconds gives you 0.17 seconds.
So, even though this index has many more k values,
it is actually still cheaper to use the dense index
than it was to do the search on the data [inaudible].
Notice that what we are talking about here is just lookup cost.
So, in all of these cases,
if we are doing some updates,
then the cost would be both the lookup cost in order to find what we are
updating and then the cost to write things back to disk after they've been changed.
In typical simple situations,
you would add an extra disk access to write things back.
In some cases, if they had changed that affect the index,
you will actually have additional cost related to that.