To use the phone book to illustrate for you how a single level index might work,
we're going to have to make a few changes to that phone book.
You all know that at the top of the phone book is the first key that's
mentioned on that page listed together with the page number. Let me show you.
So for example, on this page here at the top it says Adairsville, page 25.
What I'm going to do for you is I'm going to build a single level index.
So, here we go starting to build that index.
So, I've now started building an index for the phone book.
I cut off the key values together with
the page number at the top of each page and I started putting them in,
in the same order to build my index.
So, here's where I am now.
So I build the piece of the index here,
you see their are key values listed,
and together with each key value there's
the page number for the page on which that key is the first entry.
Now, let's take a look at how we use it to search in the phone book.
So we were looking at Adairsville,
Adairsville when I look up in the index appears right here,
it says page 25,
I open up to page 25 and right there indeed I
do see Adairsville is the first key value that appears on that page.
I can now look through that page for anything that sits
between Adairsville and the next entry in the index.