Let us now look at secondary indexes.
So again here, you have a file with data blocks.
These data blocks are sorted on some key value.
But what you want now is you want to build an index
not on the key value but on some other value.
Now, since the other value you want to build an index on will
not be in sync with the order of the key values,
what will be all over the place building this index is going to be somewhat more painful.
Also notice, that since the values
here that we are going to build the index on are not sorted,
we cannot build a sparse index.
So, all indexes that are secondary indexes have to be dense indexes.
So, here's the idea looking at the data.
We go down to the first record,
we find the value of the field we are building the secondary index on.
That value we insert into
the index here together with the point back to where it came from.
Look at the second record,
pick up the key, put the pointer in,
third recorded and several.
So, every single one in our example,
20 records here will have a key value and a corresponding pointer back to this.
When we are done with that,
we pick up all the key values here with pointers back,
pick up all the key values here,
and point back et cetera.
Continue to add index blocks until we are all done.
If you look at what one of these blocks
will look like immediately after we have done that,
what you're going to see is of course,
that the pointers come nicely and point in order here
because the way we explain the construction took these in order.
So, all the pointers are going to sit like this.
But as I mentioned before,
the key values are going to not be ordered.
So, what we're going to need to do after
this first initial step of building the index is we're going to have to sort it.
So after the sort,
the key values we have picked up for the secondary index
are all going to come in order K1, K2, et cetera.
But now, the pointers are going to point all over
the place to different parts of the file.
The implication of that is,
that a secondary index is good for point queries only.
You cannot trust that once you follow the point or after a particular key value,
that the subsequent key values will come after that.
As a matter of fact, this is a counter example to that.
The course to look up in the secondary index is still a log-based two to the size of it.
The only problem is that,
you can't utilize that as a starting point for range query.
So log-base two to n is as we did before for a dense index.
Comes out that the point look up is going to be 0.17 seconds.
Notice that I've implicitly made the following, simplifying assumption.
I made the assumption that the non-key field we are
indexing on here actually had unique values.
So, what if a value appears multiple times in
that field that we want to build the secondary index on,
then we need to consider whether we are grouping those key values together,
so they don't have to be repeated all the time,
and then keep a bucket of pointers to
all the different copies of that key value accessed.