To understand some of the many issues involved in physical database design,
let us take a look at a simple computer architecture.
There are two kinds of storage on memory in a computer:
there's the disk where the bulk of data and application programs are stored,
then there's main memory,
where the programs that are run right now and
the data that they are run-on need to be located.
The CPU can only run applications on data that's stored in main memory.
The BUS is there to allow us to transport data from
the disk to main memory and to write it back again if it has been changed.
The reason the architecture is like that is the following:
Main memory or random access memory is volatile.
So, it constantly needs power to keep its state.
It is very, very fast.
It is small, and it is relatively expensive.
On the other hand, secondary memory or the disk
as is most often the case, is permanent storage.
It does not need power in order to keep it state,
it is relatively slow compared to main memory,
it is very big compared to main memory,
and it is very cheap compared to main memory.
It is important that only a tiny fraction of a real database will fit in main memory.
So, it is necessary to have for example,
proper management programs that will allow us to transport the data from
disk to main memory when it's to be operated on and write it back again.
People that talk about main memory database are not really talking about databases.
They are talking about toys.
So, our assumption going forward will be that
the vast majority of the database will be stored on disk,
and only a tiny fraction will be in main memory at any given point in time.