So, we've seen a couple of good ideas now.
We have seen the idea that sorting things and being
smart about how we search and sort of things is really helpful.
We have seen that reducing the size of the search space by building indices,
and then pay a slight extra penalty for
accessing the data lever that that is a smart way to proceed.
But if it's a good idea once,
maybe it's a good idea twice.
So, if you look at this index here,
that's a sorted file.
So, why don't we build an index on the index and an index on the index of the index,
etc, until we end up at the root with just a single index page.
So, searching through this index would now
work as follows: we look at the top level block,
we know that block has have fanout of up to 60.
So, among those 60 different key values,
we pick the place where the key we are searching for
either is equal to one of them or fits between two of them,
and we follow the appropriate pointer to the next level.
At that next level we have one data block,
it has a fanout of 60,
we fit in the key value where it fits,
and follow the pointer to the index plug at the next level.
Eventually, we come down to the bottom of the index level
and we need to add one in order to get to the data level.
So, in this case here,
the search time is locked but the base is not too,
the base is the fanout of the index.
That fanout is substantially higher than the
two we used for binary search in a data file.
The larger the base of the lock function is the flatter is the log function.
So, we can expect the cost here to be smaller,
and smaller, and smaller the higher the fanout is.
Using the exact numbers of our example here,
we actually see that log base 60 to 3334 is actually just two,
we add the one to it,
that's three axes at 10 milliseconds each.
That's 0.03 seconds to access a data block through this multilevel index.
The more complicated construct like this becomes,
the more levels of indices we put on top,
the more sensitive we are to overflow.
So, if we for example,
are trying to insert data at the bottom level,
and although we started out with some slot space at the end,
once we come to the point where blog actually needs to be broken up,
then the question is, is that going to have any impact on the first level index?
If it does, how far is the ripple effect going to be?
It would be important to keep the ripple effect smaller,
and that's exactly why we have some slot space built in at the end.