So, in a binary search the idea was to cut the search space in two every single time.
So, I cut it in two here so it's in half of the space,
cut that in two,
search in the half the space.
The idea of a multilevel index is that the multilevel index will allow
us to cut the search space into much smaller pieces in each step.
So, using the multilevel index,
I can illustrate as follows.
You basically take the book,
but instead of cutting in two you cut magically,
you cut in much smaller pieces like this.
Then, one of the pieces is going to qualify for continued search.
Let's say that that piece is this piece.
So see, we don't have half the book left,
we only have a tiny fraction left.
So, that piece needs to be cut down again.
We used the index at the next level and magically,
we cut it into smaller pieces.
Drop all of them except for one and we continue the search with that one.
So, continuing to search for that one, again,
we cut it in smaller pieces, and eventually,
we end up with a piece that may just be a single page.
The key value we are looking for is on that page,
if it's in the database at all.
So, that illustrates what a multilevel index does for us.