The most popular of the multi-level indices is one called a B plus Tree.
In a B plus Tree,
all the data is at the bottom and all nodes over that index nodes in multiple levels.
B plus Trees are implemented in many relational database products.
Insertion, deletion, and update operations, of course,
are provided together with those implementations to
guarantee that the B plus Tree continues to be balanced.
B stands for balanced.
So, if the tree over time would deteriorate,
so would the search time.
So, it's very, very important that the distance from
the route to the base level is the same at all times.
It is actually quite rare that an overflow at
a lower level will propagate far up the index.
Maybe once, maybe twice is what is most common,
and that in and by itself is rare.