Let me finally show you a completely different approach to primary data organization.
It's called static hashing.
The idea in static hashing is the following: You have a very large space of key values.
Think for example the email addresses of regular users.
So, that's your key value space.
You have a hash function h. The job of the hash function is to take keys from
the key value space and match them into an atlas in a pocket directory.
The addresses it can map to would be at where zero,
one, two, etc up to a minus one.
A good hash function will have the following characteristics.
First, it would need to distribute
the values that it hits uniformly or with the address space.
So, given the keys that are actually used in the application,
it would have to uniformly map to this space.
Also, it has to fill the space as much as possible because
this by itself will take more than just a few blocks and
therefore it needs to be stored somewhere and therefore a piece of it might indeed be
stored on disk and itself be subject to being ported between disk and memory.
So, it's important that pockets are full as much as possible.
Contrary to that, it's also important to avoid collisions,
and I'll explain a little bit later why it's important.
So, collisions occur when the hash function maps
actual keys that occur to the same space too many times.
Now, let's take a little bit more look at what
happens then and how the hash table is actually built.