Let me start out by telling you how the data actually get inserted.
Here no data has been inserted yet,
all we have is the bucket directory and we have space in the bucket directory to
put block addresses in that would point to the places where data records are stored.
The hash function will map that key to an address.
In this case here, it mapped it to the address two.
In address two, sits a block address that block address points to a data block.
On that data block,
we stick that first record which had that key and now we proceed like that.
It might be that additional records will go into this right now or later on
but as we look at how this evolves you're going to get data blocks gradually allocated.
Remember that several records can be stored on each block.
There might not be additional blocks added for every single record we insert.
Also remember, that as we insert the data
an important job of the hash function is to uniformly allocate that data here.
With the example that we have used we got room for about 20 records on each block.
What happened here is that we have inserted data here.
These are all partially full but now
we actually had a second time that this address was hid,
this data block here was full and therefore,
a second data block is allocated to continue to store records
that were mapped in by the hash function to this bucket directory address.
I get more filled in here.
Here's a second one that requires two levels more and more.
It proceeds like this.
Now the hash structure has been built,
the data has been inserted and now we want to use
this hash structure to find a record with a particular key value.
We take the key value,
we give it to the hash function and let's say
the hash function returns this address in the bucket directory.
In that is the block address we need to follow to get to the data block
on which the record with that key value is stored if it's in the database.
We need to access a block of the bucket directory.
We need to access a block of data and
then we'll look at whether the record is there or not.
If the bucket directory page that we need is not in
memory then it's going to cost one block access to get it up to memory.
Then following the Pointer it's going to cost us one block access to get to the data,
that's a grand total of two.
Each one, one to two of them,
each one cost 10 milliseconds.
The cost is going to be about 10 to 20 milliseconds to look-up the data on it.
It could be that a big portion of
the bucket directory would actually fit in memory and stay there.
If that's the case,
then looking this one up would basically,
we used a hash function,
we get the address of that but that we don't pay for because it already in memory.
We follow the pointer so we pay one to pull this block up and we find the record.
That's a single one,
that's only 10 milliseconds.
What is interesting about this is,
all the different look-up times we have seen they dependent on the size of the data,
dependent on the size of the index et cetera.
This one appears to be at least semi constant.
There exist dynamic hash functions that will actually allow this
adress space here to be expanded as to keep the access cost constant.
Of course, if we cannot dynamically expand and we continue
inserting data more and more and more
here than this organization is going to deteriorate.
The more data we insert with the same bucket directory size,
the longer these lists of blocks we'll get.
Notice that the way they were built was such that data is
simply inserted in the order it arrives here when we run out of space.
We go to the next one and the next one.
If change like this become 20, 50,
a 100 blocks long then the search in one of
these linked lists is actually going to be like searching in a heap.
It's very important to make sure that data is uniformly distributed.
That this has the appropriate size to guarantee that this does not get too deep.
In the previous data organization examples,
I've illustrated them by using a phone book example.
Forget about it here.
They exist no such contraption.