Let us briefly discuss why we should care what amount of
time it takes to access main memory and to access the disk.
So, main memory access time is typically
30 nanoseconds or 0.3 times ten to the power of minus seven seconds.
In comparison, disk access time is
about 10 milliseconds or 10 to the power of minus two seconds.
So, in the amount of time that it would take to do a single disk access,
you would be able to do three times 10 to the power of five main memory accesses,
that is a very large number.
It is actually so large that when we do cost computations in database access,
we completely ignore the amount of computing time that spent in main memory and
we count only disk access time or what is called the I/O cost.