Using the phone book as a metaphor,
I would like to illustrate the difference between main memory access and disk access.
Main memory access corresponds pretty well to having the book open on a page,
and then process that page.
Let us say that would take me a minute to do.
The question now is how long time would it take me to
open the book to have the next page available for processing?
There are five orders of magnitude difference between main memory access and disk access.
So, assuming it would take a minute to read this page.
It would take 200 days to open the book to the next page.
So, I read this in a minute,
and then I start opening the book,
and opening the book,
would be way into next semester 200 days from now,
I got the second page open and I read that in a minute.
That's the difference.