In order to get an understanding of how data is sitting on our disk,
let's first take a look at what a disk actually is.
So, in this example here,
you are seeing the insides of a disk.
The disk has a number of plates or platters.
For each one of the plates,
there is a read/write head that accesses
the top of the plate and one that accesses the bottom of the plate.
All of these read/write heads are connected together and are operated by an actuator.
So, what the actuator will do in order to move the read/write heads
further out or further in on the disk is that this one will turn.
So, when it turns,
then you will see that this will move further out or it will move further in.
All the platters move together.
They all sit at the same spindle and they all move together.
So, with the read/write heads in
a particular position and all of these plates spinning together,
what passes under the read/write heads is called a cylinder.
On each surface, what paces under the read/write head in that position is called a track.
So, on the surface here,
you have a track and you have
a corresponding track on every single surface under the same head position.
That collection of tracks is called a cylinder.
Each surface is split up into a number of sectors.
A sector is the smallest physical unit
that could be transported from the disk to main memory.
It consists of 512 bytes.
Typically though, blocks that will have contributions
from several sectors on them is what is transferred as unit.
Block typically will be 4K,
in other words, it contains eight sectors,
or it will be 8K or 16K depending on the type of data we decide to store on the disk.
There are several quite interesting videos out on
YouTube that shows you disks that are spun open.
Some of them show your head crashes and so on.
Here's one that's interesting.
Go take a look and be impressed when you see how fast
the read/write head moves in and out in order to transport data.
So, here's an example of a typical higher end disc pack.
It would have four plates.
Therefore, it will have eight read write heads.
It might have approximately 150,000 tracks per surface.
A track might be 1,000 kilobytes.
Total disk capacity might be 12,000 gigabytes.
As I mentioned, a sector is 512 bytes.
Disks are formatted, if it's highly formatted data,
typical block size would be 4K.
If you're dealing with fairly large less formatted objects,
you might go higher than that.
Most systems by default will come with block size of 4K.
Some major systems come with default block size of 8K.
A high end disk pack like this would typically
have a 600 megabyte per second transfer rate.
It would run with 10,000 RPMs and it would
have a latency somewhere between three and four milliseconds.