So now, we know what the disk looks like.
Let us take a look first at how records would be stored on a block on a disk.
In order to understand that,
we need to take a look at what is the size of a record?
How do we even determine that?
So, let's go back and take a look at one of
the relations we've been dealing with in our example namely,
the regular use of relation.
So, in that relation,
we have an email,
sex, birthdate, current city, hometown, attribute.
We defined previously the email to be a varchar 50.
Sex is a single character.
Datetime type is eight bytes.
Current city and hometown were both varchar 50s.
So, if you add these numbers up,
50 plus one plus eight plus 50 and 50,
you end up with a record size of 159 bytes.
So, here's a block with records allocated from this relation.
So, in position one,
would be the e-mail of the first record.
That would fill out 50 bytes.
Then, in 51, we would have the single character that represents sex.
Starting in 52, we have birthdate.
Then starting in 60,
we have the current city.
In 110, we have hometown.
Then, up at 160,
we would be ready to start the email of the second record.
So, all in all, each one takes 159 bites.