So, now we have looked at Records.
Let's take a look at the blocks they sit on.
So, with the example we used it's possible to store several records on a single block.
Let's assume that the block size is 4K and let's ignore the metadata that is on it,
that will keep information about for example where records start,
what their formats are and might contain information sources and next pointer.
We assume that we've got 4K space available for data.
Let's also assume that we run only about 80 percent full.
The reason you might want to not fill a block completely with data is,
that if there's some additional record, you need to insert,
and there's no room for it then,
you would get an overflow and then it takes extra work.
So typically, we don't run with blocks totally filled,
assuming 80 percent fill.
If you've got 80 percent fill and you got 4K block size,
then you got about 3,200 bytes with a record size of
159 that means that you will fit about 20 records per block,
leaving a little bit of space open.
So, here's record number 20.
You can see, you might be able to fill some additional records in here.
There are two ways of thinking about what happens to the piece of
a block that might not fill a complete record at the end if it comes to that.
Do we then break up the record we are trying to put in?
Put the first part here and the second part on
the next block that will be called a spanned representation.
If we just ignore the tiny amount of waste at the end,
that's called an unspanned representation.
In most cases, when multiple records,
they will fit on a block.
Most database systems will run with unspanned representation,
simply to avoid the processing that's necessary to break up records.
Obviously, if you have record sizes that are larger than block sizes,
you don't have a choice,
you have to run with a spanned representation.
So, now that we know what a block looks like,
let's address what files look like.