So here's an example of a file.
It consists of multiple blocks.
These blocks are linked together by address pointers.
The blocks may not sit right next to each other on disk,
but when we have seen one block,
we can use the next pointer to get to the place
on disk where the second block is et cetera, et cetera.
So those are all the blocks on the file.
Continuing with the example,
we can assume that block pointers are four bytes in a 32 bit architecture.
Let's say, we had four million regular users records
and we know that we could fit 20 records on a block.
So that means the number of data blocks would be four million divided by 20,
which is 200,000 blocks of data.
That also means with a block size of 4k,
it means that the file size here is about 800 megabytes.
Not a big file, not a small one either.