To be able to compute the amount of time it takes to
transport data from disk to main memory and back again,
let's just make some assumptions.
Typical seek times are between three to eight milliseconds,
rotational delays are typically between two and three milliseconds,
and transfer times may be somewhere between half a millisecond to one millisecond.
If you add these up, you get a total of five to 12 milliseconds so let us
conservatively say that a particular page fault is going to cost us 10 milliseconds.
While we will make that assumption,
we need to make the following observation.
Once we are at a particular location on a disk,
might there be a chance that instead of just picking up a single block of data,
maybe we should pick up 10, 100,
250, because we might need those next in our application?
So, bulk transfer or extent transfer would allow, for example,
250 blocks to be transferred in
one shot without paying additional seek time and rotational delay.
Once we have found the first one of the 250 blocks,
we simply just, from that point on, incur transfer time.
If we do that with our default of 10 milliseconds per page fault,
then this will take us a grand whopping total of 2.5 seconds to transfer the 250 blocks.
If, on the other hand,
we consider the savings in seek time and rotational delay,
then transferring to 250 blocks would
only cost us slightly more than a quarter of a second.
Very big difference.
One of the problems, of course,
with extent transfer of
bulk transfers is that we are probably going to need more buffer space.
When we use the buffer in general and data
moves from disk to memory and memory back to disk again,
then we need buffer management strategies.
In timeshare systems, a favorite strategy used in
buffer management is the LRU strategy or the Least Recently Used strategy.
The idea is that when we run out of buffer space and we need to
free up space for the new data coming in from disk to main memory,
then it's what is least recently used that we overwrite.
The philosophy being if we haven't used it for the longest time,
we're probably not going to use it next.
It is not always that an LRU strategy
works well from the point of view of a database management system.
It would be excellent for merge joins where two relations are
sorted on the join fields and you simply merge them together on matching keys.
However, if you're doing nested loop joins,
then LRU strategies would kill that computation and rather strategies like MRU,
or Most Recently Used,
might work well for nested loop joins.
Much more detail about the join strategies needed in order to make that decision.
I just want to give you a heads-up on the importance of buffer management strategies.