The mapping of EER diagrams to relations
will in all cases be solved in a database which is normalized.
In spite of that, we still have to learn about normalization.
"Databases are forever, they are all I need to please me,
they can stimulate and tease me,
they won't leave in the night,
I've no fear that they might desert me. "
A second reason you need to know how to normalize databases is that
the EER diagrams they may have been created from may have gone missing.
When you get a database and you look at it for the first time,
it's really like a box of chocolate,
you never know what's in there.
So when you look at a database,
it may be beautifully normalized,
designed by experts or it may not be normalized and look like it was designed by idiots.
Although it looks like that,
it could be because some compromises had to be made in the way
the database was normalized in order for example to get the database to run faster.