So, having seen all the problems with the table we started out with,
the idea is then to try to decompose that table into multiple tables,
so that the function dependencies we talked about
can be enforced in those without problems.
When we decompose the table into multiple tables,
we have to be careful though that we do not lose information.
So, look at the regular user table and let us try to decompose it into two tables.
When we do the decomposition,
we have to include at least one attribute in the two tables,
so that we can combine them back together to create the table we operated with initially.
The basic idea actually is that this may be the information we would like to
look at but the form it's represented in
with all the redundancies is all the problems that come from that,
we choose instead to operate with two alternative tables.
But at any point in time we need to be able to
re-combine them and create this look or this view,
which is the one we would like to operate with.
So, let's look at the example here.
So, we take the regular user table and project it first on the columns,
email, interest, since age,
birth year, and current city.
That gives you this table.
We then project regular use on current city and salary,
that gives you this table.
Now also, as I mentioned the idea is that when we
now join this table together with this table,
we will recreate this table here.
Unfortunately, an interesting thing happens in
this particular case with this particular decomposition.
By combining all the tuples in this relation with
all the tuples in this one we will create all of these.
But see what happens in addition to that.
This San Diego here for user3 will be combined with this San Diego here and 38.
Now, let's go look at user3,
San Diego 38, that doesn't appear there.
So, there are two additional tuples added to the result of the join from here.
Also when you look at you user12, San Diego,
that user is hooked up to 38,
but inadvertently now this San Diego will match this San Diego and 45.
So in other words, when we join these two together we actually create
three additional tuples in the regular user table that were not there before.
This phenomenon is called information loss.
You may say, come on that's a bad name for it because I got more information.
Well, getting more information that's not
reflecting facts of reality is actually information loss,
because now you're going to have three additional rows here,
and those rows do not reflect facts in reality.
Therefore, you have lost your ability to distinguish between the true facts that you
started out with and the false facts that were inadvertently added.
This is called information loss.