A similar concept called dependency loss happens as follows.
So again, look at the regular user table and split it up
as we did before in these two alternative tables.
Remember, there were a set of functional dependencies that we wanted
to enforce on this original table here.
When all the information is together in the original table,
it is possible to enforce them.
However, when we start decomposing the table into additional tables,
we may lose the ability to enforce the functional dependencies within a single table.
I have two examples of that here.
One example is that we had a functional dependency from email to salary,
since email and salary do not appear together in any of these two new tables,
we can't enforce it within a table.
Similarly, birth year determines salary,
since the two do not coexist in a table,
we cannot enforce them in a table.
This is called dependency loss.