So, having seen all of the problems that result from an inappropriate decomposition,
let's look at a perfect decomposition.
So, in this case, here,
we take the regular usual relation and decompose it into three tables.
The idea then is that we throw this one away and we operate on these,
and when we would like to see this one again,
we simply join these together and it appears as if we had
continued to operate on the regular user table in a disciplined manner.
This decomposition is perfect.
Let's analyze it.
So, first of all, you saw in the regular user table that there was a lot of redundancy.
For example, user1 living in the current city Seattle was repeated three times.
That is no longer the case,
and other instances of redundancy that we had in this relation have disappeared now.
Since there's no redundancy,
it is not possible to end up with an inconsistent database.
Let's look at some of the other problems.
There will not be any insertion anomalies anymore either because
the facts that are represented by the forms
dependencies are separated in different tables.
Therefore, you will also not have deletion anomalies because you can delete
one fact without inadvertently deleting other facts for a particular user.
There won't be any update anomalies because information is not redundant.
Also, you can check it,
but there's no information loss here.
If you join this table together with this table on email,
you will simply get the birth year and current city information appended to this table.
So, none of these joined fields,
the pair of emails,
the pair of birth years,
is going to create any additional tuples that were not in the original relation.
There's also no dependency loss.
There is a separate relation for each one of the functional dependencies we had.
Email, interest, determine since age,
email determine birth year and current city,
and birth year determine salary.
Big question is, how do we get there?
How do we understand that starting out with this,
these are the three relations that we should end up with after our decomposition?