To understand how to decompose relation in a proper manner,
we need to look at the concept of functional dependency.
So, here's the definition.
If X and Y are sets of attributes in relation, R,
then we say that Y is functionally dependent on X if and only if for each X in R,
there is precisely one Y in R. Looking at a couple of examples here,
current city is functionally dependent on e-mail if for each e-mail value,
there is precisely one current city.
Here's e-mail value, user one,
Why? Because user one is not repeated.
Because of that, it is impossible to record a second city.
User two determines a single city,
user three, a single city.
Similarly, with birth year,
for each e-mail, there is exactly one birth year.
E-mail two, birth year, 69.
E-mail user four, birth year, 88, et cetera.
Let's take a look at this from dependency e-mail and interest
together as a function determine SinceAge.
So, when you look at user one and music,
user one has been interest in music since the age of 10.
User one and music is not repeated anywhere here.
So, in this table, it is currently true that the pair
of e-mail and interest determines SinceAge.
Although it's currently true,
how do we make sure that it's always true?
We will look at that in just a little bit.