A second definition is that of a full functional dependency.
So again, let X and Y be sets of attributes in R. We say Y is
fully functional dependent on X if and only if Y is functional dependent on X,
and Y is not functional dependent on any proper subset of X.
So, let's look at the example again.
In this relation here,
we would like to represent that Email and Interest together determine SinceAge.
That is, SinceAge is not determined by Email alone,
and you can see that's true because for the three user ones,
the SinceAge has three different values.
Similarly, when you look at the interest,
for example music, is associated with different SinceAge values.
So, SinceAge is in this example fully functional dependent on Interest.
Again, as before the question is,
how do we make that continue to be true in this relation?
Here's an example of a set of forms of
dependencies that are not full functional dependencies.
So, current city is not fully functional dependent on Email and Interests.
Why not? Because it's dependent on Email alone.
So, as you see in this example here,
every single time you give a particular Email address,
there is a single city associated with it.
You do not need Email and Interest together to determine a city.
So, these are examples of non full functional dependencies.