So back to the question then,
how do you enforce functional dependencies in a relation?
The trick simply is that you use keys.
So, if you want to enforce a frontal dependency that X determines Y,
then all you need to do is you need to make X the key in that relation.
So in this case here,
making email and interest a key will guarantee that
the functional dependency email and interest to SinceAge.
This one here is enforced.
Why is that the case?
Because by making that pair the key,
there will be no duplicate values.
Since there are no duplicate values,
given a particular email an interest in
the table that will determine exactly one SinceAge,
namely the one that shows up next to it.
This example here, how do we enforce that for a particular email,
for a current user?
There is a single current city and a single birth year.
We do it by making email the key that makes these values unique.
That means that if you mention a particular email address like user3,
it's going to be in the table a single time,
and therefore it's going to have associated with it as
single birth year and as a single current city.
Third example, if you want to enforce
the function dependency birth year determines salary,
all you need to do is make birth year the key.
That means that if you mentioned a particular birth year like 67,
it's going to be in the table as single time,
and next to it is going to be the salary that's determined from it.
So all of these are functions.
There's a function from the pay of email and interest to SinceAge,
there's a function from email to birth year function from email to current city,
and finally a function from birth year to salary.