To help us recognize how well a relation is laid out,
we are going to introduce four normal forms.
First, in general, the whole set of data structures is called non-first normal form, NF2.
Most of those are not relations in the sense we have defined what a relation is.
A subset of the non-first normal form data structures
is the set of first normal form relations.
A subset of the first normal form relations is the second normal form relations.
Within the second normal form relations,
there's a subset of third normal form relations.
As a subset of the third normal form relations is
a set of Boyce-Codd normal form relations.
Boyce-Codd normal form relations are the relations we are aiming at.
I'm trying to make one additional point with this illustration here.
There are certainly first normal form relations that are not in second normal form.
There also are second normal form relations that are not in third normal form.
However, as illustrated by this small number of
relations that are in third normal form but not in Boyce-Codd Normal Form,
it is theoretically possible that you have a relation in
third normal form that's not also in Boyce-Codd normal form.
However, in practice, what happens when you
normalize relations from second normal form to
third normal form is that you get lucky and actually end up in where we want to be,
namely in Boyce-Codd normal form.
More about this to come.