So, let me now define the four normal forms.
A relation I set to be in first normal form if all domain values are atomic.
But wait, we defined a relation as a data structure
where the domain values are pulled from sets of atomic values.
So in other words, all relations are automatically born in first normal form.
A subset of the first normal form relations are in second normal form.
They are in second normal form if and only if
every non-key attribute is fully dependent on the key.
So, they are a subset of first normal form,
and every non-key attribute is fully dependent on the key.
A relation is in third normal form,
if it is in second normal form,
and every non-key attribute is non-transitivity dependent on the key.
Finally, and this is the goal,
this is the desirable normal form for relations to be in,
a relation is in Boyce-Codd normal form or BCNF,
if and only if every determinant is a candidate key.
To understand that, of course,
we need to define the concept of determinant.
So, a determinant is a set of attributes in a relation on which
some other attribute is fully functional dependent.
So, let's take a look at these normal forms,
and let's see how we progress through each one of the normal forms
when we decompose a relation to end up in Boyce-Codd normal form.
Notice that first, second,
and third normal form really not our goals in and by themselves.
Our goal is to get relations decomposed into Boyce-Codd normal form.