So, let's take a look at how we can work through normal forms,
and of course we'll continue with the example we've been using.
Here you have the function dependency diagram,
for our example database.
You have a relation which says,
email and interest in it.
Has current city, BirthYear, salary and SinceAge.
Function dependence are as follows;
email and interest together determines SinceAge,
and email alone determines current city, BirthYear, and salary.
In addition to that,
salary is also determined by BirthYear.
So, let's take the first step in decomposing that relation.
So, what I want to do is,
I want to isolate function dependencies that have different left hand sides.
So, as you see here,
since email and interest together determines SinceAge,
that's a good form of dependency to split out.
When you split out that function dependency,
you actually also see that at least this portion
of the decomposed relation is in boyce-codd normal form.
Why is that? Because the only determinant
of these three is the pay of email and interest,
and they will have to be a candidate key to enforce that functional dependency.
What else remains then is,
that we need to represent that email determines current city, BirthYear, and salary.
That's BirthYear by itself determines salary.
What form is this relation in?
Well, it is certainly in second normal reform because all of
these attributes fully depend on the key, namely email.
But unfortunately, there are transitive dependencies.
Email determines BirthYear, which in turn determines salary
resulting in the forced dependency from email to salary.
So, this is not a third normal formulation.
So, let us transform this piece of it and let us isolate out email and current city,
and BirthYear by itself.
So, you have the first relation here as,
email form determines current city and BirthYear.
What remains then is BirthYear and salary,
that you represent by itself.
So, what normal form are these relations in?
Well, there are no transitive dependencies outside of the key,
the email attribute here.
Therefore, this is certainly in third normal reform.
It is also in Boyce-Codd Normal Form,
because the only determinant in this relation is email,
and email of course is going to have to be the key to
enforce those two forms of dependencies.
So, this relation is now in Boyce-Codd Normal Form.
This relation is of course also in Boyce-Codd Normal Form.
There's no opportunity even for transitive dependencies outside of the key,
because there's only one attribute outside of the key.
So, this one is in Boyce-Codd Normal Form.