So, what is it all about?
The idea is that you are given a relation
and a set of functional dependencies like these.
Here's a relation; it has a number of columns,
Email, Interests, SinceAge, et cetera.
And there are some dependencies among these columns so-called functional dependencies,
we will define them a little bit later.
So, for example, it could be that one functional dependency is that given
an Email like here that would determine for you what the BirthYear,
CurrentCity, and Salary are.
So, given the email that would determine birth year,
current city and salary could also be that Email and Interest together would determine,
so these two together would determine the age since when you had that interest.
The big question, is this relation laid out in such a manner that it
is easy to enforce the functional dependencies that we want to enforce in the database?
An additional question is,
how do we normalize the relation or decompose it into smaller relations
without losing information and without losing functional dependencies?