To make sure that we do not lose information,
and that we preserve the functional dependencies when we decompose relations,
we need to be able to compute with meaning.
The rules for doing that are called Armstrong's rules.
The first is the rule of reflexivity.
All it says is that if Y is part of X,
then X determines Y as a function. Very simple rule.
Easy example, If Y is part of X,
in other words if the right hand side is a subset of the left hand side,
then the left hand side determines the right hand side.
The second rule is the rule of augmentation.
So, if X function determines Y,
then you can augment it with the same thing on
the left hand side or you could augment it with the same thing on the right hand side,
or you could augment it on both sides.
It will be true, in this case,
when you augment on the left hand side,
that WX function determines WY.
To show you an example of that,
let's say Email determines BirthYear,
then it will also be true that "Email,
Interest" will determine "Birth year, Interest".
Finally, very importantly, transitivity.
If X function determines Y,
and Y function determines Z,
then X function determines Z.
An example of that here is that if
Email determines BirthYear, Email determines BirthYear,
and BirthYear determines Salary, as you see here,
then Email will determine Salary by transitivity.