Question now is how do we guarantee lossless
joins when we decompose a relation into smaller relations?
Here's a very easy way to remember that and to check it.
The join field must be a key in at least one of the two relations.
So when you look at this decomposition here of relation in two relations,
then the join field between these two relations, obviously, is email.
If email is a key in one of the two relations as it is here,
then we are guaranteed not to lose information from doing this decomposition.
In other words, when we join these two relations together again over email,
then we are guaranteed to not create
additional tuples that were not there in the relation we started out with.
The simple way to understand why this is the case is that when
the join field is a key as it is here in
this one relation when the join field is the key,
there's no way of blowing duplicates in this column up with duplicates in this column,
and that was exactly what created the lossy
join that we saw in example of earlier in this lesson.