Second question is, how do we guarantee preservation of functional dependencies?
And here the simple rule is,
you're using Armstrong's rules.
The meaning implied by the remaining functional dependencies
must be the same as the meaning that was implied by the original set.
So, looking here at the decomposition of this functional dependency diagram into Email,
BirthYear and CurrentCity in one relation,
and in a separate relation BirthYear and Salary,
as you see there.
We can now, by the transitivity rule, see the following,
Email determines BirthYear from this relation,
and BirthYear determines Salary from this relation, and therefore,
by transitivity, Email determines Salary or as you see here,
that is implied and therefore,
the meaning implied by the remaining functional dependencies is the same.
So, in spite of the fact that you do not see Email determining Salary with one relation,
by the rule of transitivity,
it's implied by this decomposition.