So, let's go back to the example of a good decomposition that we did before.
Again, starting with the function dependency diagram here of our major example.
So, first, we decomposed this relation here into these two relations;
email and interests together determine SinceAge and email
determines current city BirthYear and salary email determining salary.
Is this loss less decomposition?
Well, remember the rule is that the join field,
in this case email,
must be a key in at least one of the two relations and of course
email here needs to be the key in order to enforce these functional dependencies.
So, this is a lossless join.
Is it dependency preserving? Yes, it is.
This is a very simple case to check if you look at
the dependency from email and interest to SinceAge that's directly there.
If you look at the three from email to
current city BirthYear and salary they are directly here.
If you look at the dependency,
both year to salary it can be enforced within this one relation.
So this one is dependency preserving.
So, what happens after we split this one up in these two relations?
Let's first check whether it's lossless.
So the join attribute here would be BirthYear.
BirthYear is clearly the key,
in the second relation year therefore,
the join is loss less.
Is it dependency preserving?
Yes, it is because by transitivity email determines BirthYear,
which determines salary and therefore implied in the meaning is email determines salary,
which is the only one that's actually missing.