As illustrated by the Venn diagram,
this really never happens in practice.
I'm going to show you a proof by experience.
Proof has two steps to it.
Number one: it never happened to me in 35 years.
I've designed a lot of databases in industry,
in government, and in the university,
and it never happened to me.
As a second part of the proof,
take a look at one of the bookcases in my office.
So, this one bookcase contains data-based textbooks only.
Every single one of these textbooks has in it a chapter on database normalization.
They will show you first normal form,
second normal form, third normal form,
and Boyce-Codd normal form.
Then coming to the bottom of the right page, it says, "However,
there does exist relations that can only be
decomposed to third normal form and not Boyce-Codd normal form."
With shaking fingers you turned the page to see
such an example and they change the example on you.
Why is that the case?
Because it takes a really sick brain to construct an example like that.
So, be confident if you follow the steps and bring relations through first, second,
third normal form you will be lucky and you will
end up in Boyce-Codd normal form in practice.