It's really not that difficult to envision how
you may end up with a data structure that's not
a relation or a data structure that we call a non-first normal form data structure.
So, here's an example of it.
The idea of this data structure is the following: you have users who have emails,
and then each user has a multi-value interest,
since age dependency here.
So, in this data structure you have user1.
User1 has been interested in music since the age of 10,
reading since five, tennis since 14.
Similarly, user2 has been interested in blogging since 13,
meditation since 21, surfing since 19, etc.
This is called a multi-value.
If you remember the definition of a relation,
you will remember that values of attributes are pulled from sets of atomic values.
So certainly, music 10, reading five,
tennis 14, that is not an atomic value.
So, to take a data structure like this which says
non-first normal form and create a relation from it.
There's one obvious way we could try to do that.
So, what if I simply repeat user1 for each one of these rows?
What if I repeat this value in each one of the rows?
Then I will actually have a relation.