So, that's exactly what I've done here.
You can see user1 is now repeated three times, and 1985, Seattle,
and 27,000 is repeated three times,
and it's done to avoid having this be a multi-value,
and avoid having this be a multi-value.
So this indeed now is a relation,
but it is really a relation with many problems in it.
So, let us say that in this relation,
we want to enforce these three function dependencies that we looked at before.
Or an easier way to see what they are is actually to provide a drawing of them like here.
So, what we are seeing here is that email will determine current city,
birth year, and salary,
and the pair of email and interest will determine the since age,
and finally we see that birth year will determine salary.
So that corresponds to those three functional dependencies.
So, with that relation and with these functional dependencies,
let's see what kind of trouble we are in.