So, the first problem the relation has, is redundancy.
Because we repeat it,
all the user1 information;
birth year, current city,
and salary, in order to avoid the multi value problem you now have redundant information.
Redundancy potentially leads to inconsistency.
Inconsistency here would appear,
if user1 moves say,
from Seattle to Atlanta but for whatever reason,
you do not get all the Seattle values updated to Atlanta,
maybe just the first one.
Subsequent to that, users of the database will come in,
and they will look for the current city of user1 and in one place it will say Atlanta.
In other places it will say Seattle.
That means, the database is useless from the point of view
of understanding what the current city of the user is.