The next relationship type we'll look
at is a many to many relationship type,
or an N to M relationship type.
You can see it's a many to many
relationship type when the cardinalities
here are described on
the lines of the relationship.
So this is a many to many relationship
type between regular users and
the schools they attended.
Again, let's take a look
at the instance diagram.
So here we have five
regular users shown.
Here we have a a bunch of schools shown.
The relationships here demonstrate
that this regular user here has
attended these four schools.
This regular user, this one school.
This regular user here, these schools.
But see what happens now when we're
dealing with many to many relationship
types.
So notice now that one element here,
this regular user here may have
attended these four schools, but
notice that this school here
actually has three regular users
who have attended that school.
So in other words, any single element
here may be mapped to multiple
elements over here, and any single
element over here may be mapped to
multiple elements on the left
side as is shown here.
No longer do we have a function here.
This is a relationship in
the mathematical sense of the word.