So far all the relationship types
we have looked at have been binary.
We are now going to look at an N-ary
relationship type with N greater
than two.
In this case here,
the event team member relationship
type is a ternary relationship type.
It relates three entity types,
regular user, team, and event.
The semantics of this
ternary relationship type
is somewhat complicated.
Let's try to analyze
exactly what it means.
Let us fix email to be a single value.
Let us fix event name
to be a single value.
So now we have a pair of one
regular user and one event.
Because this is many on this one
here it means that a particular
regular user in a particular event
may participate on many teams.
Now let's fix event name and
let us fix team name.
Again, since these are the identifiers,
event name is going to give us a single
event, and team name is
going to give us a single team.
Holding onto that pair, you see
that there are many regular users.
Finally, let's now fix an email,
and let's fix a team name.
So now we have a pair of one
regular user and one team,
and we see here that there are N
events that that particular
regular user being on that
team may be participating in.
So the meaning of an instance
of this relationship type event team
member really is the following.
A particular regular user on
a particular regular team
participates in one particular event.
The implication of that is,
that you need email and event name and
team name to identify precisely a single
instance of this relationship type.
It's quite rare that you see
examples of relationship types that
are degree higher than two.
I think one of the reasons for that is
that they are difficult to understand,
they are difficult to explain.
Unfortunately, the problem is,
that it is not always possible
to take an N-ary relationship
type with N three or greater, and
decompose it into a conjunction
of binary relationships.
We'll look at that next.