So in this example, what I've done,
is I revised the single relationship
type we had here to basically three
different binary relationship types.
So here, you see Regular User,
while the User Team relationship
is hooked up to Team.
Team is hooked up to
Event by Team Event, and
Event is hooked up to
Regular User by User Event.
What would the meaning of
these relationships be?
Well, this one would merely state that
a regular user is on a particular team.
It would state that regular user
participates in some event.
It would state that in some event,
particular teams are participating.
But those three facts together,
do not cover that a particular
user on a particular team
participate in a particular event.
That's space is much, much more narrow
than what is illustrated by these.