Let us now take a look at
identifying relationships types and
weak entity types.
In this example we have two entity
types, regular user and status updates.
We have an identifying property type,
email, and
we have another property type,
date and time.
The idea of this example is as follows,
regular users,
they can post multiple status updates
during the day to their website.
Status updates, when they are posted,
will have a date and
time associated with them.
However, other users could potentially
post status updates at the same
date and time.
So, what we need to model is that
each status update in addition
is identified by the email of
the regular user that posted it.
And then of course needless to say,
date and time need to have a fine
enough granularity that is
physically impossible for
a regular user to post to
at the same date and time.
So, here's how we identify
a particular status update.
We need the email, and
we need the date and
time in order to identify
an individual status update.
So, email, date, and time together
will identify a status update.
On the other hand since
it's not plausible
to uniquely identify a status
update just by date and time,
every single status update that is
an instance of this entity type
must be hooked up to a regular user so
that we have the email available.
So, status update cannot exist without
being hooked up to a regular user.
That's why we call that
entity type weak because
instances cannot exists
without them being hooked up.
And we say that this is
an identifying relationship type
because in order to get to a unique
status update, we need to go through
the email of regular user and
combine that with date and time.
The fact that this one is not in and
by itself, a unique identifier,
as illustrated by the dotted line here.
And this is called a partial identifier.