What you see here is
a recursive relationship type.
It's called recursive because it
relates an entity type to itself.
So you have the AdminUser
entity type here with
properties Email which is identifying
and then a SinceDate property,
a SinceDate When that adminUser became
the supervisor for
another adminuser who is the supervisee.
As you see here, a couple of extra
things are added to our notation.
First of all, there's a direction
to the lines of the relationship.
Second we add roles to
the relationship sides.
Why do we do that?
We do that because when we have
one instance of an admin user,
we need to know whether that admin
user plays the role of supervisor or
supervisee in the manages relationship.
So let us illustrate that
with an instance diagram.
So take a look at these seven
instances of admin users and
let's see how they are related
to each other in this hierarchy.
So what you see in this hierarchy
is that this admin user instance
is the supervisor and manages this admin
user who is the supervisee then,
apparently, of that admin user.
This admin user is the supervisor
of this one and he or
she is the supervisor of this one.
And at this node,
supervisee of this supervisor Is
this person and here's another one.
The person here is the supervisee
of that supervisor.
So this is the manager's hierarchy
that you see among the admin
users in this example.