Let us look at super subtypes or
is-a relationship types
as they are also called.
Here we have the entity type of user and
we have two subtypes of user,
regular user and admin user.
A RegularUser is a User and
an AdminUser is a User.
We also have Female users and
a Female User is a User and
a Male User is a User.
Let's look at the instance diagram
to understand the semantics
of this relationship type.
So here we have two instances of Male
Users, three instances of Female Users.
As you can see,
everyone of the Male Users and
everyone of the Female Users
is also a User.
In other words there are no
instances of Male and
Female Users that are not also a User.
None of these users are both in the set
of Female Users and Male Users.
Why is that the case?
That's because we have insisted on
enforcing a disjointness constraint.
And that means that the two
subtypes cannot overlap.
Now let's look at the instances in the
Subtype of RegularUser and AdminUser.
Again you see that you
cannot have a user
who's a regular user
without also being a user.
So every single one of
these also appear up here.
Neither can you have an AdminUser who
does not appear as a User up here.
But notice that it is actually
possible to have a user
who is both a RegularUser and
an AdminUser reflecting
that this constraint here allows
that the two subtypes overlap.