Those of you who are familiar with
object oriented programming languages
are also familiar with
the concept of inheritance.
So take a look at this example.
As before, we have users with subtypes
of RegularUser and AdminUser.
And User has subtypes of Female and
Male.
In general for users,
we have two property types.
We have Email, which is the identifying
property type, and we have Password.
So that means that every single
user has an Email and a Password.
Well of course that means that a regular
user will also have an Email and
a Password.
So will an AdminUser.
So will a Female user and a Male user.
In contrast to that, RegularUsers
will have BirthDates and CurrentCity.
For AdminUsers, we just record and
store their LastLogin of the AdminUser.
As I mentioned before,
when you look at a RegularUser,
that RegularUser will have an Email and
a Password.
But also immediately visible
will be BirthDate and
CurrentCity because these are local
properties of RegularUser.
When you look at an AdminUser,
that AdminUser will have an Email and
a Password, but
also the local property LastLogin.
As opposed to that,
when you look at a User,
the only property types you can
see are Email and Password.
So, for a User,
it is not plausible to see BirthDate,
CurrentCity, or LastLogin.
So, we say that regular User and
AdminUser will inherit
the properties Email and Password,
as will Female users and Male users.