In this example I'm showing
a relationship type current job
between employer and regular user.
The point I want to make here
is that the employer may be
one of two different kinds of entities.
It could either be a company,
which is the employer, or
it could be a government agency,
which is the employer.
In case the employer is a company,
then an attribute EIN,
which is a tax identification number, is
needed to be attached with the employer.
In case the employer is the government
agency, then we need an agency ID,
which may be a composite property type
consisting of the agency name and
which municipality it's in.
The employer type in this case
is called a union entity type.
So there are two important rules
associated with union entity types.
The first one is that employer
is a subset of company union
government agency.
So, in other words, they are not
going to exist any employers that
are not either a company or
a government agency.
The second rule is that
the intersection between company and
government agency is empty.
So it is not plausible
to have an employer,
which at the same time is both
a company and a government agency.
So let's take a look.
Here's the set of
instances of companies.
Here's the set of instances
of government agencies.
Here's the set of instances of
employers at a given point in time.
So let's try to find out what it
means now to satisfy these two rules.
So as you see with this instance
diagram here, we obey the rule that
the set of employers must be a subset
of company union government agency.
And you can see, actually in this
case here, there's a proper subset.
There is one company in the instance
diagram, which is not an employer.
And there are two government agencies
that are not employers in this database.
However, every single element of
the employer entity type instances,
ie they're from one or from the other.
Let's look at the intersection here.
As you can see, there are none of
the elements in the employer entity type
instance set that comes
from both of these types.
So we are also, in this instance,
satisfying this role.