So the first question is,
are relationships entities, or
are they just glue that
tie together entities?
So in this example we have two
entity types, employer, and
regular user, and a relationship type,
current job between them.
And, it's a one to
many relationship type.
Now as you notice,
this relationship type has a property
type current job since date.
But, if the relationship
type has a property type,
isn't it then an entity type?
If we can accept that relationship
types have properties,
then fortunately in this one to many
case, there is an acceptable solution.
Take a look at these two
instances of employer.
So in this case here, this employer
here has two regular users,
this one and this one.
This second employer here has
three regular users that have
current jobs under that employer,
this one, and this one, and this one.
You can think about the values of
the properties of the relationship type,
as values that label the connection
between employer and regular user.
So this d1 would be the date,
the current job since date,
of this regular user,
under that employer.
And likewise,
d2 would be the current job since date
between that employer and
that regular user.
Since these are hierarchies,
instead of actually labeling
the relationship instances between them,
we could simply move the date d1 down
here, and the date d2 down here.
It would not be possible
to move the current job
since date up to be
a property of employer.
The reason that would not be possible
is then all the regular users employed
by that employer would have
to have the same date.
So the solution in this case,
as mentioned here,
is that the current job since date
becomes a property of regular user.
So basically, this one disappears, and
instead it becomes
a property of regular user.