The first symbol of the Extended
Entity-Relationship Model I'm going to
introduce to you is
that of an entity type.
This is a time-invarying
representation of a set of users.
For each one of the symbols that
I'm going to introduce to you,
I'm also going to show you
what the semantics is.
This symbol is part of
the Extended Entity-Relationship Model.
This is not.
This is just my attempt at
explaining to you what it means.
So at any given point in
time there is a set of users
that we have captured in our model.
Each one of these dots
represents such a user.
We have previously
talked about surrogates.
Think about these as surrogates.
They are the substance inside the system
that represent users
out in the real world.
So, here, I got four, seven,
nine users represented.
It is important that within one
entity-relationship diagram,
All entity type names must be unique.
So it is not plausible to have
multiple entity types, for
example, with the name user.