What needs to happen is the schools
attended need to be an entity type as
opposed to a relationship type.
We call that an objectified
relationship type.
So, schools attended is
now a relationship type.
The GPA property type is a property
type of that entity type.
Now, we need to model the two
relationship types that are necessary
in order to get the same
functionality or
cardinality of the mapping between
the regular user and school.
The way that is done is
that you introduce two,
one to many relationships.
One from regular user
to schools attended and
one from school to schools attended.
That functionality,
the two one-to-many relationship type,
that meet in the middle,
is going to result
in a many-to-many relationship type
between regular user and school.
So here we have regular user instances.
And here we have schools
attended instances.
As you can see,
a regular user here maps to multiple
schools attended via this
one-to-many relationship type.
Here's another example of that.
Now let's look at school
to schools attended.
Again, that's a one-to-many
relationship type.
This one maps to one,
which is one example of many.
This one here maps to many.
This one here does not map.
Now, let's convince ourselves
that this action, in the end,
results in a many-to-many relationship,
between regular user and
school, exactly like we
were supposed to have.
So take a look at this
particular regular user here,
how many schools does that user map to?
Well maps to these two
schools attended and
this one maps to that school and
this one here maps to that school so
that means that this one
maps to multiple schools.
Adversely, take a look at
this particular school here.
Here are two of the the instances
of schools attended, and
this one matched to that user,
this one matched to that user.
Thus, this school here maps
to multiple regular users.