Let's take a look at
a beautiful car here.
A car is composed from
many many components.
Let's take a look at the drivetrain.
So here as you can see
you've got the engine and
you've got the clutch,
the transmission right behind that.
Here's the driveshaft,
it's a rear wheel drive car.
Your differential,
one of the axles has shock.
These are all parts of a car.
If you look at an instance
of a drivetrain,
then that instance is composed from
instances of the component parts.
So you will need
an instance of an engine,
an instance of a clutch,
an instance of a transmission
in order to actually compose
an instance of a drive train.
How do you model that in the EER model?
Unfortunately the answer is, you can't.
So the entity relationship model does
not explicitly support aggregation.
Of course you can force it and use
existing types, relationship types etc.
But that's like playing object
oriented programing in C,
it might be a good idea but
it's not supported by any kind of tool.