Let's say we want to print a list of
information about regular users and
the schools they attended.
The information we would like to
come out in the result could be,
say, their email address,
their first name,
their last name, and the school name.
And this is for regular users and
the schools they attended.
What's the type of that query?
Well, it's a list of properties.
But a list of properties is not a type.
It's not an entity type,
it's not a relationship type,
it's not a super sub type,
it's not a property.
So there is no type to
capture this result.
The essential observation that comes
out of that is that since the result
doesn't have a type, there is no way
that we can take that result and
continue to operate on it
with a query language.
So the query I just asked
does not have a type and
therefore what I used was
not a closed query language.
Query languages have to be closed.
It's the only way we can
formulate high level ideas and
ask high level questions.
It is actually the reason we don't
run around in loin cloth anymore.
Later on, when we look at relations
database you'll see elegant,
powerful examples of
closed query languages.
In my opinion the lack of a generally
agreed upon closed query language for
the extended entity relationship model
is the reason that database management
systems are not based on the extended
entity relationship model