So whenever we look at a data model
we know there are three
things we need to look at.
We need to look at data structures.
We need to look at constraints.
We need to look at operations.
There are two fundamental notations
that can be used to express operations
in relational databases relational
algebra and relational calculus.
We'll look at both of those.
There are actually two
calculi notations.
One is tuple calculus.
The other one is domain calculus.
In the first case it's tuples of
relations that are the variables.
In the second one it's cells of
domains that are the variables.
Sequel, or SQL which we will
talk a lot about later,
is an example of a tuple
calculus language.