Second we are going to
talk about property types.
Property types
are represented by ellipses.
These ellipses carry names.
So for the user entity type we just
introduced I have here shown you
two single valued properties.
The fact that this is a single line
ellipsis signifies that it
is a single valued property.
The first property here has the name,
Email, second property here
has the name, Password.
So let us look at the instance diagram.
So here you see there
are three instances of user.
And the first user is Leo and
that user has the password qwerty.
The second user is Rocky,
has the password Lydia.
And the last user is Jim who
has the password Fido123.
So what are property values?
They can take many forms.
They can be lexical,
as you can see here,
we've used letters to represent them.
They could be any other form
of visible element, I mean,
it could be a picture of a user.
They could be audible.
In other words, you can say what they
are without writing them down, without
showing a picture, but it's just the
audible, the sound of it that's used.
It's interesting to see that,
whereas the instances of user
are just surrogates, just representing
user, when you look at values,
for example, of Email,
not only is it a thing in and
by itself, but it's actually
a thing that names something.
In this case,
it actually names the password.