So let's first talk about data
structures of the relation model,
as opposed to the extended
entity relationship model.
Which had all kinds of notations to
capture structures from entity types,
to property types, to relationship
types, to super sub types, etc.,
there is only one structure
in relation databases.
Namely, relations.
So guess what you're going to use if
you're going to capture entity types,
property types, relationship types,
super sub types?
Yep, you're right,
you're going to use relations.
So a domain is a set of atomic values.
Atomic values that from the point of
view of the database management system,
has no meaning inside of it.
In other words nothing
is coded in the values,
they are just values without
meaning that we want to represent.
You can think about the set
of atomic values as a type.
Now a relation R is a subset of the set
or ordered n-tuples defined here.
So this set of ordered n-tuples
of which the relation is a subset
is constructed as follows.
Each one of the elements in the tuple,
in element D I,
is pulled from
the corresponding domain D I.
It is absolutely essential to
notice that a relation is a set,
the concept of an attribute is very
important in a relation databases.
Basically, attribute names
are used to explain or
to interpret the role of
a domain in a relation.
A great advantage of having unique
names of attributes within a relation
Is that now, instead of referring to
the position of a column in a table
by using the unique attribute name,
you can now refer to it by naming.