Let's now look at some
of the constraints.
So we have keys and primary keys.
There are some consequences of
defining in particular primary keys.
Two consequences are the consequence
of entity integrity and
referential integrity.
To explain those,
let's take a look at an example.
So we have a regular user table
here with email, birthday, sex,
current city and home town.
And we have the more general table here
of users with attributes email and
password represent the list of
users that exist in reality
about whom we are capturing
information in the database.
So this is an existence list.
This case here, we have chosen
to use emails as the unique
identifiers for users as opposed to,
for example, using surrogates.
Email is called the primary
key of the user table.
There's an important consequence
of being a primary key.
And that is that no value of email
is allowed to be the null value.
There's another important implication
and that is, whenever something,
which is a primary key somewhere else,
like email here,
when that's used in another table like
here, the following must be obeyed.
The set of email addresses
that appear here in this table
must be a subset of the email
addresses that appear here.
So this must be a subset of this.