Some property types
are identifying property types.
That's shown by underlining
the name of the property type.
Let's look at what that means
in the instance diagram.
So here you have again a user
with a name leo@gt.edu.
Got another user Rocky,
you got a third user Jim.
The constraint that email
be an identifying property
has the following implication.
When you point to a particular value,
like leo@gt.edu,
there can be only a single entity
instance identified by that email value.
So what would not be possible is
that given a value of email here,
that this would point to two
different instances of user.
So that's not possible.
It is important to understand that
every single entity instance in
the database at any given point in
time must be uniquely reference-able.
It was very easy and
very simple to see in this case here
where you just have one identifying
property type that is used to uniquely
identify the identity instances.
Later on we going to see cases
where multiple property types and
even in some situations
relationship types are needed
in order to uniquely reference
instances of entities.