The next property type we're going to
look at is a multi-valued property type.
Multi-valued property types are modeled
by the the double ellipsis.
So here we have a regular user who has
a multi-valued property type interest.
Let's look at the instance
diagram again.
So here you have your regular users.
There are four instances of those.
Here is a multi-value, so
this one multi-value consists
of reading, chess and math.
Those are the interests
of the first user.
This third user he is
interested in biking.
Notice that that's also a multi-value.
That's acceptable,
although it's just one.
The last user here has a whole
bunch of interests, soccer, beer,
cricket and baseball.