We've now seen the concept of an entity
type, and we've several different
property types, let's now turn our
attention to relationship types.
Relationship types
are represent by diamonds.
So here in this example, we have
two entity of types, male user and
female user, and they are connected by
the relationship type, current marriage.
This notation here is
the carnality of that relationship.
It says that this relationship, current
marriage, is a 1-1 relationship type.
Let's add the instance diagram
to see what that means.
So here we have four instances of
maleuser and we have six femaleuser.
As you can see, this maleuser here is
currently married to this femaleuser.
This user here may be
married to this femaleuser.
And this user here is currently
Notice that there are a couple of
maleusers here that are currently not
married.
And notice there are three femaleusers
here that are currently not married.
So since there are instances
of maleuser and
instances of femaleuser that are not
married, this function here or
this mapping between these two
entity types is a partial function.
Why is it a function?
It's a function because for
each one of the elements here,
there's at most one element
over here that it's mapped to.
It's partial because there are some
that are not mapped to anything.
If we were to have two relationship
types between the same two entity types
then they would clearly have
to have different names so
we can distinguish between them.