The next relationship type we
need to talk about is the one
to many relationship type.
So here we have an example of
a relationship type between employer and
the regular users that work for
employers.
It's called a one to many relationship
type for the following reason.
Let's look at the surrogate C or
D instances of employer, and
the instances representing
regular users.
Then it's a one to many, because each
surrogate of employer can be hooked up
to zero, one, or
more instances of regular user.
So let me connect a couple more.
So this employer here
may be the employer that this
regular user works for and
may be the employer that
this regular user works for.
This employer here may be the employer
that this regular user works for.
So when you look at this, being at one
to many relationship type means that
there's a partial function from
the set of surrogates representing
regular users to the set of
surrogates representing employers.
It's partial because it's not every
single regular user that's met by it.
So you see here there are some
regular users that are not working for
any employer what so ever.
It is also the case that
there are some employers,
that do not have any regular
users working for them.
That's not related to it being
a partial function, of course.
Being a partial function
means that each one of these
is mapped to at most,
one employer on this side.