A variation of a 1-N relationship
type is one that's
constraint to be mandatory.
Show you an example of that here.
The bold solid line
signifies that regular user
mandatorily must
participate in current job.
Let's take a look at what that means
when we look at the instances.
So we have a set of employers over here.
We have a set of regular
users over here.
When you look at this 1-N relationship
type here you see that, for
example, this employer here
has two regular users working,
this one has one, this one has four.
There are a couple of employers here
that have no one working for them.
But notice that all the regular users
that are instances of that type,
that they must be hooked up via
that relationship to an employer.
So not only is it a passive function
from regular user to employer.
It's even a total function.