Let's look at a projection now.
Let's say, we want to find just some of the columns of the regular user table,
namely email, birth year,
and sex for regular users in Atlanta.
So, it is a projection.
We can't use to star wild card.
It is a projection on only some of the columns of the regular user table.
So, in other words,
the result from this query here is going to have three columns,
e-mail, birth year, and sex in that order.
So, going through then the regular user table,
we're going to have to look at where hometown equals Atlanta.
It does here, so that means that user1,
85 and male is at row in the result.
User4 hometown is Atlanta,
so user4, 88, and male is in the result.
Finally, user6, 88 female is in the result.