When we looked at Relational Algebra and Calculus I
emphasized many many times that relations are sets,
and that the result of a query is always a relation and therefore, a set.
In SQL, tables may have duplicate rows.
Let me talk about the keyword 'Distinct'.
So let's say I want to find a sex for regular users in Atlanta.
The query to do that is as follows.
SELECT sex, FROM RegularUser,
WHERE HomeTown equals 'Atlanta'.
Looking at the RegularUser table and the rows where HomeTown equals Atlanta,
you see that user one satisfies that.
So, male is part of the result.
So is male a second time for user four and so is female for user six.
So here, male appears twice.
If you want to avoid the duplication,
here's the way to do that.
You use the keyword Distinct around the attribute that you want returned.
So, in this case, the result is the same except duplicates are eliminated.
So, you get just the row male and female returned.