Let me use the same example I just used for
natural inner join to show you the important concept of aliases.
So as before, you want to find Email,
BirthYear, and Salary for RegularUsers who have a Salary.
We want to do that by combining the RegularUser data with the YearSalary data.
So, an alternative way of writing that query is as follows:
We're going to involve two tables, RegularUser and YearSalary.
But notice here that for the purpose of this query,
for the scope of this query,
instead of calling it RegularUser,
we are using the alias R instead.
Instead of calling it YearSalary,
we are using the alias Y.
Now, within this query from the first SELECT,
we can now use R and Y instead of RegularUser and YearSalary.
So up here in the SELECT line,
we're going to select Email and R.BirthYear,
Salary, and the condition is that R.BirthYear equals Y.BirthYear.
So the idea here behind the query then is as follows,
and this is why this is a very interesting query and why aliases are important.
So remember in the Tuple calculus,
we worked with Tuple variables.
R and Y, in this case,
are exactly Tuple variables.
So when we introduce R here to range over RegularUser,
think about it as R taking on the value of each
one of these rows in turn joined the query evaluation.
Similarly with Y, we'll take on these row values one at a time,
and then for each pair starts S. For example,
user1@gt.edu, '85, male is one instantiation of that,
here's an instantiation of the YearSalary alias
Y they combine here and therefore they create this Tuple here.
So that's the whole idea,
R and Y are Tuple variables.
There are some other advantages, of course,
it saves typing; some SQL queries get really, really long.
If you have ROLLUP queries,
they could be several pages of print out text.
One important thing that aliases are also used for is to disambiguate table references.
In particular, aliases must be used if you join a table with itself so you can
disambiguate between the first of two tables
in the join and the second one of the tables in the join.
I strongly recommend using aliases when you write queries.
it's just a great way to think,
and you are then aided in your understanding by thinking Tuple calculus.