Let's see how we do the left outer JOIN in SQL.
So, the example we used was find email, birth year,
and salary for regular users who have a salary by
combining regular user data and year's salary data,
but return email and birth even when the regular user has no salary.
It's called an outer JOIN because as opposed to an inner JOIN,
the only tuples from a regular user and year salary that would
be combined are those that actually match up on the JOIN condition.
So, here's how you write that query in SQL.
Select email regularuser.BirthYear,Salary from regular user left outer JOIN year salary.
Notice again, that algebra has snogged into this query.
You get user1 here combined through matching years.
The first table you get user2 combined through the 69 for this result.
You get user3 matching 67 to give the third row in the result.
But, now look, user4,
six, eight, and nine,
the years do not match birth year of year salary.
So therefore, for those four last tuples,
we do get user4 and 88,
but there is no salary to match a doc with.
So, in each one of those cases a null value is put in.