Until now, most of the SQL questions we have looked at have
been just SQL versions of relational algebra queries.
There was one exception and that was distinct.
So, SQL databases are real practical tools.
They need to have capabilities that you have not
seen before in relational algebra and calculus.
The second one of those is a string matching capability.
So, consider a query like this;
find data about RegularUsers who live in a CurrentCity that
starts with San and is followed by something.
Here's how you write that in SQL.
Select Email, Sex, CurrentCity from RegularUser,
where CurrentCity is like San % sign.
So, % sign will match any string.
That actually, includes the empty string.
So, San % sign is going to match San and
it's going to match San followed by anything of any length.
So, let's take a look at that query.
What is the result going to be?
So, it's on CurrentCity and we are going to return Email,
Sex and CurrentCity but only if the beginning of the CurrentCity matches San.
So, that's certainly not the case for Seattle.
It's certainly the case for San Diego,
starts with San, ends with Diego.
So, user3 with sex male,
and CurrentCity San Diego,
is part of the answer to the query.
User4 , San Francisco, same thing.
User6, San Diego, is part of the result.
Las Vegas, no.
College park, no.
There are more types of wildcards.
Don't confuse these wildcards with the style
wildcard we use in this select line to select all attributes.
So, this one here matches the front and you can follow by % sign.
You could put that % in other places too.
Here's a somewhat different one.
This one says, select Email,
Sex, HomeTown from RegularUser,
where the HomeTown is like A followed by underscore,
underscore, underscore, underscore underscore.
Five underscores.
Each one of these underscores will match exactly one character.
So, we are in other words looking for RegularUsers that have
a HomeTowns that start with A and are followed by five additional characters.
So, is that the case with Atlanta?
No. It starts with A,
but then there are six additional characters.
Fourth and forget about it.
Atlanta, Atlanta, Atlanta.
Austin starts with A,
followed by 5 characters.
So, user12 who has HomeTown Austin qualifies in the result.