Sorting, oh no.
Another one of those practical things.
But if you print out from an SQL query,
say a phone number list,
don't you want that sorted by say, last name?
So from a practical perspective,
although it's not part of algebra and calculus,
you do need ability to sort an output.
Let's say you want to find data about regular users who are males,
and you want to sort the data by ascending current city.
So, we select emails, sex,
and currency city from regular user for males
and we order the result by current city ascending.
So, what is the result going to look like?
Well, it's only the males that are involved here.
So, this tuple is going to qualify,
this tuple is going to qualify,
this one, and this one.
So, we know there are four tuples in the result.
Now, it needs to be sorted by current city.
So, the first output will be the row Austin,
then San Diego, then San Francisco, and finally Seattle.
It is possible to sort on multiple columns.
You can sort ascending and or descending.