Now, let's see how you would do an operation corresponding to an algebra Union in SQL.
Actually, now, we have gotten so used to algebra being involved in many SQL queries,
I'm not even gonna sound that alarm for you anymore.
So let's say you want to find all current cities in hometowns without duplicate.
How do we do that?
Well, we do one query that says select currency from regular user,
do another query that says select hometown from regular user,
and we say Union between them.
Does not get much simpler than that.
So basically, here, it's a projection on current city and from the same table,
it's a projection on home town and then it's the set Union of the two,
and notice in this case here that there are no duplicates.
So where as SQL queries in general may return duplicates?
The semantics of the Union intersection and
set difference operators is that sets are returned.
In case you do want to see cities as many times as they occur,
here is the way to do that.
Instead of saying Union,
as you do over there, you say Union All, same query.
In this case, here in the Union All result,
you will get one, two, three,
four, five, six, seven, eight, nine,
10 rows in your result,
and that will of course include some duplicates like Atlanta,
just as hometown, is here three times.
So you're going to see Atlanta three times in this result.
Union All is what makes that [inaudible].