Now, let's look at intersection in SQL.
So, let's say we want to find all cities that are CurrentCity's for
someone and HomeTown's for someone,
not necessarily the same person and do not include duplicates.
In SQL, that looks like this,
Select CurrentCity from RegularUser,
Select HomeTown from RegularUser,
intersects them while we turn a set.
So, when you look here,
which cities are going to be CurrentCity for someone and HomeTown for someone,
not necessarily the same person,
while Seattle will not because not HomeTown for anyone.
Austin will because Austin appears here and it appears here and it appears here.
So, Austin is going to be part of the result.
San Diego is not,.
San Francisco, yes, San Francisco is
here and San Francisco is here so it's part of the result.
College Park, no.
Austin is all ready included in the result.
So a set returned as before.
If you want to see all cities as many times as they appear,
then you say Intersect All.
So, the only difference between the results here and
the results here now is that Austin is counted twice.
Why is that?
Well, as you see here,
Austin is the CurrentCity for two people and Austin is also the HomeTown for two people.
So, that is why Austin appears twice in the Intersect All.