Finally, set operator Except expressed in SQL.
I want to find all cities that are CurrentCity's,
but we want to exclude those that are HomeTown's.
Again, we want to set return without duplicates.
So, same deal, Select CurrentCity from RegUser.
Select HomeTownfrom RegUser.
Return the result of the first query
except those that appear in the Result of the second query.
So, let's look at what the result of this query is.
So, Seattle is in the Result as you see up here because it's not a HomeTown for anyone.
Las Vegas is in the Result. Same reason.
San Diego is not in the Result because it's a HomeTown for User form.
San Francisco is in the Result,
it's not a HomeTown for any of these users.
San Diego, is still not in it because it's a hometown.
Las Vegas, already is in it and there are no duplicate returned.
So, the result of this query in this table is here.
Let's now take a look at what happens if we want to consider duplicates.
So, the same way we did before instead of writing Except to return a Set,
we now say Except All and the number of occurrences in
the two operand intermediate results will now play a role in what comes back.
So, Seattle as before, is in the Result.
It's not a HomeTown for anyone.
This Las Vegas is in the Result.
San Diego is going to be in the result because San Diego
appears here and here that's twice and it appears one time over here,
2 minus 1 is 1.
So, San Diego is now in the Result.
San Francisco is there for the same reason it was before.
How about Las Vegas?
Well, we already have Las Vegas here.
It's not a HomeTown for anyone.
So, the second time it appears here,
it's also in the Result.