Let me give you a brief history of SQL or Sequel as many people call it.
SQL was actually the original name standing for Structured English Query Language.
SQL was part of System R which was
a research relation database prototype released by IBM in 1973.
SQL was created by Chamberlin and Boyce.
So, name was changed to SQL which stands for Structured Query Language.
SQL is based on relational tuple calculus and some algebra.
By the way, do you know what mermaid's square?
Algebra.
They are both ANSI and ISO standards for SQL.
SQL1, first version was standardized in '86,
and then a revision in '89,
what is now we referred to as SQL2,
was published in '92,
and in '99 followed SQL3.
There have been a number of revisions here every two to three years since then.
In most of the cases,
the fundamental part of SQL is as good with a standard is the same,
but these revisions have added a lot of functionality for temporal queries,
spatial queries, and other things.
SQL is supported by a large,
large number of database products.
IBMs, DB2 which was actually a commercial version of System R,
Oracle, Sybase, SQL Server,
MySQL, and many, many more,
and they all support the standard SQL or they do that. We'll get back to that.