To continue talking about functionality,
which is very useful in real life databases,
let's consider the concept of built-in functions.
So, count, sum, average, minimum,
and maximum are all examples of built-in functions.
Let's take a look at one.
Let's say, I want to count the number of RegularUser's.
In other words, count how many RegularUser's there are.
In SQL, that's written as follows,
SELECT count everything from RegularUser.
So, the semantics is as follows,
we've got user 1, 2, 3,
4, 6, 8 and 9.
That's a total of seven users.
So, the result here is a table with a single column,
and a single row,
and the number seven in it reflecting that there are seven rows in the RegularUser table.
Let's look at a second example, max.
Let's say, we want to find Email and BirthYear for the youngest Female RegularUser.
It would look like this.
Find Email and max(BirthYear) from RegularUser where Sex equals Female.
So, let's take a look here at BirthYear and let's find out what the max(BirthYear) is.
See '85. '69? No. '67? No. '88 is younger than '85. '88, '68, '88.
So, turns out that there are three users that have birth year '88.
Two of those are females, user6 and user9.
So, the result is user6 '88, user9 '88.