Sometimes, you would like to group the data that comes back from
a query in groups and then apply some simple calculations within each group.
Let's look an example.
Let's say one of group user interests on email.
Then let's say, that for each one of those groups,
we want to return the corresponding email,
the number of interest that user has together with
the average SinceAge of those interests for that user.
And then, maybe you want to sort of result by ascending number of interests.
That query is expressed as follows.
We want to select email and count(*).
We want to return that count in our column which we give the name,
NumInt for number of interests and,
we want to return the average SinceAge in a column that we like to name average age.
So, the result table will have an email attribute.
It will have an attribute NumInt that contains the count,
and it will have an average age attribute that returns the average age.
So, let us then look at the result of the query.
So, the group or user1s has three interests in it.
So user1, three interests and then 10 plus five plus
14 divided by three gives you the average SinceAge for that user.
Number two, there's one, two,
three, four, five in the group.
So, user2 has five interests and if you add the SinceAge up divided by five,
that's the average age you get.
Find user4 has a single interest and therefore of course the average age is 18.
The order they come in is because we insisted
that we sort the result on ascending number of interests.
So that's what you see here,
ascending number of interests and that's
indicated here as you have seen before with the Order clause,
Order By NumInt ascending.
In the next example,
you will see that it's actually possible to put
conditions on the groups that you return data from.