The final SQL concept I want to introduce to you is the concept of nested queries.
We are going to illustrate for you three different types of nested queries.
So, let's look at a simple example.
Let's find email and interests for RegularUser's in Atlanta.
So, let's look at the UserInterests table.
Consider first the first row,
will then contribute to the result.
Well it's user one and user one lives in Atlanta satisfying
the nested query and therefore user one and music will contribute to the result.
What about this one here? We already know user one lives in Atlanta.
So, user one reading is in here,
user one tennis is in here,
what about user two?
Well, user two does not have hometown Atlanta,
so user two does not contribute to the result.
Neither does user three who has hometown Portland or user four lives in Atlanta,
so user four and DIY contributes to the result.
You can think about it slightly differently.
You could say, in this case here you would look at the inner query
and say SELECT email FROM RegularUser WHERE HomeTown equals Atlanta.
You're going to see, that only the user one
and user four are going to count in this example.
So, when you look at the outer query,
you just need to check whether the email
for which you are considering listing email and interest,
whether that's in the result of the inner query consisting of user one and user four.
You could say there's no correlation necessarily between the two which
you are considering in the outer query and those you are looking at in the inner query.
The inner query is the same we got this off which row you look at in the outer query.
We'll see that differently in later examples,
and alternative of course for this very very simple query is that you just take
the UserInterests and RegularUser table represented by alias I and U,
and you just join them on matching emails,
select where hometown is Atlanta and then project on email and interest.