So, in this next type of nested queries,
let's look at the following example.
Find CurrentCitys with at least one RegularUser who has
a Salary that's higher than all Salaries of RegularUsers with the HomeTown, Austin.
Since the Salary column is in one table and the HomeTown is in another one,
we obviously have to join the two tables together.
What's the join attribute?
It's BirthYear. So, let's join RegularUser and YearSalary together,
call them R and Y,
where the BirthYears match.
Select from that where the HomeTown equals Austin and project from that the Salary.
So, now, you're going to end up with the following salaries.
User2 lives in Austin,
user2 is born in 69,
people born in 69 make 43,000.
So, 43,000 is one of the Salaries for users in Austin.
Another one is user12,
born in 74, people born in 74 makes $38,000.
So, now, you have two salaries; 43,000 and 38,000.
Let's now get back to the query here.
So, here, you have 38,000 and 43,000.
So, the outer query now says select the CurrentCity from RegularUsers where
the Salary that those RegularUsers make
is greater than all of those that result from the sub query.
So, in other words, the Salary is greater than 38 and 43.
Again, since CurrentCity and Salary live in different tables,
we got to join the two tables together in the outer query also.
So, let's now consider whether the CurrentCity,
Seattle, is in the result.
Seattle is the CurrentCity of user1,
born in 85, and those born in 85 make 27.
Twenty seven is not greater than 38 and 43 so Seattle is not in the result.
Is Austin in the result?
Austin has user2 in it,
born in 69, people born in 69 make 43.
Is 43 greater than 38 and 43?
The answer is no. Had it been greater than equal to,
it would have been different.
Therefore, Austin is not in the result.
About San Diego, San Diego, user3,
born in 67, salary for people born in 67 is 45.
Is 45 greater than 38 and 43?
Yes. So, is San Diego in the result?
Yes, we just saw it is.
But it certainly is not in the result because of user6.
Because user6 is born in 88,
those born in 88 make 24 and that's less than both 38 and 43.
However, it still is in there because user3 was born in 67.
Let's take a look at College Park.
College Park, there's a person born in 68,
people born in 68 earn 44,000.
Forty four is greater than 43 and 38.
Is College Park in the result?
Well, yes it was. But it's not added to the result because of this person.
User12 was born in 74,
those born in 74 make 38.
Thirty eight is not greater than 43 and 38.
Of course, in all of these cases,
when we went in and compared,
we asked whether the salary of the user we are considering to
return CurrentCity from was greater then 38 and 43.
Why did we do that?
We didn't have to compare to both 43 and 38.
All we would have to do to make sure that salary is
greater than all of them is to compare to the 43.
So, instead of writing this comparison here,
we could just have compared the salary to
the biggest one of those returned by the inner query.
In other words, we could have done it like this.
So, the inner query instead would have been select the max(salary) here,
that would have yielded the 43,
and each one of these in the outer query would be compared just to the max query, 43.