The last type of Nested Queries I want to show you is that of a correlated query.
Say we want to find the Email and BirthYear of RegularUsers who have no Interests at all.
The SQL query looks like this and I will explain it in just a
second on the example but I want to do the following with you.
In the two previous examples,
when we read the inner query,
we could think of first evaluating the inner query and then use
the result of that when considering tupples to return in the outer query.
That cannot be done in this case when queries are correlated.
Let me show you why.
So in this query we say,
select everything from UserInterest,
U where U.Email equals R.Email. What is R?
R does not exist in this particular inner query.
So where is R?
This is called a reference out of scope.
So the next layer up from this inner query is this layer.
As you see, in the scope of this layer R is defined.
So in other words from the inner query you have a reference to the outer query.
These queries are quite different to understand.
I'm going to go through a method that
allows you to write and to understand those queries.
The problem is that since the result of the inner query depends on the outer query,
you're essentially looking at a situation where for
every single possible instantiation of R of a RegularUser,
there's a completely new query as the inner query.
So think of it as a sub query being evaluated for
every single instantiation of the topper variable R ranging over a regular user.
That gives, of course,
a clue as to how to write these queries and how to think about them.
So let's simply proceed from the top here and ask the question.
For the first row in RegularUser.
So this user 1 '85 M is that can contribute to the result of the query.
So the instantiation in the RegularUser of table of
the tupple variable R is to the first row.
Are we going to return Email and BirthYear from the first row?
Well, let's take a look.
For that first row,
is it true that there does not exist anything in the result of this inner query?
So the comparison here between the outer and the inner query is exist, not exist,.
In this case, not exist.
So, in other words, for that first row,
will the result of the inner query result to the empty set.
So look at the first instantiation of U in UserInterest.
That's the user one row.
Does that email match this email?
Yes it does.
It is not true that there does not exist anything in the restart of this query.
Therefore, the first instantiation of R does not give an empty set of the inner query.
So user one does not contribute.
What about the second row here, user two.
Is it the case that there is nothing on the UserInterest table with email user two?
No. Doesn't contribute.
User three? Doesn't contribute.
Use four? Doesn't contribute.
User six, wait a second now.
Looking for users in UserInterest with Email user six,
is that an empty result? Yes, it is.
Because user six has no interest at all.
Therefore, user six contributes to the result together with BirthYear '88.
User eight, no interests contributes to the result.
User nine, no interest contributes to the result.
So that is the expression of finding the set of Emails
and BirthYears for RegularUsers that have no Interests whatsoever.