Let's first look at a very simple selection query.
Let's say, we simply want to find all the rows in regular user.
Here's one way to write then.
SELECT Email, BirthYear, Sex,
CurrentCity, HomeTown FROM RegularUser.
Notice there's no way I'm closing this query.
Notice also, that all the SQL queries they end with a semicolon.
So basically what we are saying here is give me all the attributes: email,
birth year, sex, current city and hometown from the regular user table.
And what is the result going to be?
Well of course, it's going to be all the rows in the regular user table.
There's an easier way to write that by using the wildcard star.
So, SELECT star actually is the exact same query as the one you see there.
It makes it a little bit easier to type.