Let's now try a selection that actually has a WHERE clause.
Let's say we want to find all RegularUser's with a Hometown equal Atlanta.
Queries as follows, select everything,
in other words all the columns FROM RegularUser WHERE the Hometown equals Atlanta.
So from the RegularUser table WHERE is Hometown equal to Atlanta.
So it is here for you user one,
so that row is part of the table,
it is for user four,
which will appear in the result and is for user six,
which is part of the result.
What I'm trying to do in these examples and examples to follow is I'm trying to tie
my English text very close to the names used in relations,
in attributes, in columns etc.
etc. So, when I write something like this "Find all RegularUsers with hometown Atlanta",
this is not of course correct English,
I'm doing it because at the same time I want to point to
the RegularUser table so I had a choice between doing something like
this RegularUser's or just say find all RegularUser with Hometown Atlanta,
but that wouldn't sound right in English either.
So this is what I chose.