Looking at a selection with a composite where clause.
Let's say, we want to find all regular users who either
have the same CurrenCity and HomeTown or who live in Atlanta.
The rescue out for that would be as follows: select all the columns from regular user,
where either the CurrentCity equal HomeTown or HomeTown equal Atlanta.
So, let's take a look at the regular user table.
Does the HomeTown equal Atlanta?
Yes it does. So, user one is part of the result.
Are CurrentCity and HomeTown the same?
No. Does HomeTown equal Atlanta?
No. So, user three is not part of the result. Is user 4?
Yes. Is user 6?
Yes. So, starting out with this table this is your result.