Today, we are going to talk about archival metadata,
archival metadata is just one of the types of
metadata that's so important for Information Interchange.
Let me first motivate the topic.
The hardware I have used includes Gutenberg hand-set lead types.
This is what they look like when you set them
up before you put them in the printing press.
I worked in a small newspaper printing house from fifth grade to eighth grade.
Early in college, I used punch card to submit my programs for better processing.
I have of course used record players.
I still have about 6 feet of vinyls.
VCRs, I may even still have one in my house.
In addition to those I've used 8-bit paper tape readers following the punch card error,
I've used a manual edition machine with anvil,
I used an old gear computer in Scandinavia with
an external magnetic drum and 1K of 42-bit double word memory, wow.
I've used 8-tracks, big reel tape recorders and big magnetic disk packs.
Now let's take a look at what hardware you have used.
First of all, you have all used the Atari,
you have used to Walkman,
you've used a Nintendo and you've used the Super Nintendo.
Looks like you had more fun than I did.