There are a number of standards for archival metadata and they are constantly evolving.
One that I particularly like is
the ISO 11179 Specification and Standardization of Data Elements.
Very very informative about what metadata looks like and what kind of metadata is needed.
Then, there's the OAIS reference model I just presented.
It exists in newer versions than the one I pointed you to before and it
includes the process that sits around all the archival activities.
It includes extended entity relationship diagrams
between all the different kinds of metadata that I've talked to you about.
Then, there's the OASIS Registry/Repository for XML Schemas.