The creation and evolution of a metadata registry is a very complex process.
To be successful several elements are needed.
The first element is the initial creation of the metadata schemata.
It is very important that this process is done well.
The reason is that software will be developed to access the registry
and you don't want that software to be rewritten as the registry evolves.
It is sort of an anchor that will hold you back in future evolution of that registry
so subsequent creation of new metadata schemata must be
a controlled process so you do not get two radical changes.
A process for the long term
controlled evolution maintenance as use of the metadata schemata must be created.
Finally, of course, tools must be in place to support
the development and evolution and control of the metadata registry.