To try to answer that question,
I want to talk with you about preservation metadata and the OAIS information model.
In the late 90's,
at the request of the International Organization for Standardization, IOS,
the Consultative Committee for Space Data Systems, CCSDS,
started developing an archive standard for long term storage of data in digital form.
Initial report was released in
1999 for the open archival information system reference model.
This model went through very thorough review and got feedback from a number of
additional organizations outside of the space community such as
the Library of Congress and Nesson Archives and Records Administration.
That's the model I want to briefly talk with you about today.