Three so-called information packages are important when digital data is archived.
The first one is the submission information package.
It is the information that's submitted
together with the data that's going to be archived,
at the point in time,
that the archive receives this information.
Then, an archived information package is prepared,
that's the information package that is used by
the archive during the period of time the data is in the archive.
Finally, there's a dissemination information package.
Which is the meta data package that is used,
as portions of the information in the archive is shared with others.
Each one of these information packages consists of three things;
content information, preservation description information,
packaging information and descriptive information.
I'm going to show you some additional detail,
of the archived information package.
So, looking first at the content information,
here are the details of them.