The content information is just one of
four collections of metadata that's needed in each one
of the three information packages that are
prepared during the archival of digital information.
Before I proceed with the presentation of the details of the content information,
let me share with you what my real intent is.
My intent is not really to make you understand
all the details of this and make you remember all the details of this.
My intent merely is to share with you the massive amount
of metadata that is needed for long-term archival of digital data.
Okay. So, here we go.
The first part of the content information is the content data object.
The content data object is the bit stream which is being preserved.
The representation information consists of structural metadata and semantic metadata.
The structure of metadata expresses what the data formats
and data structures are in the data that's being preserved.
The semantics expresses the meaning with English names and prose,
and so on, as to what the data that's being preserved really means.
The content data object description is a human readable data structure description.
It contains the structural types such as whether things are images,
sound, text, web documents, executables, etc.
There's a file description.
There's information like access inhibitors, encryption, watermarks,
etc, access facilitators like time markers,
lengths, and so on.
The second part of the representation information is environment descriptions.
It consists of two things;
software environment and hardware environment.
The operating system information includes things such as the operating system name,
the version of it, the location of it,
and the documentation of it.
Then, there's the rendering programs.
What kind of transformation process necessary to allow rendering of the data object?
What's the transformation engine?
Any parameters needed?
What's the input format?
The output format?
Location of the rendering program?
Documentation for it, etc, etc, etc.
Metadata about the hardware environment includes location of it, documentation of it.
It includes which computation resources are needed,
processor requirements, memory requirements,
documentation, the storage requirements, and finally,
which peripherals are required and where's the documentation for those peripherals.