The preservation description information consists of reference information,
context information, provenance information and fixity information.
The archival system identification consists of the system ID,
the value, construction method,
responsible agency and additional information.
There is a global identifier with a value,
construction method and a responsible agency for that identification.
Finally, on the reference information there is resource description,
existing metadata, and existing records.
That brings us to the context information some of which
includes relationships between this object and other objects,
information about the relationships between
this object and other manifestations of the same object,
what the type of relationship is.
The provenance information contains
the complete history of the information throughout it's lifetime.
Where did it originate?
How was it created?
What was the history before ingest to the archival system?
What was the process that was used during the ingest event?
What's the history of archival rights management?
Each one of these events throughout the lifetime,
origin, pre-ingest, ingest, archival retention,
rights management, will have a name, procedure,
date, responsible agency, and outcome, and notes.
Fixity information refers to the authentication method for the object.
Digital signature, watermark, check sum, etc,.
Both the type, procedure,
date and result are part of the fixity information.