In case three, ET is not mandatorily related to ET1 and or ET2.
ET1 and ET2 are allowed to overlap.
Let's take a look at the solution for that.
So again this is actually an option,
you collect all the attributes together,
now you may actually have troupers in this single relay's net has A and B values,
but no C or D values because that's not mandatory anymore.
For the same reasons as before,
I just do not like that.
Second solution very similar to the one we used in
case two is that we generate a relation for ET,
a relation for ET1,
and a relation for ET2.
Attribute A is inherited in ET1 and ET2 as identifying properties.
So, both of those will be foreign keys up to the A attribute in ET.
It is now possible to have instances of ET with A and B values where
the corresponding A value does not exist
in ET1 or ET2 simply because that's not mandatory.
It is likewise possible to have instances of ET that are in ET1,
for example in this case here,
or instances of ET that are in ET2 for example these two relations together.
So, this is really a fairly pretty solution.