In Case Four, there is a relationship type,
is not mandatory and disjoint.
An elegant solution to that is this one.
You generate your relations for ET, ET1 and ET2,
and of course, ET1 and ET2 will inherit A as an identifying attribute.
The reason to this is really a beautiful solution is,
that since this is not mandatory,
you can have instances of ET that have no corresponding tables in ET1 and ET2.
However, when there are tables in ET1 or in ET2 because of the disjointness,
a table will only be in one of them.
So for an instance here,
an instance with a corresponding value will either be an ET1 or an ET2.
So there's not even a replication of an A value in the other one that it's not in.