Finally, let's look at union type.
So ET is a union type.
The semantics of that is as follows: ET is a subset of the union of ET1 and ET2,
and there's the added constraint that the intersection of ET1 and ET2 is empty.
So we know we're going to get a relation for ET1,
and we know it has identifying attribute C. We know we will get one for ET2 with
identifying attribute D. We know we will have a relation for ET with property type B.
The question now is how do we model this subtype relationship here?
One way which is sort of a soft hack that works well is the following.
We insert an artificial identifier into relation ET.
That identifier will then consist either of
what corresponds to C or corresponds to D. Remember,
that every single element in there comes either from that or
from that so it will be identified by C or by
D. So the ET identifier is a foreign key on the ET-ID and ET both from ET1 and from ET2.