What I'm going to do here and in every single step of the mapping is that to the left,
I'm going to show you the extended entity relationship modern notation and to the right,
I'm going to show you fragments of the relations that
are created by each step of the mapping.
So, here the very first and very simple rule we have is,
if we have an entity type, give it the name,
"ET" then, for that entity type,
we create a relation and that relation gets the same name, "ET".
If an entity type ET has a property type,
single valued property type B,
then the relation ET will have B as an attribute.
If an entity type ET has
a property type A and that property type is an identifying property,
then in the relation ET corresponding to it,
there will be an attribute A which is an identifying or primary key attribute.
So, these steps are very simple.
Unfortunately, it gets a little bit more complicated than that.
We have an entity type ET with a composite property type C and
that composite property type C is composed from property type D and E. Then,
in the relation corresponding to ET that adds two attributes,
attribute D and attribute E. You might then ask,
what happened to property C?
Unfortunately, in the translation,
property type C gets lost.
That means that the meaning that's expressed by
the relation will not be as rich as it is here.
Vision for example, that C was name and D was first name and E was last name,
then and this mapping here you do not really see the concept of name.
You only see the concept of first name and last name.
So, one could consider the following alternative way of mapping it.
It would be nice if in relation ET,
the concept C would continue to appear with
the two components that it consists of D and E. However,
if you remember back to the way we defined a relation,
we said that a relation was defined as a subset of
tuples that were constructed from domains with atomic values.
Now, this would certainly not be a domain with atomic values.
This would actually be a domain where we would have a name and two sub-components on it.
The relational model is inherently flat and the languages we are going to look,
relational algebra, calculus and SQL only work when that's the case.
So, unfortunately, this is the solution that we have.
We have lost C.