The rules for multi-valued property types are quite special.
Let's say we have an entity type, ET,
and it has an identifying property type, A.
Then you know by a previous rule that that results in a relationship,
ET will attribute A which is then the primary key.
Your multi-valued property type, F,
is dealt with for each F as follows.
A brand new relation is created.
The name of that relation is the name of the entity type, ET-,
the name of the particular multi-valued property type we are dealing with,
in this case, F. So,
the name of the additional relation is ET-F.
The property type F results in an attribute in ET-F.
Together with that attribute,
we insert the identifying property type for ET and
then the combination of A and F become a composite key in ET-F.
The reason for all of this gymnastics basically is as follows: so, F is multi-valued.
We would not be able to just insert F as a property or as an attribute in ET.
The reason for that is that we don't have multi values in the relational model.
So, we put it in a separate relation together with the identifying property type,
A, and make the combination a key.
The reason that works is that now,
for a given instance of ET,
it will have a unique value of A.
That unique value of A can now be represented with multiple different values
of F as long as the combination of the A and F is unique.
That's the reason for the composite key.
Of course, the As for which we record F values
has to be a subset of the set of As that exist,
so the A attribute in ET F will be a foreign key on attribute A in ET.