Now, take a look at how we map one-to-one relationship types to the relational model.
We already know from our previous rule how to map ET1 with identifying property type A.
It becomes relation ET1 with primary key attribute A,
similar thing for ET2.
Now, in databases, we are going to need to be able to start, for example,
with some B values and travel and find
the corresponding A values via the relationship type R. So,
in relational database, we need to be able to do the same thing.
So there are basically two ways of doing that.
One way is that in ET1,
we insert the primary key attribute of ET2 as a pointer or a reference from ET1 to ET2.
Now, I can start out with some A values,
find the corresponding B values,
go over here, and find them here,
and then find whatever ET2 minus to add of information.
Alternatively, I could of course take the primary key of
ET1 and insert as a reference in ET2 to point back here.
Again, this will allow me to travel both ways.
So, either the first solution here or the second solution are acceptable.
There's one particular situation where we would prefer one of these solutions.
Let's take a look at that.
Let's say that ET2 has a mandatory participation in relationship type
R. What that means is that every single instance of ET2 in
the database must be related by relationship R to ET1.
That means, in other words,
there cannot be an instance of ET2 that's not in a relationship with ET1.
In that particular case,
it is not advisable to use this solution.
The reason being that,
since there might be some ET1s that are not related,
they will have null values here.
This solution is much better because every single
one of the ET2s are going to be related to ET1,
and therefore there will never be a null value here for that A.