Now, let's take a look at how we map one-to-many relationship types.
Let us consider the two different options we had before.
In one option, ET1 would be pointing to ET2 and in the other one,
ET2 would be pointing to ET1. What would that mean?
In a one-to-many relationship type,
the instances of the relationship type look as follows.
One of those related to many of those,
one of those again related to many of those.
If we were to choose this first option here,
what would that mean?
For each instance of ET1 that would obviously be
a unique value of A associated with that unique value,
there would have to potentially be multiple pointers or
references to ET2 just like you can see here.
This one needs to reference 2,
this one here would need to reference 3.
But remember, again, you cannot have multi-valued in A field,
in a relation; that was exactly the reason we had
to deal in such a strange way with multi-valued attributes.
So this solution here having multiple pointers as a value of the attribute,
just does not work.
What about the other solution,
would that still work?
Yes, that still works because as you can see,
instances on the ET2 side point to a single value on the ET1 side.
So it's okay here to insert
the ET1 side reference or to ET1 because it's unique for every single value of B.
So this solution works, that one is out.