Next comes Many to Many relationship types.
How do we deal with those?
Well, we already saw before we could not point from the ET1 side to the ET2 side
because that would require a multi-valued reference or pointer from ET1 to ET2.
So, that one is out. Let's try the other side then.
Well, from the other side ET2 you would have to have multiple pointers
pointing to the ET1 side and that's not acceptable either.
So, that one is out too.
So what do we do? Well, here's the solution,
instead of just generating one relation for ET1
and one for ET2 as we have correctly done here,
we actually need to generate a separate relation for R. So,
basically the idea is that from R we will point
to the ET1 side and the same for the ET2 side.
It is important to notice that it is the combination of
attribute A and B that constitute the key of relation R together.
Why is that important?
Well, it's important because that is
exactly what enforces a Many to Many relationship type.
It means that for a particular value of A identifying ET1,
there will be multiple values of B that are portable and
the unique combination is going to identify to plane A and vice versa,
for each unique value of B there will be an instance of ET2 that is related
to many instances in ET1 and the combination of them is unique.