Let's now consider how we map identifying
relationship types are with weak entity types ET2.
ET1 results in a relation ET1 with primary key
A. ET2 creates relation ET2 with attribute B.
How do we now discriminate between the B values?
Well, you know that instances of ET2 needs values of
the strong entity types identifier namely A in order to discriminate between them.
So, our solution is,
to insert in ET2,
add reference to ET1 that is the A attribute in
ET2 becomes a foreign key on the A attribute in ET1.
Somewhat similar to what we saw in the many-to-many relationship type.
The combination of A and B here constitute the key for ET2.
The reason is as follows.
When you look at an instance of ET1 identified by A,
then through the one-to-many relationship type here,
that will identify multiple values of ET2.
Each one of those values has a value of B.
So, it takes the A and B in combination to distinguish between the instances of ET2.