Mapping super subtype relationships is a little bit more complicated.
There are four cases I would like to consider.
In the first case,
the relationship between ET and the two subtypes is mandatory.
That means that every single instance of ET needs to be hooked up to ET1 or ET2 or both.
However, in this particular situation,
we are looking at mandatory and disjoint.
So, the constraint here is that ET1 and ET2 are disjoint.
So, the semantics of this case is the following,
every single ET instance will have an A value and a B value.
But we also know that every single instance of ET is hooked up either to
ET1 or to ET2 as the case might be it's only going to be one of them.
Furthermore, we know that when we look ET1,
it will inherit attributes A and B,
and have C as immediate attribute.
When you look at ET2, all values of that will inherit attribute A and B,
and have D as immediate attribute.
So, in case one, we actually cheat a little bit.
We only create a relation for ET1.
For ET2, we do not also create a relation for ET.
So, ET1 will inherit attributes A and B,
and have immediate attribute C that states relation here, of course,
the identifier is still A. ET2, similarly,
will inherit attribute B and have D as an immediate attribute here.
What then you might ask happens to the ET instead are not related to any of those?
Well, that can happen because it's mandatory.
So, we will in other words,
find every single ET instance with a corresponding A and B value,
either in ET1 or in ET2.