A slight variation in the interrelationship diagram and actually makes
a fairly big difference in the mapping is when the constraint is overlapping.
So, in other words,
every single instance of ET is either an instance of ET1 or of ET2 or of both.
So, the first option,
which I really do not like,
is an option where we create one single relation.
We could call that relation ET.
It has attribute A and B.
It has attributes C,
which is representing the attributes for ET1.
One of my attributes, in this case,
just D used as an example of the attribute of ET2.
Then, it has an attribute called type.
Type will say, whether this is an instance that is in ET1 or whether
it's an instance that's in ET2 or whether it's an instance that is in both ET1 and ET2.
There are several reasons I do not like this option.
One is, that when there are instances of ET that is in either.