Closed algebra is the reason we don't run around in loincloth anymore.
Let me show you an example.
Here's an expression on rational numbers.
What's the result? Come on,
you ought to be able to do that.
First, you are Georgia Tech student.
Well, at least you know what to do.
You take the five and the three,
gives you eight, multiplied by the seven.
And the result is 56.
You subtract 21, you get 35,
then you multiply by three, gives you 105.
Then you add the 10 and five for 15,
you divide 105 by 15.
Then finally you multiply the seven by the three,
to give you the final result 21.
So, the algebra is said to be closed because each time you do
an operation on these rational numbers you get a rational number back.
The same type as the operands you started out with.
That's what a closed algebra is.
A closed algebra allows you to formulate higher level models.
So, there's no less than one,
two, three, four, five, six,
seven different thoughts involved in this.
Each one built on the next one.
So, a closed algebra allows you to use
previous thoughts to form new thoughts to build high level models.
And that is indeed why we don't run around in loincloth anymore.