Finally, let's look at Set Difference.
So, in the query,
we want to find cities that are a CurrentCity for some RegularUser,
but not also a HomeTown for some RegularUser.
So, looking at the Venn diagram,
we see the following: got a set here corresponding to CurrentCity,
got a set here corresponding to HomeTown,
and in the result we are looking for all of those that
have this CurrentCity but excluding all of these,
which in essence just means we're excluding these in here.
So these out here do not even get to play in the query.
Here's how it's formulated.
Take RegularUser, project it on CurrentCity,
take RegularUser, project it on HomeTown,
take the latter away from the former.
So, in the example here,
Seattle is part of the result because it doesn't appear over here.
College Park is part of the result because it does not appear over here,
same thing with Las Vegas.
Dallas is not part of the result because it appears over here.
College Park is not added because it's already over there,
and the result is a set.
So, the result of the query is this.