Now, let's look at natural join,
the first one of our constructor operators.
So, I'm going to be combining two relations to answer the following query.
Find E-mail, Year, Sex,
and Event when the (Birth)Year of the RegularUser is
the same one as the (Event)Year of the Major60sEvents.
So, the algebra query looks like this,
take RegularUser, natural join Major60sEvents.
Take a look at the two relations,
here's the RegularUser relation,
it has E-mail, Year, and Sex.
Here's the Major60sEvents, it has Year and Event.
What natural join does in combining
these two tables is it looks at which attribute names are the same.
In this case, Year appears in both tables and no other attributes have the same name.
Therefore, the natural join operation is going to compare tuples from
the RegularUser relation with tuples from
the Major60sEvents relation and see if the year is the same.
So, let's see what the result is going to be.
So, user1 is born in 1985,
none of these Major60sEvents happened in 1985.
So, user1 is not going to contribute to the result.
Let's take a look at user2,
user2 was born in 69.
What happened in 69?
Well, we had the Moon Landing happened in 69.
So, user2, born in 69, sex, Male,
that comes from this tuple is combined with the Moon Landing tuple which appears here.
Notice that Year is only recorded one time.
User3 is born in 67.
User3, born in 67,
matches the Year that the Alabama song was recorded by The Doors.
So, those two tuples get combined.
User8, born in 68,
matches a number of events: Bloody Sunday,
the MLK assassination, and the Tet offensive.
So, all of those get combined.
So, here were some of the properties of a natural join.
First of all, it matches values of attributes with the same names and only those.
It keeps only one copy of the join attribute.
It's called an inner join because only the tuples that actually
appear in the relation and match will appear in the result.
Those that have no matches will not appear in the result.