The second constructor operator we'll look at is theta join.
Let's say we want to find email,
birth year, sex, event year,
when the birth year of the regular user comes before the event year of the major event.
When we use the theta join for that the join condition
is that birth year precedes event year.
In contrast to the natural join,
this would have been an equality,
but there is one more difference that we will see in just a second.
So here we have the regular user table again,
here we have the major events table,
and let's take a look at when the birth year precedes the event year.
So, 85 for user one does not precede any of the 60s event years.
So if you look at user2, was born in 69,
and 69 does not precede any of the 60s events we have recorded over here,
so user2 does not contribute to the result.
User3 however, was born in 67.
67 precedes a number of the events in the event table.
So, let's take a look at it.
So 67 precedes the year of the Tet offensive which was 68,
the bloody Sunday which was 68,
the MLK assassination which was 68,
and the moon landing which was 69.
So, user3 gets combined with all of those events.
About user8. User8 was born in 68.
68 comes a year before 69 and therefore
user8 gets combined with the moon landing in the lace tubule in the result.
In contrast to the natural join, in this case,
the two join attributes have different names whereas in the natural join,
they had the same name.
Also in contrast to the natural join,
both of the join attributes will appear in the result.
Birth year appears, and event year appears.
The comparison that's allowed here in the theta join is any of the usual suspects.
Less than, greater than,
equal to, different from etc.
As I mentioned, all attributes are preserved.
This is also an inner join because the things in the two tables that
do not match each other do not contribute to a tubule in the result table.