The third construct to operate off the relation as a bar is outer join.
In this case it's (left) outer Join
signified by those two small lines on the join symbol.
Let's say we want to find e-mail, year,
sex and event for RegularUsers when the birth year
of the RegularUser matches the event year of the event.
But let's in addition to that say that we want to preserve
RegularUser information even if their birth year does not match any event.
The Algebra expression will look like this,
Outer Join RegularUser with Major60sEvents.
So, let's take a look at user three first.
User three is born in '67.
'67 matches the year that The Doors recorded the Alabama Song.
So, user three here gets combined with the Alabama Song,
and the result appears here.
User eight who was born in '68
will be combined with the three events that happened in '68,
The Tet Offensive, Bloody Sunday,
and the MLK assassination.
So, that is the next,
three tables in the result.
Together, those first four are called the "inner" part of the query.
Now, let's then go take a look at user one and use 10.
As you see, their birth years do not match anything on the major '60's events table.
Therefore there's nothing to match them up with but as we said up in the query here,
we would still like to preserve the RegularUser information.
So, you see here the user one information and
the user 10 information and in both cases they have a null associated with them.
So that null, this is called The Outer part or signifies the outer part of that result.
So, in this case the (left) outer join I showed you really was
a natural (left) outer join because we compared same values.
It is a special case of the theta-join.