The fourth constructor operator in the relational algebra is Cartesian product.
A Cartesian product simply combines every single tuple into two operands.
So, every single regular user tuple will be
combined with every single user interest tuple.
For example, here, you have user four.
User four is going to be combined with every single one of these.
For example, this one,
as you see, that combination appears here.
You might wonder what the usefulness of such a combination would be.
After all, there were no comparison rules that would decide when
two tuples in the operands would be combined in the result, everything is combined.
So, what could that be useful for?