Although Cartesian Product combines troopers,
that have nothing to do with each other,
there's a very interesting portable use of it.
So, let's look at our example here.
You got the regular user table with user one,
two, three and 12.
You've got the UserInterests table here that record the interest in
this case for user one and for user two who has two and for use three.
So, those are all the currently known UserInterests.
Let's say we want to do an email blast to all regular users
to make them aware of all the interests they currently are not hooked up with.
In that case, we sort of need that complement to this table.
How could we do that?
The first thing we do is we take the regular user table and we project that on email.
That is what we are doing here.
Take the regular user projected on email.
So, the intermediate result of that query is the email column of regular user.
Second, we take the UserInterests table and project that on interest,
that gives us all a set of interests that
are currently recorded for any user in the database.
So UserInterests projected on interest,
that's another single column table.
Now, we have that single column intermediate result
and that single column intermediate result.
Now, we simply do the Cartesian Product of the two.
Which is combined user one with all interest user two,
with all interest user three,
with all interest and user 12, with all interests.
All we now need to do,
in order to end up with a result that has
every single user hooked up with all the interest they currently
do not have is now to actually just
subtract the current UserInterest from the intermediate result.
So, that's what we do here.
We subtract the UserInterests table, email and interest.
Notice that the two operands in the subtraction
are type compatible in this case here because you
have email Cartesian Product interest and you subtract from that email and interest.
So, when you look at for example, user one,
user one was hooked up with the interest music,
but was not hooked up with blogging and meditation.
Therefore, when the result,
you now see user one hooked up with both blogging and meditation.
That did not previously appear in the current interests.