Next algebra operator we'll look at is the Rename Operator Rome,
Greek letter for R. Rename is useful when we want to control whether a natural join,
a theta join or some other type of join takes place.
As you noticed when I presented the previous three for operators,
I was renaming the attributes to make the operator work like it was supposed to do.
Here is how to actually make that happen.
The formal syntax for renaming is as follows.
Row followed by the following expression.
What's in that expression is the name of the relation as it
currently is and the name of the result relation after renaming.
In the subscript here is the list of attributes that get renamed.
So we are renaming sex to gender and birth year to year.
Let's take a look at it. So we start out with
the regular user relation and we rename it to Ruser as you see there.
Then, sex is renamed to gender.
You see that here and birth year is renamed to year.
You see that here.