So we have now looked at relational algebra.
That's one of the two fundamental formalism's for relational database query languages.
The second one is relational calculus.
To distinguish between the two,
relational algebra is procedural in nature.
It's operator-based and basically what you do is you say,
"Take this relation, take that relation, join them together.
Take the result of that, do a projection.
Take the result of that, do a selection."
You're basically describing step-by-step what you're supposed to do to get to the result.
Calculus, in comparison, is declarative in nature.
Instead of saying what to do step-by-step you simply describe the result that you want.
So it may appear that it's a higher level language with more expressive power.
As it turns out,
the algebra and calculus were defined in such a manner
that with respect to data retrieval of horsepower,
they can actually be shown to be equivalent.
SQL is mostly based on tuple calculus.
So, now on to calculus.