The second formalism in which we can express
queries on relational databases is called Relational Calculus.
In this particular case we're going to look at relational Tuple calculus.
It's called Tuple calculus because queries
have variables that range or with sets of Tuples.
As you can already see now,
queries in relation to Tuple Calculus are declarative in nature as opposed to
the relational algebra which is operator based and is procedural in nature.
So the semantics of a query like this is to find a set of Tuples T
that satisfy the predicate P. Predicates are built from atoms.
So let's take a look at some of the atoms that go into predicates.
So first they are range expressions.
A range expressions says for example in this case here
that T is a member of relational or written in
an alternative format contains Tuple
T. We need to be able to reference attributes of Tuples.
We used to dot notation for that.
So this notation indicates that we are looking at
the value of attribute a of Tuple T. Third,
constants in our queries are denoted by C. Fourth,
we have several comparison operators theta, equal to,
different from, less than equal to,
greater than equal to,
less than and greater than.
Atoms are then any one of the following.
Could be a range expression,
it could be a comparison of two attributes, here Tuple R,
attribute A compared by the theta here to attribute B
of Tuple S and again the theta could be any one of these comparison operators.
Alternatively we could compare attribute A of tuple R to the constant C,
and again all of these could be the comparison operator.
Building up then what a predicate is,
an atom is a predicate.
So this means that the range expression,
the attribute comparison expression and comparing an attribute to a constant.
Those are all predicates.
Now, if you have predicates P one and P two then you can put parentheses
around them which basically means you can use
nesting in the way you write your expressions.
You can use negation,
you can use or,
you can use and,
and you can use implies.
Finally, if P of T is a predicate and T is a free variable in P and I is a relation,
then there exists a T in R that satisfies P as a predicate.
Likewise for all T and R for which P is true is also a predicate.
If T is free in the predicate P,
then using the extended quantifier or the universal quantifier binds T.