Let's take a look at the four groups of algebra operators.
First, we have four operators that are all set operators.
As you can see here, we got set union between two sets, R n S,
set intersection, set difference, and Cartesian product.
As you can already guess now from looking just at these,
it is not all the operators that are fundamental operators,
some of them are derived or composed from others.
Second, we have two special operators.
One is a projection operator that you can think of as eliminating columns from a result,
the second one is a selection operator which you can think of as eliminating rows.
The third group is a group of operators that in general are called joins.
These are constructor operations.
We have an operator called natural join,
we have outer joins,
there are three of those,
a left and right and a full and then we have theta-joins.
Find the two additional operators that are quite special,
one is the divideby operator.
Essentially, the divideby operator allows you to do
something similar to universal quantification in relational calculus.
The rename operator, Greek letter r or row.
is essentially an operator that allows you to manipulate the names of
attributes of relations in such a way that you can get your join operators,
and your set operators to work in the way you intend them to work.