Now, let's take a look at the first very,
very simple operation expressed in tuple calculus,
namely that of a selection.
As you will see in the following,
I'm using your understanding of relational algebra operators and essentially going
through some of those in order to show you how they are expressed in tuple calculus.
In that first example,
let's try to find all regular users.
The way that's written in tuple calculus is find the set r,
where r is a member of the relation regular user.
In this example here,
what is it we are attempting to do?
We are simply attempting to find every single tuple in the relation regular user.
So therefore, the first tuple here is part of the result,
second tuple is part of the result, et cetera.
The result from this operation is identical to the relation we started with.