Let's make it a little bit more complicated.
Let's take a look at a selection that has a composite expression.
So, here's what we want to do.
Want to find all regular users who have
the same CurrentCity and HomeTown or who have the HomeTown, Atlanta.
Query is expressed as follows: find a set of tuples r,
where r is a member of RegularUser and the following is true:
either CurrentCity most equal HomeTown or the HomeTown must be Atlanta.
This reflects directly what is asked for here namely that the tuple must
satisfy CurrentCity is equal to HomeTown or HomeTown equals Atlanta.
Looking at the example here,
see which tuples become part of the result of the query here.
So, here, is it the case that CurrentCity and hometown is the same? No, it's not.
Well, is it then the case that the HomeTown equals Atlanta?
Yes, it is.
In other words, this one evaluate to true since this is a disjunction,
this whole thing evaluates to true,
and r is a tuple in RegularUser.
So, therefore, the first tuple we looked at satisfies the query,
and so there you go.
What about the second one?
Is HomeTown equal to CurrentCity? Yes, it is.
So, user2 is part of the result of the query.
Is San Diego equal to Portland?
No, it's not. Is hometown equal to Atlanta? No, it's not.
So, as you see, user3 is not part of the result.
User4, Hometown is Atlanta,
user4 in the result.
Finally, user10, HomeTown equals CurrentCity,
is part of the result.