Next, let's look at projection in tuple calculus.
Let's say we want to find Email, BirthYear,
and Sex for RegularUser's with HomeTown Atlanta.
So, we write it as follows.
We want Email, BirthYear,
and Sex directly reflecting what is asked for in the projection,
that is of tuples that are in RegularUser,
where the corresponding HomeTown equals Atlanta.
Are we going to include in this result user1,
1985, male? Yes, we are.
It's a tuple in RegularUser and HomeTown equals Atlanta.
So, user1, 85, and male is part of the result.
What about user4?
Yes, HomeTown is Atlanta.
What about user6?
Yes. What about user10?
No. User12? No. So, the result consists of parts of the first three tuples namely,
the three attributes we are projecting on Email, BirthYear,
and Sex from those first three tuples,
user1, user4, and user6.