Let us now look at Union.
Let us find all cities that are either a CurrentCity or HomeTown for some RegularUser.
So, the cities we're interested in are the following cities.
If there exists a tuple r in RegularUser with a CurrentCity,
then that's part of the result.
Alternatively, if there exists a tuple in RegularUser with a HomeTown,
then that's one of the cities.
Let's first look at the current cities.
So, San Francisco is a current city,
so it's clearly part of the result.
Las Vegas is part of the result.
Dallas is part of the result.
College Park, part of the result.
What about Atlanta? Yes, part of the result.
What about Atlanta?
Well, Atlanta is already there and the result is a set, of course.
What about Austin?
Yeah. Austin is there and part of the result.