Now to intersection, so we're going to use
the same example but this time instead we're going to find
the cities that are a CurrentCity for some user and a HomeTown for some user.
Not necessarily the same user of course.
So for a City S to qualify,
there must exist a table in RegularUser that has the CurrentCity as that City.
It must also be the case that there's
a table t in RegularUser that has that City as the HomeTown.
So what about San Francisco?
Is that going to qualify?
Well, San Francisco is certainly a CurrentCity for user four.
Is San Francisco also a HomeTown for some user? Yes, it is.
It is for user six.
So San Francisco is part of the result.
What about San Diego?
That's a CurrentCity.
Well, it's not part of the result because it's not a HomeTown for anyone.
How about Las Vegas then? Same thing.
It's not a HomeTown for anyone.
How about Dallas?
Yes, Dallas is part of the result because Dallas is also a HomeTown for someone.
In this case actually the same one.
So the result is San Francisco and Dallas.