Now, let's look at set difference.
We're using the same example with slight modifications.
Find all cities that are current city for some regular user but exclude
those that are a hometown for some regular users.
Of course, not necessarily the same regular user.
So, we are looking for cities that are found the following way.
There must exist a tubule r in regular user that has that city as a current city.
But it must also be true that there does not
exist a tubule t in regular user where that city appears as hometown.
So, let's see here.
What about Seattle?
Well, Seattle is part of the result because it appears here as
a current city and no one has Seattle as hometown.
College Park, same thing,
is not a hometown for anyone.
Las Vegas is not a hometown for anyone, so it's in the result.
Dallas however is a hometown for someone so it's not in the result.
College Park, we already have that and the result is as said.
So the result of the quiz,
Seattle, College Park and Las Vegas.