Next comes Natural Join.
Let's say we want to combine attributes from two different relations.
So, let's say we want to find e-mail,
year, sex, and event.
When the birth year of the regular user is the same as
the event year of the major 60s events from which these four attributes are poured.
So in this case, let's actually take a look at
the example instead of looking at the queer expression first.
So, what do we want to do here?
We want to take the regular user table.
We want to take the major 60s event table.
Both of those have an attribute year.
So, the Natural Join will combine these two tables,
we'll just keep a single copy of the column year.
When we turn the e-ma-il,
the year, the sex, and the event.
Now, when is that going to take place?
It's going to take place where the year after
the regular user matches the year of the major 60s event.
So, let's take a look here at the queer expression.
So, we are interested in a result that contains: e-mail, year,
sex, and event, as you can see here,
e-mail, year, sex and event.
What must be true for us to generate a tuple in that result?
Number one, there must exist a tuple r in regular user.
So, down here in this regular use ration,
and there must exist a tuple s in the major 60s event.
So in other words, our ranges or regular user,
and s ranges all major events.
The join condition for the natural join is that,
the year of r is the same as the year of s,
so these two must match.
But in addition to that,
the email address comes from the email r. The year,
we picked that from the year of r. The sex,
we picked that from the sex of r. The event,
we picked from the event of s. Let's take
a look at the first tuple in the result user two.
So, user two has birth year 69.
Sixty-nine matches, let's see, The moon landing.
So, those two tuples get combined in the first tuple in the result.
Let's take a look at user three born in 67.
Sixty-seven matches this event.
The Doors recording of the Alabama Song.
So, that becomes part of the tuple.
User eight, 68 matches, several tuples.
It matches the Tet Offensive year,
it matches the Bloody Sunday year,
and it matches the MLK assassination year.
So, user eight gets combined with all those three events.