Now let's look at Cartesian product.
As you recall Cartesian Product is a very simple way to combine two relations.
So, let's say we want to combine every single tuple of the RegularUser relation,
with every single tuple of the UserInterests relation.
That query is very easy to write.
It simply consists of Tuples r followed by s,
where r is a tuple in RegularUser,
and s is a tuple in UserInterests.
So, looking at that again for example user
one gets combined with this user one tuple here.
So, you see here user one '85 is a male,
gets combined with user one, music and 10.
Take a look at this tuple here,
where does that come from?
Well, it's user four '88 and male.
So, that's that tuple here gets combined with everything of these tuples here,
including the user three, music and 11.