Let's say, we want to run an email blast,
inviting all users to participate in
interest groups for interest they currently don't have.
Let's see how we can formulate that in tuple calculus.
I actually think it's easier to first explain that on
the example here and then look at the expression afterwards.
So, what I want to do is I want to combine all emails in RegularUser.
I want to combine that with all interests in UserInterests.
So, my results are going to have an Email attribute and an Interest attribute.
So, that's why the result is structured like this.
So, let's see which combinations user1 now gets involved in,
so user1 let's combine that with the first interest that's Music,
so is user1 and Music part of the result?
It appears not. Why is that?
Because user1 is already hooked up to Music in the UserInterests.
How about user1 hooked up with Blogging.
Is that part of the result? Yes, it is.
As you see up there,
it's in the Result and user1 hooked up with
Blogging does not exist down in the current UserInterests.
What about user1 hooked up with Meditation?
Yes, that's part of the result.
It doesn't appear here.
What about user1 hooked up with Music?
Well, we already talked about that.
That appeared up here.
So, that doesn't add an extra tuple,
so user1 gets hooked up with two additional interests namely, Blogging and Meditation.
So, user2 gets hooked up with Music,
not with Blogging because it's already here.
Not with Meditation because already here and yes with Music,
but that's what we started out with.
So, User2 is combined with Music.
Does user3 get hooked up with Music?
No, because user3 is already hooked up with Music.
However, user3 does get hooked up with Blogging and Meditation.
So, as you see here, user3 is combined with Blogging and Meditation.
How about user12? Well, user12 doesn't have any current interest at all.
So, user12 gets hooked up with all the interests and they are Music,
they are Blogging and they are Meditation and they are Music,
but we already did that once and the result is a set.
So, now look at the query expression.
So, we are looking for Emails, combined with Interests,
where r is a tuple in RegularUser and s is a tuple in
UserInterests and it is not the case that there exist a tuple t,
which is combined from the tuple r and the tuple s.