Finally, let's look at the Divideby operator.
Let's say we want to find emails of all users with at least all the interests of user1.
I think it's easiest to take a look at the example here first.
So, user1: are we going to return as part of the result the email address of user1?
Yes, we are, because user1 certainly does have at least all the interests of user1,
namely music, reading, and tennis.
So, user1 is part of the result.
Is user2 part of the result?
Well, we don't even have to think about that because user2 only has two interests.
So, user2 cannot both be interest in music, reading, and tennis.
How about user3?
Well, user3 is a potential candidate.
There's one, two, three, four user3 tuples,
and so all we got a check now is that user3 has the interest music,
reading, and tennis, and it is right here,
music, reading, and tennis.
So, user3 is part of the result.
How about user4?
Well, user4 does have three interests but only music and reading match,
DIY does not so user4 is not in the result.
Let's try to see how we write the calculus expression to do this.
So, the first thing we see is we are interested in tuples R with attribute email.
So, as you see here,
that is the structure of the result.
In order for us to consider a particular tuple R to be part of the result,
of course, R has to be a tuple in user interests,
so in this table here.
So, let us consider in turn all of these tuples in user interests.
For example, this user3 tuple.
For user3 to be in the result it must be the case that for all s' in user interests,
either the email is not user1,
or if it is user1,
then the interests that are here must match
up with the interests of the tuple we are asking for in this case.
Music, reading, and tennis matches music, reading,
and tennis, and that's why user3 is part of the result.
So, what you see in this inside expression here is that for all s' in
user interest we don't care about the interests that are not hooked up to user1.
So, all of these are those that are hooked up to user1,
and what this basically says is there must exist a tuple somewhere in
the relation that matches the interests of the user1 tuples.