Second, let's take a look at
an example of the selection operator with a simple expression.
So, let's say we want to find all RegularUsers with HomeTown Atlanta.
The relational algebraic expression is this,
select where the expression condition is
HomeTown equals the value Atlanta from RegularUser.
In general, when we form simple expressions,
we can do it in one of the following two ways.
We can take an attribute name,
and compare to a constant.
The comparison operators are the usual suspects: equal to,
less than, less than equal to, et cetera.
Or alternatively, we can say attribute
one compares to attribute two in the following way,
either equal to less than,
less than equal to et cetera.
So, let's take a look at the result.
The first rule here satisfies the requirement that HomeTown equals Atlanta.
So, that appears in the result.
Second one doesn't.
Third one does.
So, that appears in the result.
Fourth tuple does.
The fifth tuple does not.
So therefore, the three tuples that satisfy
HomeTown equals Atlanta is what comes back in the result.
Notice that all the columns of
the RegularUser table are also present in the result of the selection query.