The next operator is projection.
The Syntax is as follows,
use the Greek letter pi, and it says,
project from relation R. The following attributes A1, A2,
up through An, where A1,
A2 up through An is a subset of the set of attributes in relation R. So, let's say,
we want to find email,
birth year and sex for all regular users in Atlanta.
So, one way to express their career is the following.
We take a look at the regular user table,
we find all of those tuples that have
a hometown equal to Atlanta thus satisfying this requirement.
Then after that, we project on the attributes we want;
email, birth year and sex as expressed up here.
So, which of these regular users live in Atlanta?
Well, user number one lives in Atlanta,
and what are the email birth year and sex for user1?
It's here; email, birth year and sex.
User4 happens to live in Atlanta too.
So, for user4, we also put in the result email,
and birth year and sex.
User number six lives in Atlanta.
So, we get user6 email,
birth year and sex.
User10 and user12 do not live in Atlanta.
So, they do not add anything to the result of the query.
One thing which is very interesting to notice here is not just what projection is.
So, clearly as you can see here with email,
and birth year and sex,
that is a projection from the state because it leaves out current city and hometown.
That's what projections do.
What is very, very interesting here with
this query refers back to what I talked about earlier,
that relational algebra is a closed query language.
Because what actually happens here is that this query
here is done in two steps, when we formulated.
First, we take regular user and do a selection from it with a selection condition.
Then from the result of that,
which we know is a relation,
we then do the projection on that.
So, does a composite, query,
using two operators and this can only be done when your algebra is closed.