I want to stress the fact that relation are sets.
So let's say we want to write a query,
find the sex for RegularUsers in Atlanta.
The way we could write that is as follows,
select where HomeTown equals Atlanta from RegularUser and then project that on sex.
Let's take a look at the result.
So we have here three tables of users from Atlanta.
When you look at the sex there's one female,
one male, and one female.
So what is the result of that query?
Well, the result is this one.
Notice that male appears once and female appears once in spite of
the fact that two of the tables in RegularUser have sex female.
So in other words, relations are sets.
Again, relation rlgebra is a close clear language.
You start with a relation,
you end with a relation,
relation is a set.
Therefore, you only have the two rows male and female.