Let's take a look at the Set-based Operator Union.
So, here's an example.
Find all cities that are a current city or a hometown for some regular user.
Because of the "or",
we clearly have a union involved here.
So, drawing a Venn diagram,
it will look as follows.
So, think about this as the current city and this as hometown,
and because it says "or",
we are looking for all the tools that satisfy either one or both of those conditions.
Now, let's see how that's written in Algebra.
It's going to take regular user,
project on current city,
going to take regular user,
project on hometown and then,
we're going to do with the union of them.
One side common, that's important.
In union, in set intersection,
in set difference, the two operands of the operator must be type compatible.
Type compatibility is a very simple definition in relation to databases.
Basically, what it says is that the number of
attributes of the two operands must be the same.
Here, we see there's one attribute here,
there's one attribute here,
and the second condition is that the types must be compatible,
and if you look back a bit,
you'll see in our examples,
we have defined current city and hometown as 50.
So, they are compatible.
So, back to look at the Union example.
So, the query could be evaluated as follows:
current city is computed from regular user that San Francisco,
Las Vegas, Dallas, and College Park in the result.
Similarly, if we project on hometown from regular user,
we get Atlanta, Dallas, and Austin.
Remember, Atlanta is not repeated because the result is a set.
So, those two results now union together gives you this result set here.
So, San Francisco is in there.
Las Vegas is, Dallas is,
and College Park is and then Atlanta but only once.
Dallas is not repeated again because we already have that,
and finally comes Austin.