Second set based operator intersection.
Here's an example in English.
Find all cities that are a current city for someone and a hometown for someone.
So, showing that at a Venn diagram,
you're looking at the following,
say these are the current cities,
these are the hometowns,
and since it says both conditions must be satisfied,
we're looking for the tuples that satisfy the condition in this intersection.
The query is formulated as follows.
Take regular user project on current city,
take regular user project on hometown and do the intersection.
So, take a look at the result.
So, the projection on current city gives you San Francisco,
San Diego, Las Vegas and Dallas.
The projection on hometown gives you Atlanta,
San Francisco, Atlanta and Dallas.
Except of course, Atlanta is not repeated.
Doing the intersection of those will yield the following result.
San Francisco is part of the result because it appears both places,
San Diego is not because it doesn't appear in this,
Las Vegas is not because it doesn't appear here,
Dallas appears over here,
so that's part of the result.
So, the result is this set.