So why use models at all?
Let me give you a couple
of observations.
First, models can be useful
when we want to examine or
manage part of the real world.
Second, the costs of using a model
are often considerably lower
than the costs of using or
experimenting with reality itself.
Let me give you som examples
of models of reality.
We're going to be using a map to
talk about several important aspects
of models of reality.
There are many other examples, however.
How about a model of US economy?
Such a model would presumably allow
us to plug in ideas of new laws,
etc., and find out how they
would affect the economy.
One fundamental problem
here would have caused B,
can we agree on how to build that model.
A second example is that of
a tsunami warning system,
a system that would allow us to
save human lives, livestock, etc.
Another example is that
of traffic simulation.
Traffic simulation can be used when we
want to make decisions about where to
build roads.