So back to the example of
a map as a model of reality.
Here is a map of the world.
But wait, we are always used to north
being up and that's not the case here.
All right,
let's see if we can repair that.
So here it is.
North is now up.
You got South America, you got Africa,
you got Denmark right there.
But wait, there's another problem here.
This one looks like it's
squeezed left to right.
So here's a second
convention we are used to
when using a map as a model of reality.
And that is that it's true to scale.
One more problem,
what is it with all the blue for
landmasses here that's
somewhat confusing.
We normally use blue for ocean instead.
Using blue for landmasses would be the
same as if a math teacher used xs and
ys for function names.
And f and gs for variables that
would certainly mess with our minds.
So here's a map where
everything appears to be right.
North is up appears to be true to scale.
Although of course, we know that with
this type of projection of a map there
are always some issues close to
the north pole and the south pole.
And finally,
we got the color we normally use for
land masses namely green.