Now let's look at a more
detailed example of a map,
namely a map of the city of Atlanta,
in the Peach State of Georgia.
What do we see on this map?
Well, we see a lot of interstates here,
285 is part of the interstate system.
You see 85 coming down from northeast.
You see 75 coming down from northwest.
You see I-20 going east to west.
There are other smaller roads like,
take a look at this yellow one here.
There's all the major roads, like this
green one here is Georgia 400 but
it's a different color
from the interstates.
There's some neighborhoods
pointed out like east point here,
and as you can see there's an alphabet
that's used to your language,
that's used here to illustrate
to you what reality looks like.
And in that language,
different kinds of roads have different
colors to let you know what they are.
You have letters available
to spell names of places.
You've got symbols available
to illustrate there might be
a forest there.
It's important to understand that
there might be errors in the model.
So for example, if I were to draw
the following line here, for
example from here to here,
and pretend that's a road,
that road probably
doesn't exist in reality.
So that's an error.
There might be things on
a map like contour lines for
example, county lines that
are useful when you use the map.
But really,
they don't represent something,
which is physically present in reality.
On this map here I haven't even
mentioned the fact that North is up and
it's true to scale.
And those were things that users must
have in common in order to be able to
communicate through this map.
Now let me illustrate to you why using
a map might be a better idea than
experimenting with
a reality model itself.
So let's say I'm going to
launch on The Varsity,
start out here Georgia Tech and
I can see I gotta cross the interstate,
and go south about a half a mile to
get to The Varsity on the right.
I actually wouldn't necessarily need a
map, the only thing I would need to get
to The Varsity is the following, I would
need to know that 285 goes all the way
around the city, and
The Varsity is located inside the city.
So I could start from Georgia Tech
with a big stack of paper and
a couple of pencils and just keep
an eye on every single road I try,
if I get to 285 turn around,
do something else.
Try to minimize the number of
times I go on the same road.
There's a finite number of miles of
roads inside of the perimeter so
eventually I will get to The Varsity.
It may not be today,
but I will get there.
So you don't always need a map.
[SOUND]