Based on the example of a map,
here's my message to model makers.
A model is a means of communication.
The users of a model must have certain
knowledge in common in order to be able
to communicate through that model.
So our cover of exams of that
where the maps of the world,
one was that north is up and
other one is true to scale.
Third one is that the colors
have to be right for
us to understand what it is
that's depicted in the model.
Remember that a model only emphasizes
certain selected aspects of reality.
Namely those that are useful for
the purpose at hand.
A model is described in some language on
the map, we saw a language of symbols,
letters, etc.,
that reflected aspects of reality.
We all need to agree on and
understand what that language is,
in order to be able to
communicate through that model.
Also there can be errors on the map.
There may be things on the map
that are simply incorrect,
like a road being placed
in the wrong location.
Finally, to enhance
the model there may be
features in it that do
not exist in reality.
So examples of that would be contour
lines on a mountain, the date line, etc.