Database Management Systems are good at
supporting data intensive applications.
Think about the following distinction.
Some applications are data intensive,
some are processed intensive.
Database Management Systems are good
at data intensive applications.
Data-intensive applications
are those where a lot of data
may flow between memory and
secondary storage and
where a lot of data may be communicated
between the user and the database.
Databases provide
persistent storage of data.
That means that even if your
application is shut down
your database is still
going to be there tomorrow.
Databases provide centralized control of
data which is important, because it's
possible to enforce policies across
a database, even when it's distributed.
Databases allow you to
control redundancy.
You might think that's important,
because then we won't
waste space on having data represented
in many different locations.
But that's actually not the point.
The point is that by
controlling redundancy,
we get some other advantages.
The most important one of these
advantages is that we can control
consistency and integrity.
We'll define these concepts
in more detail later, but
consistency is the question of whether
you can derive contradictions from
within the database itself.
And that is not possible
unless you have redundancy.
Database provide multi-user support, and
I'm not just thinking about five people
sitting in a room sharing one database.
I'm thinking about systems
that would allow tens or
hundreds of thousands of users to
use the database at the same time.
Think flight reservation systems, point
of sale transaction processing, etc.
Databases allow you to share data.
Sharing data is the key behind
supporting communications.
So when you operate from many
different places on the same data, and
you share data, you are communicating.
Databases contain their own
documentation of the structures of
the data and cannot run without
that which is a great advantage.
Data independence is the ability
to change the implementation of
database to be more efficient without
affecting the user interface.
Next, databases provide
control of access and
security of the data
that's stored in them.
And finally,
databases provide you with backup and
recovery utility should the power go or
something else happen.