In spite of the great
functionality supported by
database management systems,
there are some aspects you want to
consider before you decide to use
a database management system.
First, the initial investment
in hardware, software and
training are very high.
Some database management systems
are as big as operating systems.
The hardware that's needed to run large
software systems like that is expensive.
The amount of time that you put into
learning how to learn databases well
is considerable.
It might also be the case that
the generality that database management
software provides you
with is not needed.
Let me give you some examples.
There's substantial overhead for
security, concurrency control, and
recovery in a database system.
Maybe you don't need
that level of security.
Maybe you don't need a large
set of concurrent users.
Maybe recovery is not that important.
Maybe you don't need data
independence because your data and
your applications are simple and stable.
Maybe you have an application with
serious real time requirements.
If the database management system
can't run fast enough to meet those,
then it's useless.
Again maybe multiuser
access is not needed, so
concurrency control is not needed