Let us first talk about data modeling.
A model represents a perception
of structures of reality.
The data modeling process
has two steps to it.
First, we need to fix a perception
of structures of reality.
And second,
we need to represent that perception.
Database people use two
different languages for this.
One language is the extended
entity relationship model.
Which is good for fixing a perception
of structures of reality.
And second,
the relational model is good for
representing this perception
inside a database.
In the data modeling process we select
aspects of reality that are important
to us while ignoring others and we use
abstraction to organize these aspects.