In process modeling we aim at fixing and
representing a perception
of processes of reality.
As opposed to the structures processes
are not represented inside the database,
rather they are reflected in
a way we use the database
through the database management system.
There are two ways in which we can
use the database through the database
management system.
One is to embed data manipulation
language code inside a program,
the other one is to use the data
manipulation language directly
to issue ad-hoc queries on the database.
Let's take a look at what that means.
If we have program that builds,
for example, a user interface,
if you have a program that builds
an interface for an application,
then inside of that program it is
possible to have data manipulation link
with statements that accesses a data
base, either to up take the data, or
to retrieve the data and to display
it back through the interface.
Alternatively, it is plausible to use
the data manipulation language directly
to do ad hoc queries on the database,
or ad hoc updates and
maintenance of the database.
The data manipulation language
we are going to use in
this course is going to be SQL.
You're going to spend major amounts
of time in the course learning
how to build programs like this and
how to embed in them SQL statements to
manipulate and maintain the database.