In order to do data modeling, we need to
talk about a tool called a data model.
Data models contain formulations to
allow us to express data structures,
constraints, and operations.
But there are several
additional important aspects
I want to talk about before we,
later on in the course,
get into details with the two major
data models we're going to talk about,
namely, the extended entity relationship
model and the relational model.
And other important aspect I
want to briefly talk about,
is database architecture.
So, it turns out that a database and
mode of structure of reality
act has several layers to it.
We want to look at
what are those layers.
We also want to take a look at what
the architecture of a database
management system, to allow us to
create such a database, would be.
Specifically, we will look at
the ANSI/SPARC 3-Level database
architecture, and the corresponding
database management system architecture.
Finally, I want to mention metadata.
What it is and
why it is so important to make
everything else happen in a database.
And now on to data structures.