A data model is not the same
as a model of data.
We define the database to be
a model of structures of reality.
A data model is the tool or the formulas
that we use to create such a model.
We should always be talking about
the following three elements,
when talking about a data model.
Data structures,
integrity constraints and operations.
Let me mention three
examples of data models.
The first one is the entity
relationship model.
We will use this model to fix
a perception of reality in this course.
Second is the relational
model which we will use to
implement that model in
a database management system.
Third let me mention
the Hierachical Model.
The Hierarchical Model was the one
implemented in the first data base
system the IBMIMS data
base system back in 1967.
Interestingly the Hierarchical Model
is also
the fundamental model on
the XML data bases today.