To give you an example of a data model,
let me use the relation model, and
let me illustrate to you what data
structures and constraints and
operations look like in that model.
In the relational model,
data is represented in tables.
Tables have names,
in this case, RegularUser.
Each column has a name,
Email BirthDate, Hometown,
Salary, each one of
the columns has a data type.
In this case,
emails are represented by varchar(50),
variable length character
strings maximum length 50.
BirthDate is represented over datetime.
Hometown, again over varchar 50.
Salary is represented over
the data type integer.
A table is set to have columns.
In this case there are four columns.
The number of columns is also
called the degree of the table.
A relation also has a number of rows,
in this case, one,
two, three, four, five, six,
seven rows in the table.
The table name, column names and
data types together constitute
the schema of this table.
The schema represents aspects of
the data that are stable over time.
In other words,
the schema is not expected to change.
The state of the database
represented by the rows in
the table reflect aspects that
are dynamic and change overtime.
So the idea is that whereas
the schema in general
represents the structure of data,
the rows will represent
what is the current state of reality
that's modeled by this table.