Constraints represent rules that cannot
be expressed by the data
structures we just looked at.
Let me give you some examples.
First, we might want emails to be unique
as they are in this example here.
That would allow us to think about
emails as representing unique
regular users.
So for each user out in the real
world there's a corresponding row
in this table here.
For example this one user3,
born in 1967, hometown Portland,
salary 12,000,
represents a unique user in reality.
It wouldn't make sense to allow
emails to be null in this case
because that really doesn't
represent anything.
We might also have
a constraint that says that
birth date must be after
the first day of 1900.
Finally, we might have a constraint
that says that hometown must be a city
in the United States.
Notice that none of these constraints
are expressed by the table structure or
the data types that the column
values are pulled from.
That's why I'm saying that constraints
express rules that are not
expressed by the data structures alone.