Third aspect of a data model, namely
operations, let's look at some examples.
First let me give you an example
of database maintenance.
Here's a statement that would insert
an additional row in RegularUser.
That row would contain information
about user11, born in '92,
with a home town Atlanta,
and salary of $12,500.
Here's an example of a retrieval of
data from the regular user table.
It has the well known SQL
structures select, from, where.
So in this case, it's the regular
user table we select from.
We select two columns,
namely Email and BirthDate.
This one and this one, so
we don't select these two.
And the condition for
selecting the email and birth date
is that the hometown is Atlanta and
the salary is greater than $12,000.
So will user1, born in '85, be selected?
No, because the salary is
not greater than $12,000.
Will user4, '88,
with hometown Atlanta, be selected?
Yes, because the salary
is greater than $12,000.
Will user6, born in '88, be selected?
Yes, the hometown is Atlanta, and
the salary is greater than $12,000.