Integrity and consistency are two highly
desirable properties of databases.
To give you a really great example of
integrity I have a confession to make.
This is how you know me now.
I'm Leo Mark.
My confession is I am
really working undercover.
Leo Mark Christenson,
that is who I really am.
Why?
Born in Denmark lot of people
with last name Christenson,
first day of first grade, 21 students.
There were three with
last name Christenson,
and two with first name Leo.
>From that day on I became Leo Mark.
Integrity has to do with whether
the database reflects reality well.
Consistency has to do
with whether the database
is without any internal conflicts in it.
Let's take a look at an example here.
So we have our regular user table.
The regular user table has email,
birthday, name, and
it has current city in it.
Then we have a user table.
And in the user table,
we have emails and we have address.
So let us first talk about consistency.
Take a look at User 1.
The current city of User 1
is recorded as Atlanta, but
the address of User 1 is 123 Kent Rd,
in Roswell.
There seems to be inconsistency
between these two.
Let's take a look at another one.
So User 4, current city is Atlanta.
But address is 789 1st St, Roswell.
Again, there appears
to be inconsistency.
User 5, that information may be okay.
User 6, that information may be okay.
However, since User 1 and
User 4 seem to have inconsistency,
and in general we don't know
when that inconsistency appears,
this database cannot be used to answer
the question of where does a user live.
The problem here of course is
that there's some redundancy
between where a current city is.
And what an address is.
Now, let's turn our attention
to an example of integrity.
So you all now know that my full
name is Leo Mark Christensen.
User 4 here actually
happens to be my daughter.
Louise Mark Christensen, funny name.
She's born in Denmark.
In Denmark children inherit
both the last name and
the middle name of the father.
So my daughter's cross to bare
in life is that she has a boys
name for a middle name.
So on the morning of her 18th birthday,
the extended family is
gathered in the kitchen for
breakfast and the phone rings.
A man's voice on the other ends asks,
is Louis Mark present?
So I hand the phone to my daughter.
She answers several questions,
first yes, no, and
then certainly not,
then she hangs up the phone.
Who do you think called?
Well, the military called, and the first
question was, are you Louis Mark?
She answers yes.
Second question was,
have you signed up for services?
The answer, of course, is no.
And the final question was,
are you not a male?
So the problem in this database here is
that an inference was made that someone
with the name Louise or Louis or
whatever, Mark certainly must be a male.
And therefore this person should
have signed up for services.
Bad integrity.