Everything is a thing, and
some things are just that, things,
let me give you some examples.
So there's the pen I'm using here,
that's a thing it's not a name for
anything.
There's the tablet I'm doing
the reporting on here, that's a thing,
not a name for anything.
There's the camera that's being
used to record the hand and
the writing, that's a thing,
not a name for anything.
But then, there are some things that
also are names of things, when I say
names, I mean names in a very general
sense, let me give you some examples.
The text string Leo is a thing,
but it is also my first name,
the text string GTo1 is a text string,
which is the name on my license tag.
And the text string 49 is a thing
which is the name of my age.
Let's say we have a set of
regular users in reality and
we would like to record email and
name and address for them.
So we create a table in the database
with the columns email,
name, and address.
Now let's take a look at one of
the rows in that table, the user one,
Lisa Smith, lives in Roswell.
Now if you look at the database a couple
of days later, it may say user one,
Lisa Jones, live in Roswell,
what happened?
Is that the same User, yes it
probably is, Lisa probably just got
married to Mr. Jones and she changed her
last name, but it's still the same Lisa.
Couple of days later you take a look
again it says user one, Lisa Jones,
but now the address is
Atlanta instead of Roswell.
Is it still the same Lisa?
It probably is, she probably decided to
move to Atlanta with her new husband,
Mr. Jones.
Few days later, you look in
the database, and it says user two,
Lisa Jones Atalanta.
Now is that the same Lisa or is that
a different Lisa who lives in Atlanta?
That's a difficult question to answer,
this type of representation is
called Name-Base representation.
In a Name-Base representation,
you are what is known about you,
no more, no less.
Now let's consider an alternative
way of doing this, so
we have regular users, we would like
to record email, name, and address.
However, this time, instead of just
having the three columns, email, name,
and address, in the regular user table,
we add an extra column, user, for
system generated unique identifiers.
These are also called surrogates,
they represent,
inside the system, they represent
the users out in the real world.
So for each instance of user out in
the real world, you have a surrogate or
substance inside the database to
represent that user in the real world,
now, let's reconsider then Lisa.
You have an identifier for
Lisa, a surrogate for
Lisa, that surrogate never changes then,
you have her email user one,
Lisa Smith or Lisa Jones,
Roswell or Atlanta.
In every single case you can decide
whether the user is the same by
determining whether the internal system
generated surrogate is the same or not.
You can ask, is this the same user?
This even allows email to be changed and
you to be able to recognize whether or
not it is the same user.
So the problem with this representation
here in the name-base representation
is that a thing is what
we know about it and
we have used here something to
identify things out in reality.
But email can change,
Social Security Numbers can change.
In this representation here,
the surrogate-base representation,
it recognizes that regardless of
what we know about something and
what the values are,
the thing still exists.
[FOREIGN] as Kant stated.