Let's now turn our
attention to architecture.
We'll be talking about
the architecture of a database and
the architecture of the database
management system that's used to
create and maintain the database.
The architecture we're going to look
at is called is the ANSI/SPARC.
3-Level architecture.
A database is a model of
structures of reality.
It's divided into schema and data.
The schema describes the intention or
the type of the data, and
the data describes the extension.
This separation between schema and
data is done because it makes data
access more effective and efficient.
So, for example,
when we want to search for some data,
we write a query against the schema and
that query will bring back a result of
all the data that fits the structure of
the schema that were used in the query.
The separation into a single schema and
data however is not the end of it.
If the database only
consisted of schema and
data, then the schema would have to
describe aspects of what the meaning of
data is how it's used and
how it's internally organized.
This would mean that queries against
the database through that schema
would be able to reference how
the data is physically organized.
The implication of that is If we decide
to change how data is physically
organized, then the application of
the database would be affected.
Therefore, the ANSI/SPARC 3-level
architecture separates out aspects
of how data is physically organized into
what is known as an internal schema.
And data now sits under the internal
schema, such that database access,
it will appear that it goes through
the schema to access the data, but
instead what happens is that it goes
through the schema, and the request, or
chains, is translated to one at
the internal schema level and
data's accessed and
an answer is sent back.
The benefit of this is
that now it's actually
plausible to change
the way data is stored
without affecting the applications
that run against the schema.
However, a database is used by many
different applications with different
needs to display data.
Therefore for each need, for
each application of the database,
we could create an external schema.
Therefore the ANSI/SPARC
3-level architecture
prescribes a third level named
the external schema level that separates
out aspects of how data is used
by individual applications.
So now you have applications
running against external schema
that represents data in the preferred
format for those applications
requests through the external schema
are then translated to requests through
the conceptual schema, translated to
requests through the internal schema.
Data is accessed and
the response is translated up and
presented to the application
in the format that it needs.
Turn this illustration 90 degrees,
and you get the three level ANSI/SPARC
database architecture that
people normally see depicted.
You have a conceptual
schema in the middle,
you have an internal schema
implementing that and
you have a number of external schemata,
one for each major application.
The conceptual schema concentrates on
the meaning of data, the internal schema
on the storage of data, and the external
schemata on the use of data.