So let's talk about
the conceptual schema.
The conceptual schema describes all
conceptually relevant, general,
and time-invariant structural
aspects of reality.
It describes nothing related
to data representation,
physically organization, access, or use.
Here's an example, you have
the RegularUser table with Email,
BirthDate, Hometown, LastName,
MaidenName, Sex, and Salary.
At the conceptual level,
the only thing that's visible
to the query language is this table and
the columns in it.
So you could for example write a query,
select Email, BirthDate and MaidenName
from regular user, where Sex='F' and
Salary is greater than 70,000.
You cannot in that query include
anything about how the results
are displayed other than in this order,
or how the data is accessed.