Now let's talk about external schemata.
So an external schema describes part of
the information in the conceptual schema
in a form that's convenient to
a particular user group's view.
It is logically derived
from the conceptual schema.
Here's an example of a virtual table
that exists in an external schema.
The name of the virtual table,
or the view, is HighPayFemales.
It is defined as the result
of the following query.
The query selects some of the columns
of the conceptual schema table,
so it selects email, maiden name,
current city, from regular user,
where the city equals female and
the salary is greater than 70K,
and it orders it by maiden name.
The create view statement
creates the virtual table
HighPayFemales in the external schema.
So in other words,
the virtual table here has attributes,
email, maiden name and current city,
and the name HighPayFemales.
It's a virtual table.
It's a view into the database.
It never really exists.
It's just a view or
a window into the database.