An internal schema describes how
information in the conceptual schema is
physically represented, in order to get
the overall best query performance and
update performance on the database.
So let me illustrate that.
Again, we have in the middle,
the table in our conceptual schema.
That may be represented, for example,
here by a corresponding table in
the physical, internal schema.
It has, in this example here,
the same attributes.
And it may be sorted in
some particular way.
For example,
it could be sorted on LastName.
Now, in the case that there are many
queries on Salary, it might be good,
and make queries more efficient, if
there were an index defined on Salary.
So we could define an index in
a B+-tree, for example, and
we'll look at those
later on in the course.
B+-trees create logarithmic
time access to data so
it would be possible to
ask efficiently a query.
Like the one you just saw before,
that defined the external schema, and
was based on Salary.
Furthermore, it might be that we would
like to have fast access on CurrentCity.
And therefore,
we could create an additional index
on the database on CurrentCity.
That index would basically be
a table with two columns in it.
One, the list of CurrentCity,
and two, pointers to the rows
in the database that contain that
particular value of CurrentCity.
Notice that since both the B+-tree here
and the index here cannot be seen by
way up from the applications, because
of that it is possible to replace that,
to remove it, to remove this,
or to add additional indices,
all without affecting the applications
that run on the database.