Logical data independence
is a measure of
how much you can change the conceptual
schema without changing the applications
that run on the database
over the external schema.
It is more difficult to provide logical
data independence than it is to
provide physical data independence.
The reason is that the external
schemata against which the applications
are written.
Those external schemata are logically
derived from the conceptual schema.
So needless to say if you have
an application that accesses a table
in an external schema and you go
change that table in the conceptual
schema then it is plausible that
the application will be effected.