Here's the description of
the database management system
architecture that's necessary
in order to create and
support a three-level database
as we have just looked at.
This architecture or
this framework was proposed by the
American National Standards Institute
and, amazingly,
it was done as early as in 1975.
Before there really were any commercial
implementations of relational databases.
It had a profound impact on the way
relational databases were built.
The framework consists of two pieces,
the Schema Compiler piece and
the Query Transformer piece.
Let us first take a look at the top of
it here, the Schema Compiler piece.
These hexagons represent people
working in different roles
with a database management system.
The boxes represent process or
pieces of software that transform text.
The triangle represents the metadatabase
where schema definitions are stored.
The job or
the role of Enterprise Administrator is
to define conceptual database schemata.
So using the language or the interface,
one here, the Enterprise Administrator
will define a conceptual schema.
The Conceptual Schema Processor
will check that for
correct syntax, and
through a language, too,
it will store that conceptual
schema of this in the metadatabase.
An Applications Systems Administrator
is responsible for
defining external schemata.
That human role can look
at the conceptual schema
that's currently defined through
the Language Interface three.
And can express an external schema
definition through the interface four.
The External Schema Processor will
read that external schema definition,
it will check it for correct syntax.
And it will check that it is correctly,
logically derived from the conceptual
schema that was previously defined.
Finally, it will store that
external schema definition
inside the metadatabase.
And as we all ready talked about,
multiple external schemata
can be defined from the same conceptual
schema and stored as metadata.
Next, a person acting in the role
of Database Administrator,
again can look at the conceptual
schema that has been defined for
the database through
the interface three here.
Then that Database Administrator
can define an internal schema
using the language in interface 13.
The Internal Schema Processor will now
pass that internal schema definition and
make sure that it's
syntactically correct.
And make sure that it actually,
physically implements and
supports what was defined
in the conceptual schema.
When all of that is checked,
the Internal Schema Processor
can now store that internal schema
definition inside the metadatabase.
So with those three levels completed,
there is now a definition of what
the three levels of the database
will look like stored
inside the metadatabase.