So, now let's look at
the career transformer.
So, a person acting in the role of
user can now express careers on
the database using this
language interface number 12.
We previously talked about two
different ways that could be done.
The user could write ad hoc queries, and
those ad hoc queries would then be
translated down through the levels,
executed on data, and
an answer would come back to the user.
Or as we saw, the user, or a programmer
implementing a user interface
would include access to the database
inside some host language code.
And when, in the execution of that
program, the database access statements
are met, then they are sent down
through the translation, evaluated and
an answer comes back up to
the application program.
So let's talk about
these translations here.
So, here's a database query
expressed in this interface.
The external to conceptual schema and
transformer will
read the metadata which describes what
the external schema looks like and
describes what the conceptual
schema looks like.
And we're using that information from
the meta database, coming through into
phase 36 here, will translate the query
that was issued in interface 12,
to a query expressed in interface 31.
Likewise, the conceptual to internal
transformer will read the conceptual
schema definition and the internal
schema definition through interface 36,
and translate the query from
a query here at this level,
to a query here at this
level in interface 30.
And finally, the internal
schema to storage transformer
will read the internal schema
definition here through interface 34,
translate the query to be one from
over the internal schema to one that's
under the internal schema and
over the data.
So, this is essentially the operating
system level here, the language 21.
And through operating system calls,
our database calls, the operation
would be executed on the database.
The result will come back from
the operating system, and
again in the same way, will be
translated back through the levels.
And returned as an answer to the query,
or
the external schema that the user
is accessing the database through.
If this process took place every single
time there's a query that's executed
on the database, the database
would be incredibly inefficient.
Therefore, it's actually
done slightly different.
But the functionality of what happens
is exactly what I have just described.