Is a somewhat different rendition
of what I just described to you.
In this, DBA staff includes the three
human roles that I described for
you before.
The role defined conceptual schema,
internal schema, and external schema.
That's done through the DDL,
or data definition language,
with statements that
basically define them, and
the DDL compiler will compile them and
store them in the metadatabase.
With that in place a casual user
can now write an interactive query.
That query is processed
by a query compiler.
It is optimized to find
an efficient way to execute it and
it's given as a DBA command to
the one time database processor,
which will execute it together with
other queries on the database.
Looking at application programmers,
they can write application programs,
which consist of host language code
with embedded database access.
That code is passed to a precompiler and
out of the precompiler comes two things.
Number one, the host language code and
number two, the database queries or
database manipulation
language statements.
Those DML statements, are then compiled
and optimized and then combined
with the complied host link which
code in this complied transaction.
The compiled transactions
are sent tot the database and
execute by the run time,
data base process on.
Since there may be many concurrent users
on the database, a concurrency control
sub-system make sure that all
these competing transactions and
queries on the database
are executed in a proper order.