Metadata is essential for
making everything happen in a database.
One distinguish between
two kinds of metadata.
One is systems metadata,
the other one is business metadata.
Systems metadata includes
where the data came from,
how it was changed, how it's stored,
how it was mapped, who owns it,
who has the right to access it, how has
it been used, and usage statistics?
Business metadata includes, which data
is available, where is it located,
what does it mean, how can I access it,
are there any predefined reports,
predefined queries and
our current list of data.
Systems metadata is absolutely critical
to make a database management system
work and business metadata is
absolutely critical for businesses for
example, in data warehouse application.
Late in this course we going to
talk about metadata and
the use offered in data archival.