The next step of the design phase,
is to now take this graphical representation of the relations that resulted from mapping,
the extended into relationship diagram,
together with a format specifications that we created earlier and combined those two,
in create table statements that actually define these relations in SQL.
Here's the create table statement for the first one of the relations.
The user relation, the email is a varchar (50),
it is not allowed to be null. Why not?
Because you are going to participate in the primary key.
Then we have, first name,
last name and password these are all varchar (50)s. They are also not allowed to
be null but that's because we insist on collecting all that information from every user.
The primary key of this relation is email.
The SQL syntax for this is simply as stated.
Notice that these statements end in a semi colon.
So, this is the SQL that will set up this structure,
with a data format specified inside the database.
Now let's look at the regular user table,
it has five attributes;
email, birth date, sex,
currency and home hometown,
email is a varchar (50),
it can't be null,
because I intend to set it to be the primary key.
The property type sex is a single character initially set to null,
birth date is order type,
date time and initially set to the value null,
current city and hometown,
are varchar (50)s also set to null.
Primary key is email and notice the email of
the regular user of course is a foreign key on email of user.
So, foreign key email references the email in the user table,
direct modeling this relationship.
The admin user relation is very simple,
email is the primary key,
lastlogin is the only attribute initially set to null.
The primary key is also a foreign key pointing to email in the user table.
So, email in admin user is a foreign key and it references email in the user table.
Finally, the interest table has two attributes email and interests.
The primary key consists of both,
so none of them can be null.
Email in addition is a foreign key that points to the email of regular user.
Why not to the email of user?
Well, the reason is,
that it's only the regular users that actually have interests,
admin users do not.