Let's look at how requesting a friendship is
done through an insertion into the friendship table.
As before, we assume that the application knows the e-mail of the current user.
It will also know the e-mail of the friend that's
being requested through a user click on the screen,
and the relationship will be input by the user that's making the request.
With that information, this is the insertion.
So, insert into the friendship table,
and e-mail, a friends e-mail,
and date connected and a relationship.
The values the following;
the e-mail of the current user,
the friend email identified there,
the null value for date connected,
because this invitation has not yet been accepted,
and then the value of relationship read from the screen.