Let's look at the subtask view pending requests.
There are two kinds of pending requests;
pending requests to you and pending requests from you.
Let's concentrate on pending requests to you first.
When it's a pending request to you,
you know that in the friendship table,
the friend email in this case, is your email.
The one requesting you to become friends has this email.
To collect the information about the requestor,
you need a three-way join that puts together the first name,
last name, birthday, sex etc.
to the email of the person that requests you to become friends.
This three-way join is illustrated here.
So, you join friendship,
RegularUser and user and it's all on matching emails.
That email matches this one, matches this one.
Now, you got one big table with all this information in it.
Their particular row you want to extract in that table is the row
where their friends email is your email as current user,
and date connected is null because it's still pending.
So, now you've got that one row.
From that you can now extract from the requester the email,
the first name, the last name, hometown, relationship etc.
When the request is from you,
you know the following,
the email in the friendship table is your email.
To pull together all the information about
the other user you have requested to be friends with,
you need to match the user email,
the regular user email to the friends email,
and that is exactly what is done in this three-way join here.