If you decide to reject a request,
then the road to look for is the one where friend's email is your email,
and the email is that of the person that requested you to become friends.
So, delete from friendship where the email is
the value of friend's email and the friend email,
is your email is going to do the trick.
Now, if you decide to accept a request,
and the time is now,
then this update will do it.
You update the friendship table and you set date connected to now,
where the friend email is yours and the email is that of the requestor.
Finally, if you decide to click cancel,
and cancel a request that you have made,
then the following SQL statement is going to delete the appropriate row.
Delete from friendship where the email equals your email as current user,
and a friend email equals the value of the friend email identified on the form.