So, we have now completed the data first portion of
the design phase of the database application development methodology.
We took the extended interrelationship diagram,
used the mapping to generate a set of relations.
We check that the relations are in the proper Boyce-Codd normal form.
Now, the next step is to take a look at the tasks
that we specified in the specification process.
Those tasks express what tests of the application will
do relative to the extended interrelationship diagram.
Now, that we have translated that diagram into a set of relations,
we need to adjust the task to do to
the relations what they previously did to the extended interrelationship diagram.
So, in the abstract code for the task,
we need the code to work on the relational schema
as opposed to the extended interrelationship diagram.
So, let's now dive into that step of the design phase.