The attend and employment relations are both very complicated.
They both stretch, both the capabilities of the relational model
and the extended entity relationship diagrams they were mapped from.
Let's talk about the attend relation.
The attend relation is many to many relationship between regular user and school.
So, it comes as no surprise that we need the identifiers for both,
to be combined, to identify a row in attend relation.
However, adding to the complication,
we have a multi-value property type year graduated.
And we know that the way that it is modeled
is that the thing it is about has a key which is
combined with the multi-valued attribute in order to
identify each individual value for this particular combination.
We, therefore, need an identifier here that consists of three elements.
However, the customer requirements that we are working
from allows year graduated to be left blank,
because no portion of a primary key is allowed to be null.
It is not possible to use primary key in the table definition.
So I'm using unique instead.
So this relation here is going to have email is a varchar (50),
school name varchar (50).
None of those will be null because then we would not
know which relation we are talking about.
Year graduated is an integer which initially is set to null,
the intent being that a value can later be
added when the person has graduated from the school.
We use unique instead of primary key to include all of all three.
Obviously, both email and school name are foreign keys on
the relations that contain the existence of the corresponding entity.
Even this way to model things could get us in trouble.
For example, if a particular person is working,
or two educations at the same time in the same institution,
like both are bachelors and a masters in the same university at the same time,
then year graduated will be null in both cases.