We have now completed the first half of the design phase.
We started out with an extended entity relationship diagram
and some data format specifications,
and we use the mapping from
the extended entity relationship model to
the relational model to create a set of table definitions.
So, now we have completed our relational schema definition.
We now turn our attention to the tasks.
In the specification, the test stated what the application case
needs to do relative to the extended entity relationship diagram.
In the design, we now need to replace the code that states what
the application does to the database with SQL statements that realize that.