Let's first look at the View Profile text,
and concentrate on the subtext that retrieves the personal information.
So, in other words,
we are looking at how to retrieve first name,
last name, rest of
these personal information items to display on the View Profile screen.
We are making the assumption that the email of
the current user is managed by the application.
So, we are going to retrieve first name, last name, sex,
birth date, current city,
and hometown for the particular user in question.
We do that as follows: here's your SELECT, FROM, WHERE statement.
So, we select first name and last name,
birth date, sex, current city,
and hometown from the user table which contains the first name and the last name.
INNER JOIN RegularUser, which of course contains the birth date,
sex, current city, and hometown.
The INNER JOIN condition is that
user email which the application remembers is equal to RegularUser.Email,
and that email is the one that the application remembers.
That leaves us with the multi-valued attribute interests,
and we simply find that with select from interests
where the email matches the one that the application remembers.
We display those on the form.