Let us now look at the second subtext of the View Profile text,
namely the subtext education.
In that subtext, we extract school name,
school type, and year graduated.
As you see, school name and type are in the school table;
year graduated is in the attend table.
So, we need to proceed as follows.
We take the score table and join it with the attend table on matching
school names and then we extract where the email is the email of the current user.
So, let's look at the SQL for that.
We select School.SchoolName and School.Type and
we select Attend.YearGraduated and we do it by
taking the attend table and doing an INNER JOIN with
schoool and the join condition is that the two school names match.
School name must match school name,
and we extract where the email matches that of the current user.
Finally, extracting the professional information consisting of
employer name and job title is done from the employment table.
So, we select employer name and job title from employment
where the email is that of the current user and we display that information here.