The Edit Profile task has four sub tasks.
View Profile, which we just completed,
Update Personal Information, Add or Delete a School,
Add or Delete an Employer.
The first step is to populate the dropdowns namely,
School Name and Employer Name.
So, those dropdowns here, to populate those,
we need to do a selection from the set of
school names and a set of employer names that currently exist.
So, each one of the SQL statements for that are here.
SELECT SchoolName and Type FROM School,
SELECT EmployerName FROM Employer.
Now to update the personal information,
we continue to assume that the email of the current user is managed by the application.
We then read Sex, Birthdate,
CurrentCity and Hometown from the input fields
on the personal information portion of the Profile screen.
So, having read those,
we now update the RegularUser and we overwrite the Sex with a new value,
the Birthdate with a new value,
CurrentCity, and Hometown with a new value and we do it for the row
that has an Email address that matches the Email of the current user.
For each one of the Interest that's added,
we insert into the Interest table the Email of the current user, and the interest.