If the user clicks "Delete this School," then we delete
from Attend where the email matches the email of the current user.
The school name matches the school name identified to be deleted,
and the year graduated matches the year
graduated of the school that has been identified to be deleted.
If a new school is added with a school name given here and a year graduated given
here that will be done by an insertion into the Attend's table of email,
school name, and year graduated,
where the values are the email of the current user,
the school name read from input,
and the year graduated read from input.
To update an existing school,
we need to make the assumption that the application
manages the old school name and the old year graduated.
To overwrite those with the new values of school name and year graduated,
we need an update statement.
Update Attends will set the school name to
the new value and the year graduated to the new value where the following is true,
namely the email equals the email of the current user,
the school name is the old name,
and the year graduated is the old year.