Let's finally look at how to add and delete employers for particular regular user.
On the screen, we will have identified
the EmployerName and JobTitle that need to be deleted.
The following SQL statement will do the deletion.
Delete from employment where the Email matches that of
the current user and the EmployerName is
that on the screen and the JobTitle is that on the screen.
If we are adding a new job where the value of
the EmployerName and JobTitle are given in the text fields on the screen,
then the following statement will do that addition of the job.
Insert into Employment, Email, EmployerName, and JobTitle,
where the values are the Email of the current user,
the EmployerName written in the text box,
and the JobTitle written in the text box.
To update an existing job,
we will assume that the application manages OldEmployerName and OldJobTitle.
The following update employment statement will
replace the old values by the two new values.
So, update employment, set EmployerName to the new one,
set JobTitle to the new one,
where the Email is that of the current user,
and the EmployerName currently is the OldEmployerName,
and the JobTitle currently the OldJobTitle.