Let's first look at these two documents,
the login screen and
the registration screen.
And here's one of the requirements
from the customer from whom we're
building the application.
The requirement says all users
are uniquely identified by his or
her email address,
what does that tell us?
Well, it tells us that there's
an entity type of users and
that users are identified
by email addresses.
It also tells us something about the
processes, namely that email address and
password in combination will
log the user into the system.
That means there also is
an attribute of password.
So the first piece of the extended
entity relationship diagram
models users as an entity type,
with attributes email and
password, where email is a unique
identifier for the user, and
therefore we have underlined it
as an identifying attribute.
On the registration screen we also
have a first name and a last name.
I've chose to include a composite
attribute name that has first and
last name as components.
Strictly speaking, this actually
models this situation here, where
there's a name field which is composite
consisting of first name and last name.
I have chosen to specify
it like this though.