Having now addressed the data
formats of the property types,
lets talk about constraints.
Here are some examples of constraints
in the particular application we
are creating now.
For example,
DateConnected must be NULL until
a friend's request has been accepted.
Another example is you cannot
be friend with yourself.
So whenever there is an insertion into
the database to establish a friendship,
the application needs to check that
this constraint is not violated.
You could have a constraint saying that
only comments on the status of friends
is allowed.
In other words, if you try to submit
a comment on a person that is not your
friend, then the application
system should reject that.
To be a little bit more specific about
the kind of constraints we are looking
for, remember we have already
expressed constraints in
the Extended Entity Relationship
diagram.
And by specifying what
the data formatting would be,
we should not include
those on the constraints.
So where does that leave us?
Well, it basically leaves
us with a set of rules
that we can describe in the database
that we can't format our way out of.
So there's only one place left to
do it and that is to program it
into the application program so
that constraints like this are enforced.