Having now addressed the structural
aspect of the specification,
let us look at
the specification of tasks.
So for each one of the tasks we
identified in the information flow
diagram, we need to talk about
whether that's a single task or
whether it should be decomposed.
The rules of thumb I'm going to give
you are based on a deep understanding
of the internal workings of
a database management system.
In each one of the cases I'm
going to give you the rule, and
I'm going to tell you
what it is based on.
Later on when you do task decomposition,
you're going to go through these
rules that I'm giving you
in order to determine
whether the particular task you're
looking at should be decomposed or not.
So from a database management
system perspective, there's a big
difference between whether a task just
is a look up task or whether it actually
modifies the database through
an insertion, deletion, or update.
The reason for
that is that different database locks
are needed in order to support lookups
versus changes to the database.
So if many different things take place,
then that's a indication that
the test should be decomposed.
The second rule of thumb is based on
how big a portion of the database
is involved in the operation.
The bigger the portion is,
the harder it is to acquire
all the logs that are needed
in order to support concurrent execution
of transactions on the database.
So if a large number of schema
constructs are involved,
that would make you want to decompose
the task into smaller tasks
using smaller portions of the database.
The next rule of thumb is based on what
enables the different
portions of a task.
So if some portion of
a task are enabled,
then why not let those proceed instead
of waiting to later on when there might
not be resource available to run those
tasks that were earlier enabled.
The smaller portions of
a task that can run,
the easier it is to schedule the task.
The next rule of thumb is
based on what the frequencies
of the things that
are done by the task are.
If the task contains things that are
done with a high frequency and things
that are done with a low frequency,
it is a good idea to split them apart.
The reason is that high frequency
things, you want to index to run fast.
Whereas low frequency things,
you may not need to index.
The next really important
rule of thumb is related
to consistency of the database.
Is it really essential that all
the pieces of a task get done
in one transaction?
Or is it okay that things get
spread out a little bit over time?
An example of that would be
transferring money from one
bank account to another one.
So it is very important that all
the steps involved are done together.
For example, monies must be
available in the from account.
They must be subtracted from
the balance of the from account, and
they must be deposited
into the to account.
All of those things
must be done together,
in order that you do not end up
with an inconsistent database.
The final rule of thumb is based
on the question of whether
a mother task is needed
to control subtasks.
Sometimes you need a mother task,
sometimes you do not.
The banking example I just gave
you certainly needs a mother task.
We're later going to see things
that may not need a mother task.