Before we look at some examples of tests
decompensation, let us briefly talk
about web based applications,
versus traditional applications.
Web based applications
are almost completely stateless.
The amount of state may be as
little at the login information for
a session user.
There may be a small amount of
click stream data that's available
in order to proceed
with the application.
Things, however, for
web-based applications are changing.
With new technologies
such as Web 2.0 and
AJAX it is now possible to provide
much more state with the application.
Because of that web applications
are beginning to act
more like traditional applications.
What is it we have been able to
do with traditional applications?
Well, in a traditional application,
it is much easier to manage local
states separate from the database.
That means that a whole bunch of
changes can be collected, before they
are submitted to the Database
Management System for execution.
That means, that there is not
a roundtrip to the database needed
every single time a minor
thing is changed.
So it's as you have to do in a web app.
Traditionally applications are much
better to support control of
ACID transaction properties,
so that's a big advantage too.
So fortunately,
web app technology is moving closer
to traditional app technology.
An understanding of this is
necessary as we consider examples
of tasty composition.