So as our first example
of Task Decomposition,
let's now try to use our rules of thumb.
On the View Profile test,
which is the test that supports
the View Profile screen.
So by looking at the screen here,
we notice that there are three lookups.
There's a lookup of
the personal information.
the education information, and
finally the professional information for
a regular user.
All three lookups are read-only.
In other words, there's no operation or
update of the database that takes place.
All three are enabled by a user's
login or a friend's lookup.
All three have the same frequency.
A fairly large number of schema
constructs are needed for this task.
Just look in the EER diagram and see how
big a portion the personal information
covers the education information and
the professional information.
Consistency is really not critical.
So even if there is an update
going on here on the database
by some other user, whether you
get the absolute 100% up to date
version of the personal information,
the education information, and
professional information
is not really important.
Another important observation is,
that these can be done in any order.
They do not need to be done in
the order of personal, then education,
then professional information.
So there's flexibility in
the order of execution.
However all three of the must be done
in order to display the information
on the View Profile screen.
So another task is needed to make
sure that all three things get done.
Most of these are good indicators
that the task should be split up in
three subtasks.
So we take the View Profile task and
split it up in the View Personal,
View Education, and View Professional