So the first step is to find
the current user using User Email.
We can now, having found that user,
we can display on the output document
View Profile the name of the user.
Again, using the User Email
we can now move down and
check the RegularUser entity type and
by looking at the property types here
we are then able to display Sex,
BirthDate, CurrentCity,
Hometown and Interests.
That takes care of
the personal information.
Now we gotta go through each school
the user has attended and display that
information and each job the user has
had and display that information.
So let's first take a look
at the school information.
So we start with a RegularUser and
that leads us to N number of
schools that the user has attended.
So for each one of those, display
the school name and the year graduated.
Find the SchoolType and display that.
For each employer,
start with a RegularUser,
find the N employers that that
RegularUser has worked for.
And for each one of them, display
the EmployerName and the JobTitle.
So that's the abstract code, there is
no formal syntax for abstract code.
Every one has his or her own style.
But this is fairly formal and fairly
precise and fairly complete description
of what needs to take place for
each one of these subsets here.
And it is sort of the penultimate
step before writing this in SQL
on a real relational database
when we get that far.