Now let's take a second example and
look at test decomposition for
the edit profile page.
Here is the document which
is both an input and
output document that needs to be
supported by the edit profile task.
This is somewhat more complicated
than the view profile task.
Let us first check the rule of thumb for
decomposition for this task.
The first step in the edit profile task
is a lookup of personal education and
professional information in order
to be able to support editing it.
Now, fortunately we just
specified the view profile task,
so we're going to use that for that.
So that takes care of that step.
In order to populate the edit profile
screen, it is necessary for us to
go to the database and look up the list
of schools and the list of employers.
Without those we won't be able
to populate the drop down menus.
The added profile task
may end up editing
any one of the three
groups of information.
The personal, the educational,
and the professional information.
Both reading from the database and
writing to the database are possible
in the edit profile task.
Reading for example, to look up
the list of schools and employers.
And writing could take place in
order to execute an insertion,
a deletion, or an update.
Certainly insertion is
possible if an extra school is
added to the education section.
Deletion is possible if
one of them is removed.
An update is possible if information
has changed, for example,
in the personal information section.
The only thing that's required
in order to enable one
of these operations is the users login
and then separate edit requests.
As you can see,
there's a separate save here.
There's a separate add and save here.
Separate add and save here.
The frequencies of the things
that happen in this task
are somewhat different.
Some of the information will not change,
like sex and birthdate.
Current city might.
Interest might change overtime.
The education won't change
that many times, but
your job history may change overtime.
These are not great differences in
frequency but there are differences.
Clearly there are several different
schema constructs involved.
There's both the personal information
portion for user and for regular user.
There's the whole education portion.
And there's the whole
professional portion.
Again, consistency is not
necessarily critical.
If someone else is looking up
this profile that the owner
of the profile is currently updating,
it is not
essential that the absolute up to
the second latest version is available.
There's some sequencing of what needs
to take place, so the lookup or
the read to the database of
course needs to be done first.
And then followed by any number
of edits or additional lookups.
A model task is clearly needed for this.
This task should be decomposed
into a set of subtasks.
So the edit profile task
should be subdivided into
view profile that's read only.
Update the personal information.
Add and delete schools.
Add and delete jobs.
This subtask will update only
the regular user information.
This one could update both
regular user and school.
Likewise, this one could update both
regular user and employer information.
So, as we did in our first example,
our job is now to describe the abstract
code that's going to make this happen.
And the idea is to say how each
of these are going to take place,
which will tie this input output
document that sits outside of the system
boundary, through the task edit profile,
to the database.