The first step of the task is to
execute the View Profile task.
That task will populate the School and
Employer drop down lists.
The next step is to sit back and
do nothing.
As long as no one pushes one of
the buttons to add or delete or
save, we don't need to do anything.
So sit around, do nothing.
When a button is pushed,
then do the following.
If the button that's pushed is
the Save Personal Information,
then update the personal information and
run View Profile again
as you did in the beginning in
order to display the new state.
If it's the Delete This School
button that's pushed,
then delete the school and run
View Profile to redisplay the screen.
If it's Delete This Job,
then delete the job, run the View
Profile to redisplay the screen.
If it's the Add Another School button
that's pushed, then, one, View Profile
again and display the added profile
screen with room to add another school.
If it's Add Another Job button that's
pushed, then run View Profile again,
redisplay the edit profile screen
with room to add another job.
If the Save School button is pushed,
then add the school to the database,
rerun View Profile, and
redisplay the edit profile screen.
If it's the save job
button that's pushed,
then add the job, rerun view profile
to redisplay the edit profile screen.
Finally, if the Cancel button is pushed,
then run View Profile for
the current user and
display that screen.
In this and the previous example,
I've used the following notation.
I used bold, underline for
the task definition.
I use bold for task calls,
so it says View Profile.
I use italics for names of buttons,
such as Delete This School,
Delete This job, etc.