Without going into the same
level of detail as I did
with the first two examples.
Let's take a look at test
decomposition for friend requests.
The idea gain is that we have the forms
that are the interface
to the application.
And our job is to now talk
about the decomposition
of the tests that are necessary
in order to tie these forms
through the task into the database.
If we did a closer analysis using the
rule of thumb for task decomposition for
this task we would arrive
at the following result.
The request friend test would
be separate from the others.
This task would update the database with
a request and would support this form.
The view, cancel, accept, and
reject request task is the one that
supports this form, and supports actions
taken to the requests that are pending.
It would end up being decomposed in
two subtasks, view the request and
then support the accept,
reject, and cancel options.
This subtask would update
the friendship relationship type.
This task would support the reading
of user and regular user and
friendship information.