This basically complete
the specification phase
of our database development methodology.
We have generated an extended
energy relationship diagram,
we have looked at data formats,
and we have looked at constraints.
And based on that, we then looked
at the test decomposition and
wrote abstract code for the tasks.
We now need to take a little detour.
When we come back again,
we're going to proceed with a design.
In the design,
we're going to translate the extended
relationship diagram to
a Relational Database Schema.
And we're going to take the abstract
code for the test and put in the SQL
that is necessary, in order for the test
to do to the relational database,
what our abstract code did to the
extended entity relationship diagram.