Here's one more requirement for
the cosmos we're building
the application for.
It's says that all GT online users
except admin users have a profile.
What did we learn from that?
We learned that they are not just users.
They are also admin users.
The way we specify that is as follows.
The users actually has two subtypes.
It has regular users and admin users.
The regular users are those that have
this additional information in their
profile whereas admin users do not.
An additional requirement
from the customer says that
administrative users have some of
the same information as regular users,
namely e-mail address, password,
first name, and last name.
So it is okay to keep those as
properties of user in general.
Since both regular users and
admin users have them,
they would then be able to inherit those
properties from the super type user.
It is also further specified here
that the admin users do not have all
the other properties that are in
the profile of regular users.
Then it says a user must be either
an administrator or a regular user.
That must, is reflected by
the mandatory relationship here.
And it says the user must be
either an administrator or
a regular user, but never both.
That means that the constraint
here on the super sub type is
a disjointness constraint.
The only additional
attribute an admin user has,
other than those inherited from a user,
is that of the last login date and time.