Looking further down
the edit profile screen,
we see the education section of it.
Looking at the requirements
from our customer is a snippet,
says a list of schools from
which the user can select
is maintained by
the system administrator.
So in other words,
we have a list of schools as
an entity type in the database.
Further says that school
names are unique,
that means that school name is
an identifying attribute of school.
It says that user can have any number
of schools associated with him or her.
So that means for
a particular user, many schools
can be associated with that user.
Of course, for a particular school
there may be many regular users who
have attended that school, so given one
school there may be many regular users
associated with that school.
In a unique relationship instance
between a regular user and
a school, there's year graduated
date associated with it.
Since a regular user may
attempt the same school for
many different levels of education,
like bachelors and masters, for
example, the year
graduated is a multi-value.
So here's the screen that an admin user
uses to maintain a list of schools and
their types.
Each school must have a school type.
So the relationship here is mandatory.
A school type, of course, can be
the type from any schools on the list.