So at the bottom of the Edit Profile
screen, is the Professional section.
Just like a regular user can
have attended multiple schools,
a regular user may have
had several employers.
Here you see the screen that the admin
user uses to maintain a list of
employers.
So, we have an entity type of Employer.
Employers have the property
type Employer Name, and
Employer Names are unique.
As we saw from the Edit Profile screen,
a regular user may have had multiple
employers over time, and, obviously,
a particular employer may have multiple
regular users working for that employer.
Job title is not maintained
by the administrative user.
It can be anything that
the regular user wants to insert.
It's a multi-value, because over time
a particular regular user may have
held different job titles for
the same employer.