Let's look at the two screens that are
used to request and accept friendships.
So a particular user can request
multiple other users to be friends.
For each one of those requests, there is
an instance of the request relationship.
So one regular user may have requested
several different friendships.
In the pending request here,
the list of people who have
requested to be friends with you.
Here is the list of people that
you have requested as friends.
When a user accepts a request, that adds
an instance to the accept relationship.
So a particular regular user
may have accepted requests for
friendships from multiple
different users.
The date connected records the date
that the invitation was accepted.
Notice in this requirement it's very
interesting that friendship here
is not always reciprocal.
Just because Emily is
a friend with Sarah,
does not necessarily imply that
Sarah is a friend with Emily.