Adding it all together, here is
the EER diagram we have arrived at.
We have a set of users.
The users are uniquely
identified by email.
Users have passwords and
they have names that are composed
from first and last names.
A user must either be a regular user or
an admin user, but cannot be both.
Therefore, the constraint is disjoint.
Regular users have profiles with sex,
birthdate, current city, and
hometown, and a list of interests.
Admin users only have a single property
name the last time they logged in.
Regular users may have
attended multiple schools.
And a particular school may have
multiple regular users that attended it.
A school must have a school type.
Schools are identified by school name,
school type identified by type name.
A regular user may have worked for many
employers and a particular employer of
course may have many regular
users working for that employer.
A particular employer could hold
multiple titles over time for
the same employer.
Employee names are unique.
You have the friendships.
Regular users request
multiple friendships.
And regular users can accept
Date connected reflects the date that
our friendship request was accepted.