Please notice that the way
I just summarized that
extended entity relationship diagram
was quite mechanical in nature.
It would actually be possible to write
a program that would take as input and
extend it into relationship diagram and
then read out in English
exactly what it means.
No more, no less.
When you are talking with your customer
about your database specification,
they will not be able to understand the
extended entity relationship diagram.
They might be able able to understand
this English representation
of that diagram.
Of course we all understand that when
reading this, you need to pay very
very careful attention to every single
word that's in that description.