Now that we have used the input and
output documents for
the application to help
us with the specification
of the database in terms of an extended
entity relationship diagram,
let us take a look at what kind of
data formats are going to be needed.
We're going to take a look at
the documents that are input to or
output from the data base
because whichever format
it is that's required for those,
corresponding formats will eventually be
needed to represent property types
inside a relational data base.
So looking, for example,
at the user entity type,
let's talk about some
of the property type.
So email could, for
example, be 36 characters.
Here's an example of that.
A password could be
maximum 20 characters.
There might also be a restriction
on how short it's allowed to be.
A first name could be 25 characters,
last name 40.
Addresses, when needed, are very,
very difficult to deal with.
A couple of years ago when I
was looking at address formats,
I ran into the United States Postal
Service's recommendation for
addresses across the world.
It's a whopping 200+ page guideline.
Guidelines like that take specialists
to develop, and it takes a lot of time.
Instead of every single database
designer out there who needs to
create addresses in their database,
maybe they should take a look
at what other people have done.
In general, you can extrapolate that
idea into one of the basic concepts when
it comes to data formatting,
namely beg, steal, and borrow.
If someone already has spent a lot
of time thinking about this,
why would you do it, too?
Continuing, for the regular user,
some examples could be birthdate
might have this format.
Sex might have this.
Current city hometown may have, say,
20 characters, interest and multi-value
attribute with 16 characters per each
one of the values in the multi-value.
To determine what the data
format should be,
you will need to look at the input and
output documents, and
you might need to consult with
a customer to ask what their needs are.
That detail was not specified in the
description that you read previously.