The database application development
methodology was specifically designed
for applications that
are supported by databases,
it will not work in general for
software development projects.
Furthermore, in order for
the methodology to work certain
assumptions must hold true.
The assumptions are as follows.
We assume that business
processes are well designed.
We assume that all documents are known.
We assume that tasks are known.
We assume that the system boundary
is known, and we assume that
one database schema unifying all views
can be designed for the database.
Documents represent
anything that's input to or
output from the applications
that run on the database.
The tasks represent the processing that
takes place using those input documents,
and generating those output documents,
and
appropriately updating
the database in the process.
If we cannot create a database
scheme that unifies all the views,
then the methodology fails.
Anyone who has been associated with
a database development project
knows that this is
an incredibly difficult task.
In an organization there
are many many different
interests that need to be unified.
People may have different goals.
There may be power struggles involved.
There might be company
politics involved, etc.
Without a doubt, this is the most
difficult part of the whole process.
You might ask the questions, if it's
that difficult, is that a problem with
the methodology or
is it a problem with the organization?
It is always a problem
with the organization.
One definition of an organization
is that it's an entity created
to pursue a shared set of goals.
So if the organization
cannot successfully arrive
at such a unifying view, then it's
a problem with the organization.