Immediately after registering,
a new user would be sent
to the edit profile screen.
The edit profile screen contains some
personal information, list of interests,
their education, and
their professional information.
The basic personal
information contains sex,
birthday, current city, hometown,
and a list of interests.
Entering the personal information and
hitting save will save that information.
Any number of interests can be added,
one at a time,
by using the add button and
typing the interest in that field.
To add a school,
the new user uses the drop-down menu and
types in the year graduated,
if applicable, and hit save.
Similarly, to add a new job,
the user enters the information
by picking from the drop-down,
enters the job title, and says save.
The edit profile screen, obviously, is
going to be solved in potentially many
types of information being written into
the database, the person's information,
interests, education information and
profession information.
But, notice that there will
also be information that's
read from the database.
For example, because the drop down-list
for school and the drop-down list for
employer needs to be consoled in
the database to populate the screen.