Let's now see what that looks like
from the view profile screen.
You see that Michael Bluth now has Sex,
BirthDate, Currency, Hometown,
and a list of Interests entered.
He also has two schools entered
one is a college/university,
the other one is a high school.
He has graduated from both.
He also has a job in the tier with a
title Assistant to the Regional Manager.
As you noticed on the previous screen,
to enter a school there
was a drop-down menu.
Likewise, to enter an employer for
a job there was a drop-down menu.
A number of administrative users
behind the scenes will maintain
the list of scores and
the list of employers.
The View Profile screen also
contains a number of links that
will allow you to go to other screens.
For example, the view friend screen
will show the list of Friends for
this particular user.
Log Out, of course,
will log you out of the system.
The View Pending Requests screen, you
could see the list of friends' requests
that have not yet
been accepted or rejected.
And the Edit Profile link will send you
back to the Edit Profile screen that we
looked at previously.
Notice that the View Profile screen
is not an input to the database,
it is an output document from
the database where all the information
about the user's profile has
been read from the database and
written onto this output document.
There is, of course,
control information here
that leads you to a different screen,
depending on which link you choose.