The search screen is an output document.
It returns to search result
based on the search criteria.
The request new friends screen is
an input document to the system.
The pending friend request screen for
Michael Bluth
shows here the people that have
requested to be friends with Michael.
Michael can then either then push accept
or reject for each one of these friends.
This is the list of friends with whom
you have requested to become friends.
So Phyllis here, you have asked
to be friends with Phyllis.
You could decide to cancel
that request if you want to.
This document is both an input and
output document.
It's an output document from the
database because it displays information
from the database.
It is also an input document to the
database because it will cause changes
in the database depending on whether
you hit the Accept or Reject button.
Of course if you hit the Cancel button
it will delete your request to Phyllis
for her to become a friend of yours.
The friends' list form is an output
document from the database.