The output of the analysis phase of
the database application developement
methodology is
an information flow diagram.
Here is the information flow diagram
that results from our analysis
of the requirements to the system.
Let's first look at the form Log In.
So the Log In Form is
an input to the Log In task.
The Log In task reads from the Database
to confirm that the combination of
email address and password is correct,
and if it is logs in the user.
The Registration Form
is an input document,
the result of providing the registration
information right in to the Database,
that information for that new user.
The Profile Edit document is both an
input document and an output document.
It's an input document in that
both personal information,
interests, education information, and
professional information is going to be
written in to the Database, potentially.
It's also an output document, because
to populate with school and employee
information in the Profile document,
a read from the Database is necessary.
The View Profile document is
simply an output document from
reading the corresponding
information from the Database.
Likewise the Friends List is
a read from the Database, so
the Friends List is
an output document only.
We have not talked about
the Status/Comments document.
It is used for many different things,
for example, viewing the status and
updates it serves as an output document.
If you want to add a status
update it's an input document.
If you want to add comments
about someone's status update
then it's an input document.
Read more about that in
the requirement description.
The Friends Search and Results document
is an input and an output document.
When the search criteria
are given to the search for
friends database qualified potential
future friends will be read
from the Database and
written on to the document.
The Friend Request document
is an input document.
The information on it will result in
writes to the Database about the request
that has been made.
The Pending Friends List Is both
an input and an output document.
It will be populated by
a read from the Database and
you taking action starts as accepting or
rejecting an invitation will result
in a write in to the database.
There are several things that
I want to know this year.
First, I followed the syntax and
the rules for
creating information flow
diagrams presented earlier.
Notice, how the names of the
input-output documents in the test very,
very closely reflect those that I
used in the requirements document.
The information flow
diagram is just a first,
high-level specification of the system.
As we analyze further
the tasks of the system,
you will learn much more
about what they need to do.
In spite of that,
it is not necessary to go back and
refine this information flow diagram.
There's only so
much you can code by boxes and baubles.
So, just take this as the first,
top-level specification of the system,
which will form the basis for
the next phase of the methodology.
So the information flow diagram clearly
models the system that was described
by the customer.