Instead of the information
flow diagram modeling clearly,
the requirements of the customer.
As a software engineer or
computer scientist you might be tempted
instead to think about it as follows.
It's an application,
you got to log on to it.
So, there's a log in document and
a log in task.
You got to maintain the data base.
There's a bunch of documents involved in
that maintenance, as input and output.
And you need to generate
some reports as output.
So, the application will have three
tasks, login, maintain the database, and
generate the report.
Don't do that.
That does not model the future
system you're building.
There's models programs, code, etc.
That's not what you want to do.