We have now looked at the customer's
requirements to this application system.
From those requirements we designed
an information flow diagram.
The next phase in our database
application methodology
is that of specification.
We are going to concentrate
on specifying the database.
In order to do that, we're going to
look at the input/output documents to
the system and we're going to use
those to help us design an extended
entity relationship diagram representing
a specification of the database.
Subsequent to that,
we are then going to look at the tasks
of the information flow diagram and
from each one of those we are going to
provide a specification of what the task
will do relative to the input and
output documents and
the database that we have now designed.
With a little bit more detail,
the output of the specification
phase will be an extended entity
relationship diagram, data formats,
constraints, and
then the task decomposition.