Given an information flow diagram,
with documents that are input
documents to the database or
output documents from the database,
how does one go about creating
a specification of the database?
When the database discipline was young,
people talked about this as
the art of database specification,
or the are of database design.
Over the years I have developed this
database development methodology, and
it attempts to take some of
the art out of the process and
add in some mechanical steps.
So I have two fundamental questions.
One is, what goes into the database?
And the second one is,
what comes out of the database?
Corresponding to each one of these two,
I have two observations.
First, observations related to
what goes into the database.
So everything in the database
has got to come from somewhere.
It doesn't happen by magic.
And everything on an input document,
must go somewhere
corresponding with the second question,
I have these two observations.
Everything in the database
should be used for
something, otherwise why
is it in the database?
And everything on an output
document must come from somewhere.
We are now going to proceed by
looking at the documents, and
using these four observations to help us
create a specification of the database.