Let me now give you
an overview of the methodology.
In database application development
methodologies data is always first.
In general software development
methodologies process is often first.
So, they will concentrate
on laying out the class
diagrams in just the right way to get
the functionality just the right way.
And then they will hang the data
onto the classes where they fit.
In database development it's data first.
And once data is designed just right,
we would hang the processes
on where they fit.
So, the four phases are Analysis,
Specification, Design,
and Implementation.
So the idea is that in the analysis
phase here, we start with
all the information that's provided by
the customer, and then the end product,
the output of the analysis phase,
is an information flow diagram.
That diagram again together with all
the information provided by the customer
constitutes the input to
the specification process.
Remember data is first.
So in the specification process,
the first thing we do is to create
an Diagram or
EER diagram representing the data.
With that as a foundation,
we then go ahead and
create a specification of the tasks,
or applications that need to run
on the database represented by this Or
EER diagram.
Then in design,
we first concentrate on translating the
diagram to a relational database schema.
With that in place, we now take
the task that represented what needs to
happen on the Diagram and
represent in an abstract code,
accessing the relational database
represented by the schema.
Finally in the implementation step, we
take the relational database schema,and
we use a specific implementation
in our sample case,
use MySQL,
to create the relational database.
We then look at the abstract
code with the embedded SQL and
use a programming language,
like for example PHP,
with embedded SQL to represent the tests
that need to run on this database.
That brings us all the way from
analysis, starting with customer
requirements, all the way to a running
database application implementation.
Needless to say if we don't know
the customer's requirements,
the methodology is not going to
result in a database application
that meets any requirements
that user might have.