Here's the notation we're going to
use for an information flow diagram.
The ellipsis represent tasks.
The documents represent input and
output screens, as you've seen in
the requirements specification.
The arrows represent information flow.
Very importantly, information flow.
Not control flow.
So this is not a flowchart,
this is a chart that shows potential
information flow through the arrows.
And then finally, the broken line
here represents the system boundary.
So in this example here,
we are implementing a system and
you can see the boundary of the system
here is what we're implementing.
Inside on that system there is a number
of tasks, task T1, T2, T3 and T4.
There's also a number of documents that
we use to interact with the system, D1,
D2, D3, D4, etc.
If you look at document D1,
then document D1 is an input
document to test T1.
Test T1 may then interact with
the database by writing things in
the database and
reading things from the database.
Document D2 is both an input and
an output document.
Test T1 will read information from D2,
will interact with the database
potentially writing in the database and
reading from the database and
returning information to document D2.
It's possible that a task can
interact with multiple documents,
as you see here.
So, as I mentioned before,
this is an information flow diagram,
not a control flow diagram.
There are some rules of
this symbolic language.
You never connect two documents.
You never connect two tasks.
So these are the only ways that the
document is allowed to be constructed.