Having now read the document that
describes the client's requirements,
let us now analyze some of those
requirements in more detail.
So all users will log in via
the GTOnline login screen.
Users are uniquely identified
by their email address and
providing a correct email password
combination and hitting log in,
the user will be logged into the system.
If a wrong incorrect
combination of email and
password is presented on the screen,
then the user should be sent to some
error message, and
back to the login screen to try again.
If a user has not previously logged in,
then he or
she needs to register first,
by pushing the Register button.
Notice, as the user interacts with the
login screen, the information provided
is not written into the database
as a result of the login process.
However, the test that checks the login
information will read information from
the database to make sure that the user
who's about to login in is a valid user,
and has provided the correct email and
password.
So this is purely an input document.