On the register screen the new user
first provides first name and last name,
and then an email and password, together
with a confirmation of that password.
If that email is not previously
used by another user, and
if the password and the confirmed
password are identical, then the result
of this will be that a new user is
created with that email and password.
Should the user join this process,
remember that he has been
previously registered.
They can push cancel, which would
send them back to the login screen.
Notice that the register document is
an input document to the system, and
as a result of interacting
with that registration task,
the information will be
written into the database.