As a result of the specification phase of
the database application development methodology,
we generated an extended entity-relationship diagram
together with a set of test decompositions and
associated abstract code specifying what the test would
do relative to the extended entity-relationship diagram.
Our next phase of the methodology is the design phase.
In the design phase,
we first concentrate on data and take
the extended entity-relationship diagram and translate that into a relational schema.
We then take the abstract code for the tasks and
translate that into abstract code with embedded SQL
that will do to the relational schema what the tests was
specified to do through the extended entity-relationship diagram.
In order to understand that first step of the design phase,
we have taken a detour to find out enough about relations and enough about
the mapping of the extended entity-relationship model
to relations that we'd be able to carry out that step.