So, here's the extended entity relationship diagram we ended up with.
Just in review, we have a set of users.
Users are uniquely identified by their Email,
and in addition to that property type,
it has property type of Password and Name
which is composite consisting of First and LastName.
Users have two subsets: RegularUsers and AdminUsers.
The two subsets are disjoint.
In other words, extensions often cannot overlap.
Each one of these subsets of course will inherit the properties of the supertype,
so RegularUser will inherit Email,
Password, and Name, and so will AdminUser.
AdminUser in addition has a property type LastLogin
whereas RegularUser has a number of property types: Sex,
Birthdate, CurrentCity, and HomeTown,
and then a multi-valued property type Interests.
RegularUsers also are connected to the many Schools that may have attended,
and each one of these Schools will have a SchoolType.
RegularUsers also have worked for a number of Employers.
They may have worked for the same Employer several times,
each time with a different JobTitle.
Employers are uniquely identified by the EmployerName,
as Schools are uniquely identified by SchoolName.
Friendships may be requested and may be accepted.
So, a RegularUser can request a Friendship with an other RegularUser.
That other RegularUser in turn may accept that Friendship.
For a particular RegularUser, of course,
they will be a set of Friendships that that RegularUser has requested along
with a set of Friendship that that RegularUser has accepted to enter into.
So, our job now is to take
this extended entity relationship diagram and translate it into a relational database.
We will do that a little step at a time.