Now, let us concentrate on mapping the portion of the entity relationship diagram that
tie regular users to the schools they attended
and to the employers that they were employed by.
Let us start here at the bottom.
The entity type, SchoolType,
results in a relation with a single property type namely TypeName,
which is the identifying property type of that relation.
So, therefore, TypeName in essence will have values
that is just a listing of the different kinds of types like high school,
middle school, elementary school, etc.
The School entity type has identified property type SchoolName.
For that entity type,
there'll be a relation school,
it has SchoolName as a property type,
it's the primary key,
and then it has type as an additional property because it is
the many site of a one to many relationship that many site can point to the SchoolType.
So, the type you see here is basically
a foreign key pointing to the primary key of school type.
The attend relationship type is many-to-many relationship type as you can see.
In order to map many-to-many relationship types,
we need the identifying property type of each one of the participating entity types.
So, we need Email to identify RegularUser and we need SchoolName to identify the School.
So, therefore, it's no surprise that for the attend many-to-many relationship type,
we will have both the Email and the SchoolName included.
What is a little bit different about
this mapping is that for each one of these instances,
there is a YearGraduated associated with it.
One reason for that could be that you might attend, for example,
Georgia Tech twice, once for your bachelor's and one for your master's.
For each one of those, there will,
of course, be a unique YearGraduated.
How do we model a multivalue like this?
Well, it's a multivalue of that relationship type,
so we would need the identifier for the relationship type,
which is a combination of these two.
We can collapse that mapping all-in-all into
a single relation call Attend that has both the School identifier of SchooName,
the RegularUser identifier of Email,
and then YearGraduated, all of those combined as unique.
The employment relationship type is also a many-to-many relationship type,
so it will result in a relation called
employment that will have the Email of the RegularUser employed,
the EmployerName of the Employer,
and as before, an attribute for the JobTitle, which is multivalue.
So, this is very similar in nature to the relation we just generated here.
So, Employment will have Email,
EmployerName, and JobTitle as unique.
Noticed that for this unique or for this key,
SchoolName is a foreign key on SchoolName of School.
For this unique key,
EmployerName is a foreign key pointing to
the primary key EmployerName for the employer relation.
Notice that I have indicated the RegularUser table here,
although we have previously dealt with that.
The reason is that the RegularUser who
participates in the Attend relationship and the Employment relationship,
those are users who have emails that of course,
appear in the RegularUser Email list.
So, therefore, Email of Attend and
Email of Employment are foreign keys on Email in RegularUser.