Let's first concentrate on the mapping of
the super sub type relationship that connects users to regular users and admin users.
There were a couple of options in the mapping,
we have chosen the option where we create a relation for each one of the entity types.
So, for the first entity type user,
we create the relation user it has identifying
property type email and that therefore becomes the primary key of the user relation.
In addition, it has property types password
and it has property types first name and last name.
Unfortunately as you recall,
composite property types are not preserved in the mapping.
User has two sub types;
regular user and admin user,
both of those will inherit email password,
first name and last name.
However, in the mapping of each one of
these entity types the only one of these that will appear is
the identifying property type email which will become the primary key
in the admin user relation and in the regular user relation.
In the admin user relation,
we have in addition the last log in and in
the regular user relation we have an additional four properties namely;
sex, birth date, current city and hometown as reflected here.
As you recall, multi value property types,
each one of those,
will get its separate relation together with
the identifying property type for that entity type.
So, for the interest property type a separate relation will be generated and that
relation will have the combination of email and interest as primary key.
You see here that email of admin user in addition to
being primary key also is a foreign key pointing back to the user relation.
In other words, it's not possible to have an admin user who is not also a user.
Similarly for the regular users,
the email primary key of regular user
is also a foreign key pointing back to email end user.
Finally, interests are properties of regular users,
therefore email which is part of the primary key of interest,
email will be a foreign key pointing back to email of the regular user.