Finally, let's look at the mapping of the week entity type friendship.
This is a fairly complex situation.
So you have a strong entity type regular user and
a weak entity type friendship and there's
an identification relationship type between them.
So in other words in order to identify
friendship you're going to need the identifier for regular user.
But wait, there's one more of those involved.
So in order to understand a friendship you need to know
not just the regular user that requested it but
also the regular user who has been asked to accept it.
So when looking at the friendship relationship type it will have email twice.
It will have email of the one making the request and
email of the friend that the request is being made to.
Then there are two property types relationship and
date connected and date connected is going to initially be
null and then subsequently if the one invited to become
friends accepts it will be set to the date of that accept.
Again I've included this one in order to show that
both the email of the requester and the potential acceptor of
the friendship is going to be an email of
a regular user since only regular users can participate in these friendships.
An interesting aside about this friendship relation is the following.
Notice that there are two one to many relationships into friendship and typically when we
have a many to many relationship type that can actually be
modeled by two one to many relationships into the same entity type.
When that's the case,
then the combination is a key.
That corresponds very much to other cases we've seen of many to
many relationship types where you take a key from each end of the relationship.