We are now ready to look at the last phase of
the database application development methodology, implementation.
Let us review where we are.
So, in design, we created a relational database schema and wrote the SQL for it.
We also wrote the SQL for the tests that are going to access that relational schema.
We surrounded that SQL with abstract code.
In the implementation phase,
we are again going to do data first.
So, we start out with relational schema and we
need to implement that on relational platform.
We will install MySQL to run it on.
After we have done that,
we'll take a look at the abstract code that surrounds the SQL,
we will implement that in PHP and we will show how to
run that PHP script with the embedded SQL on the database we have set up.