Now, addressing the issue that multiple access paths
really add up is done also by the RegularUser example.
So, if you recall back to previous phases of the methodology,
there was a pending request from you for someone to be friends,
that accesses the RegularUser table.
There was also a pending request to you that accesses the RegularUser table.
Then, there is the View Profile test which is
just a retest and that accesses the RegularUser table.
Then, of course, there was an Edit Profile test that updates the regular use information.
So, all of these different queries,
insertions, deletions to updates and so on,
they all affect RegularUser.
We need to know the frequencies of each one of these to see what
the weight of access on RegularUser is from an overall point of view,
and to help guide us as to whether we therefore need additional indexing of RegularUser.