Most tables will be read from by some of the tests and written to by some tests.
So, here's an example here again,
continuing to use RegularUser.
So, in View Profile we do a selection,
that's a read from RegularUser.
In Edit Profile of RegularUser,
we clearly are updating, thus,
writing back to the database the new state of that RegularUser we are updating and here,
we actually, initially do an insertion of RegularUser into the RegularUser table.
So, you see here reading, writing, and writing.
In general, reads are faster if a table is indexed.
If there are multiple indices on a table, however,
then writing is slow because not only will we have
to write the updated data or insert the data in the table,
but we are also going to have to maintain
any additional indices that are defined on that table.
On the other hand,
many writes will require that we first find what we need to write.
So, for example, in an update we are clearly first
identifying and finding the RegularUser tuple that needs to be updated,
and then we are updating it.
So, although writes are slower,
if we don't have an index to find what we need to write fast, then we are in trouble.
Of course, in insertion there is nothing to find because it's a new tuple.
But what if we need to find the proper place to insert it in some order table?
So, we're having a mixture of reads and writes will make it more
complicated to decide whether additional indices are needed on the table or not.