So, let me now give you some general advice to summarize our discussion of these issues.
First of all, pay attention to size.
Even for relatively small table,
you might not be able to keep it in memory at
all times and you might need to index it to get to [inaudible].
Multiple queries add up.
You need to consider all the different ways in which a particular table is accessed.
In general, writes will suffer inefficiency when you index a table.
However, in most cases,
the write is preceded by a read,
which benefits from an index on the table.
There are some neat tools that many database management systems come with.
One valuable tool is a tool to measure performance.
Some database systems are able to print out for
you the actual query graph that's used to execute a query.
Very valuable to help you understand whether you need to further index that table or not,
to force the use of a better query graph.
I recommend that you think globally but you act locally.
So, make small changes and when you have made small changes,
compare the performance before the change to the performance after the change.
If you want to know in more details what you're doing,
you actually need to learn more about efficiency,
more about physical database organization,
and more about query optimization.