Let me show you how I can run PHP Scripts for some of
the tasks in the GT Online example that we have discussed in class.
By now, all of us should have either vamp,
mamp or lamp stack installed on our local machines.
Let us first head to the php my admin page which contains
the GTOnline complete database with the tables installed a regular user,
user, and friendship which we'll be focusing on in this demo.
Now to run PHP scripts,
we need to have a local host server running on our machines.
For that, I'll next head to the domain lan, the MacBook.
For Windows users, you need to go to the command prompt and type run.
The command to start the php local host server is php -S localhost: and port number.
The port number can be anything,
you just need to remember the port number that we have
entered and my local host server has
been started on the same folder which contains all my PHP Scripts.
So gtpe, underscore db,
underscore course is the same folder which contains
all the PHP scripts that I'm going to run in this demo.
Next, I head to the browser and I will first
show you the log in page which is the first page in the application.
To access the log in page,
you need to type localhost:8000.
The port number again should be the same port number that
we gave by starting the local host server;
/login.php and this takes me to the application login page.
Now I need to enter the login credentials of
a particular user to get into the application.
I'll head back to the php my admin page to pick up the details of one particular user.
I'll go to the user table and I'll select Michael Bluth for example.
I will just copy his email address and remember his password.
Heading back to the log in page,
I entered the details which were already entered in the database and try logging in.
I've been successfully able to log into
the user page and I can currently view the profile of Michael Bluth.
Now the view profile is also another php page which is running in
the background that was accessed from the login.php page.
So next I can do a few tasks on this page like viewing the profile,
editing the profile, viewing the friends of the user, etc.
Let's try making a few changes to the already existing profile of Michael Bluth.
For that, I need to go to the edit profile page.
Let's quickly head back to the php my admin page and
verify the details that are currently existing on that log in page.
So it says the date of birth is 1st January,
1971 and the current city is New York.
So if I head back to the php my admin page and I go back to the regular user table,
I can find out that Michael Bluth's date of birth is 1st January,
1971 and his current city is New York.
So if I go back to the edit profile page and change
his current city from New York to San Francisco,
next I click "Save".
Next, let's see if these changes
that we've made have been reflected in the database or not.
If you go back to the php my admin page and refresh the page,
you can see that the user Michael Bluth,
his city, his current city has been updated to San Francisco.
Exactly what we did on the application.
Similarly, we can also view friends of
Michael Bluth and these are the same that I again listed on the database.