Now that I've shown you how to use BHB scripts on the web browser,
let us take a look what's inside a few of them now.
I'll take you to the login.php page which was a first page on the application.
So here is the page.
The first step in the php page is to connect to the database using three credentials.
The first is the host,
the host name should be correct.
Next is the user and the password.
The user and the password is the same which we enter while
creating the database on the mamp or lamp stack.
Next we select the database GT online complete which is the database we are focusing on.
We need to enter the details of
the email ID and the password of the user as our first step.
And since we're requesting data back from the web browser,
this is a post request which is mentioned in this php code.
Also you'll notice that every step,
we have error statements to help you debug in case something goes wrong.
Next the page requests the user to enter the email and password.
Once we have entered the email and password,
it gets stored in these two files.
Next, the query which runs in the background to retrieve the user,
the details of the user,
is the query as follows: select "Start" from user,
the email is that username that entered and password is the password that I can enter.
Now once this query runs in the background,
it returns me a result set.
Next I check the number of rows in the result side is equal to zero.
That means I have not been returned any user from the web application.
That means the log in has failed or no such user exists.
So if all such things go smoothly and I'm able to successfully log in,
the session starts and the session is what,
which will be active till the user logs out.
Next, I'm redirected to the profile.php page which is done by the header.
The rest part of the script includes HTML.
HTML is what we see in the front end of the application.
This HTML code uses the php script that I explain to you just know.