As in all the previous phases,
let's look at data first.
Following this, you're going to see a number of WAMP stack demos.
In the first one, you're going to learn how to install a WAMP stack.
Once the WAMP stack is installed,
it's ready to accept a database.
In general, database management systems come with bulk load utilities.
These utilities make it easy to load
a lots database into a relational database management system.
We're going to cheat a little bit in this case because we
actually going to use a script to load
the example GTOnline database in through a tool called phpMyadmin.
That script is going to be available to you on
the downloadable so you can use the same script
to create the GTOnline database
inside of the MySQL database that's part of your WAMP stack.
I strongly encourage you to play around with
the GTOnline database using the phpMyAdmin interface.
It's a good way to familiarize yourselves better with SQL.
You can play with insertions,
you can play with queries,
and once you need to clean up the example database,
just go load it in using the script one more time.