So what we're basically here for is to install the WAMP stack,
which is the tool that we're going to use for doing the projects in this class.
There are essentially three different AMP stacks.
There's the WAMP stack, which is good for Windows.
There's the MAMP stack,
which is for Macintosh and the LAMP stack which is good for Linux.
The LAMP stack is actually the oldest as I understand it,
but we're going to work with the WAMP stack because we're on a Windows machine here.
So these are the URLs that you will use.
I've tried all three of them.
They all seem to work very well.
So you can use the one that's appropriate for you.
I will say, if you're using the WAMP stack on
Windows and you're on a machine that's still at XP,
it isn't going to work for you because I tried.
They don't support anything prior to Windows 7, I believe at this point.
So start with the URL that you want which in this case is this one.
We're going to go over to the browser and we're going to go to that location.
The screen looks exactly the same whether you choose WAMP, LAMP or MAMP.
It's the same format so you'll see the same thing.
And what you'll do is over here, the latest version.
Just click on it. I'm sure you all know how to download things.
Click on "No thanks,
just take me to download" and save
the file or whatever's appropriate for your particular browser.
So here's the file that we have downloaded and we're just going to execute it.
Go through the standard install.
Nothing special to achieve here.
Put it where you want to put it. You know how this works.
Now, this is the first thing that you need to be aware of.
It's going to create a root account for you.
The root account is what's going to have all of the access
to the database so you need to pick a password you're going to use.
Now try to begin installing.
Installation has completed and it will launch forth automatically when I click "Finish."