There are two different things that you see when you run the WAMP stack.
The first thing is it brings you to this main page
here but it also brings you this control panel.
And the most important thing you're going to want here is
the managed servers because there are two things that will be running
on your machine and every once in a while you'll need to
stop them or start them or make sure if you reboot your machine,
"I don't know why one of the machines I
installed this on it comes up and automatically starts.
The other one I installed it on when I was
playing comes up and doesn't automatically start," So you
have to start this up and then click "Start All"
and "My SQL" and the Web server will start.
And then you can go over to here and say "Open my
phpMyAdmin" and this is where you need that password that we had before.
So again we use GATECH.
You can use whatever you use and that brings us into the M"y phpAdmin" main screen.
This is a web-based utility.
It's essentially if you have used any other databases,
if you've used PostgreSQL,
this is similar to the pgAdmin program.
If you've used Oracle,
it's similar to a number of different utilities that they have.
It basically shows us everything we have here.
So if I click on "Databases",
by default it has a few things that get loaded.
The next thing we're going to do is we are going to install
the sample database for the class that we are working on here.
We have this SQL script that we're going to use and I'm going to do it through.
You can run this at the command line but we're going to do it through the
gooey just to show you some of the usefulness of the gooey.
So basically, this is the script and I'm just going to cut it and
paste it into the query window for phpMyAdmin.
As you can see guys, I've posted this in here it has already formatted.
Apparently, it did that on this one.
When I did it on my computer,
it didn't automatically format.
You can press the Format button if it looks really funny and it
will become something more human-readable.
If you're not familiar with databases,
this will look like Greek to you.
By the time we're done, you'll understand what all this
is but it just creates table scripts and puts in
some initial rows and stuff so we're just going
to run that query and it's going to run and when it's done,
it tells us "That returned an empty result set."
The reason it says "I returned an empty result set," is we didn't do any queries.
There is DML and there's DDL.
DML is data manipulation language.
DDL is data definition language.
That's things like creating tables,
inserting rows, that sort of thing.
This has all been DDL.
There's no result sets coming back because we haven't asked for anything.
But if we go back over here to the databases tab,
you will see that now our DDL online complete database exists and we
can click on it and go in and see all the tables that we have just created.
Let us choose user and we can click browse and we can see what's in there.
So this is basically just showing what's in
the table and we can do the same thing by going to
the SQL window and they've even showed us the query that they used.
I don't know why they have to wear one that's
not necessary but we could do the same thing
here and just type go and we get the same results back.
So now we're going to look at the regular user table and again we're going to
browse which shows us what's in that table.
It's got some different different columns in it and if we go to the structure tab,
we can actually see what the different columns are in the structure of the database.
So this one has the primary key.
This shows us the primary key is the email address which is
a very lengthy character up to 250 characters long.
So the collation field has something to do with which character set is supported.
This is non-nullable field.
To have a row in the table,
you must have something in this field as opposed to down here where it is nullable.
You can enter something and not put in a current city or a home town.
There is no default value for these three so again
you have to specify them when you add a row.
You don't have to specify these two because they have a default value defined.
So we could define a default value that says "Hello" as the default value and save that.
And now if we go back to the structure,
we can see that the default value for current city is hello.