The last thing to consider in the data first portion of
the implementation phase is whether we need to index any tables or not.
First, I'll show you how to compute the size of a table.
Second, a single table can be in the access paths of multiple queries and updates.
Third, the relative frequencies or reads and
or writes will affect our decision of whether to index or not.
Next, it could be that the table is already appropriately indexed.
Some database management systems like MySQL,
don't give you a choice.
Sometimes that's good, sometimes it's bad.
Finally, I'm going to give you some general advice of when to index and when not to.