First, let's consider the size of the table.
So, I'm using the example here of RegularUser,
and these are some of the attributes.
So, we have an Email which is a varchar(50),
we have Sex which is a char(1),
Birthdate is a datetime type.
CurrentCity and Hometown are both varchar(50)s.
So, the size of a record in this table is 50 times 3 is a 150,
eight for datetime and one for Sex.
So, that gives you a grand total of 159 bytes as record size.
Second, let's assume our block size is 4k.
Different database management systems come with different defaults.
For highly formatted data,
a lower block size is often used.
If you have large objects and tables,
then normally a higher block size is used.
Also, we typically do not fill all blocks completely
because it's going to cost a lot of overflow when we insert.
Typical fill is somewhere between two-thirds,
80% is probably a fairly high number,
but let's assume 80% here.
Now, since the block size is 4k and since it's 80% full, which is 3.2k,
divide that by a 160,
and you end up with an approximate number of 20 records per block in this organization.
Let's say that we got 4 million regular users,
so the number of records is 4 million.
What does that mean?
Well, if we can fit 20 records per block and we got four million,
that means that we'll have approximately 200,000 blocks to store the RegularUser table.
That also means the total table size is going to be 800 megabytes, approximately.
So, 800 megabytes may not sound like much.
Some computers come with a main memory that is larger than that.
But remember, this is only one table in the database;
there may be many, many tables in the database.
So, no one says that we are going to have the luxury
of always keeping this table in memory.
So, in general, you need to consider that
major parts of tables are stored on disk and need to be brought up.
So, even in this case here,
where we only have 200,000 blocks in the RegularUser table,
if we make the assumption that a page fault
on the average is going to take a hundredths of a second,
then to scan 200,000 blocks is going to
cost you 200,000 times one hundredths of a second.
That's about 33 minutes to scan the block
if it's not clustered and/or indexed appropriately.